[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
[AUDIENCE EXCLAIMING]
[观众惊呼]
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
SPOT: Hello, world.
斑点：你好，世界。
This is CS50, Harvard University's introduction
这是 CS50，哈佛大学的入门课程
to the intellectual enterprises of computer science
介绍计算机科学的知识领域
and the art of programming.
以及编程的艺术。
Woof, woof.
汪汪。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
I'm sorry, Dave.
对不起，戴夫。
[PINK, "WHAT ABOUT US"] What about us?
[平克，"我们呢？"] 我们呢？
What about us?
我们呢？
La-da-da-da-da-da-da.
啦啦啦啦啦啦啦。
We are searchlights.
我们是探照灯。
We can see in the dark.
我们可以在黑暗中看到。
We are rockets pointed up at the stars.
我们是指向星星的火箭。
We are billions of beautiful hearts.
我们是有数十亿颗美丽的心。
And you sold us down the river too far.
你把我们卖得太远了。
What about us?
我们呢？
What about all the times you said you had the answers?
你曾经说你找到了答案，那我们呢？
What about us?
我们呢？
What about all the broken happy ever-afters?
我们呢？那些破灭的“从此幸福快乐地生活在一起”的承诺呢？
What about us?
我们呢？
What about all the plans that ended in disaster?
那些最终以灾难告终的计划呢？我们呢？
What about love?
爱情呢？
What about trust?
信任呢？
What about us?
我们呢？
La-da-da-da-da-da-da.
啦啦啦啦啦啦啦。
DAVID J. MALAN: All right.
大卫·J·马兰：好了。
So--
所以
[APPLAUSE, CHEERING]
[掌声，欢呼]
This is CS50, Harvard University's introduction
这是 CS50，哈佛大学的入门课程
to the intellectual enterprises of computer science
介绍计算机科学的知识领域
and the art of programming.
以及编程的艺术。
And this is Spot.
这是斑点。
And our thanks to our friends at 3D Cowboys
感谢我们 3D 牛仔的朋友们
for bringing him by class today.
今天让它来上课。
Perhaps a round of applause for our special Professor [INAUDIBLE]..
也许我们可以为我们特别的[听不清]教授鼓掌。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
My name is David Malan.
我叫大卫·马兰。
And I actually took this class, CS50, myself, some years ago.
几年前，我本人也上过 CS50 这门课。
But I almost didn't.
但我差点没上。
And I didn't because when I got to campus, as a first-year,
我当时刚到学校，是大一新生，所以没上。
I really gravitated toward things already familiar, things
我当时对熟悉的东西非常感兴趣，
with which I was already comfortable, specifically, government.
具体来说，我对政治学感到很舒适。
And I came in here thinking I was going to major or concentrate in government.
我当时以为我会主修政治学，或者专门学习政治学。
And it was only once I got to sophomore year, fall semester,
直到我读到二年级秋季学期，
that some friends of mine were coming to this class called
我的一些朋友开始上这门课，它叫做
CS50 that was very much to beware at the time, in that it
CS50，当时这门课非常令人望而生畏，因为
was an unfamiliar field to so many of us, myself included.
它对我们中的许多人来说都是一个陌生的领域，包括我自己。
But I got up the nerve to go over the threshold, sit in on the first class,
但我鼓起勇气跨过门槛，参加了第一节课，
just shop it, so to speak.
随便听听，这么说吧。
And I was hooked.
我被迷住了。
I found that homework was, for the first time, fun.
我发现，第一次，作业变得很有趣。
And this was after having enrolled only because the professor let
而这发生在我报名的时候，我报名仅仅是因为教授允许我
me enroll pass/fail or [INAUDIBLE] because I didn't really
我以及格/不及格的方式报名，因为我真的
think I could even cut it.
不认为我能应付得了。
But fast forward to five Mondays later in the semester,
但快进到学期之后的五个星期一，
I actually switched to a letter grade, deciding,
我实际上改成了字母评分，决定，
wow, this is actually something for me.
哇，这实际上是我的菜。
And I say this because computer science, what
我这么说，因为计算机科学，在我当时没有意识到的是，
I didn't realize about it at the time, really
它实际上是一种非常通用的思维方式和解决问题的方式。
is this very general purpose way of thinking and way of solving problems.
即使这是你唯一上过的CS课，
And even if this is the only CS class you ever take,
即使这是你唯一接受过编程的正式培训，
even if this is the only formal training you have in programming
它在很多其他领域都非常适用——艺术、人文、社会科学、
as a practical skill, it's just so darn applicable
自然科学等等，当然也包括STEM领域本身。
to so many other fields-- the arts, humanities, social sciences,
也就是说，这通常会让人感觉有点像这样。
natural sciences, and beyond, and certainly within the STEM fields,
这是来自我们位于马萨诸塞州剑桥市麻省理工学院的朋友们，这是他们的一项黑客行为，
themselves.
他们把消防栓连接到饮水喷泉，
That said, it's going to often feel a little something like this.
上面还贴了一个小牌子，上面写着：“从麻省理工学院接受教育就像
This is from our friends at MIT, down the road, which is one of their hacks
喝消防水管一样”，也就是说，在这堂课上，
whereby they connected a fire hydrant to a drinking fountain,
你经常会感到
with a little sign up there that says, "GETTING AN EDUCATION FROM MIT IS LIKE
信息量太大。
DRINKING FROM A FIRE HOSE," which is to say that it's
你不可能全部吸收，但要明白
going to feel, quite often, in this class,
这在入门课程中是正常的，
too, that there's just a lot of information.
关键是让很多东西感觉都是新的，但随着练习，随着时间的推移，
And you can't possibly absorb it all, but realize
甚至几年后回过头来看，你会对这些材料越来越熟悉。
that's to be expected, especially in an introductory class.
但你并不一定要在学习过程中感到舒适。
The whole point is for so much of it to feel new, but with practice, with time,
所以我要鼓励你，邀请你，期望你
with years, even, looking back, will you get all the more
在学习过程中学会适应不适，
comfortable with the material.
无论你之前是否有计算机科学或编程经验。
But you're not meant to feel comfortable along the way.
现在，在我的那个年代，这门课的教学大纲有点不同。
And so let me encourage you, invite you, expect
当我和我的所有同学从这门课毕业后，
you to get comfortable feeling uncomfortable along the way,
我们会告诉我们的朋友，我们学会了如何用C语言编程，
whether you have or have not prior computer science or programming
我们自己也会在这门课上学习这种语言。
experience.
但那是我们只学一种语言。
Now, back in my day, the class' syllabus was a little bit different.
但现在，你会发现，我们将探索的不仅仅是
And, really, when I and all of my classmates exited the class,
C语言。
we would say to friends that we learned how
所以，在这门课中，我们会介绍
to program in C, which is a language that we, ourselves, will still
一些不同的编程语言，比如
learn in this class.
Python，
But that was it for languages.
JavaScript，
But nowadays, as you'll see, we'll explore not just
以及SQL。
this older language called C, but a more modern language
一种叫做C的比较古老的语言，但是现在流行的语言是
called Python that's very much in vogue for data science, and web applications,
叫做Python，它在数据科学和网页应用领域非常流行，
and much more.
以及更多领域。
But we'll also introduce you, along the way,
我们还会在学习过程中向你介绍
to another language called S-Q-L or SQL, which is specifically for databases.
另一种语言叫做SQL，它专门用于数据库。
And SQL is a different type of programming language
SQL是一种不同类型的编程语言，
that's just going to give you different ways of solving problems,
它只提供给你不同的解决问题的方式，
different building blocks with which to express problems you want to solve.
不同的构建块，你可以用它们来表达你想解决的问题。
We'll introduce you, toward the end of the semester,
在本学期结束时，我们会向你介绍
yet another language, JavaScript, often used
另一种语言叫做JavaScript，它通常与
with markup languages called HTML and CSS, with which maybe you
称为HTML和CSS的标记语言一起使用，如果你做过网页，也许你
have some experience if you've made websites.
对此有一些经验。
But we'll do this because so many of today's actual real-world software
但我们会这么做，因为如今许多现实世界中的软件
is web-based.
都是基于网页的。
Or it's phone-based, mobile-based, but even then,
或者说是基于手机的、基于移动设备的，但即使是那样，
it's using these same languages, like JavaScript.
它也在使用这些相同的语言，比如JavaScript。
And so by the end of CS50, in particular,
所以，到CS50结束时，特别地，
you won't know how to program in X, or Y, or Z, per se.
你不会知道如何用X、Y或Z语言编程。
But, period, you'll learn how to program.
但是，你将学会编程。
And, indeed, among the goals of this class
事实上，这门课的目标之一
is to equip you with enough of a set of concepts, enough practical skills
就是为了让你掌握足够的概念和实践技能，
and experience that after CS50, again, if you never take another CS class,
以及经验，这样你就可以在学习完CS50之后，即使你不再学习其他的CS课程，
you can teach yourself new languages.
你也能自学新的语言。
And you won't feel--
你不会感到
you won't have been reliant on a class to, indeed,
你不会依赖课程来学习，
introduce you to each and one of those ideas.
向你介绍这些想法。
And what are we going to do, then, in this class?
那么，在这门课中，我们要做什么呢？
And, really, what are we going to start doing today?
实际上，我们今天要开始做什么？
Well, we're going to learn how to solve problems.
嗯，我们要学习如何解决问题。
And that's really what computer science is all about.
这正是计算机科学的本质。
We'll, very specifically, today, knock off a few to-dos.
今天，我们要更具体地完成一些任务。
We'll learn how to represent simple things, like numbers.
我们要学习如何表示简单的事物，比如数字。
We'll learn how to represent letters of an alphabet, like English.
我们要学习如何表示字母，比如英语字母。
We'll learn how to represent colors-- red, green, blue,
我们要学习如何表示颜色——红色、绿色、蓝色，
and everything in between.
以及所有介于其中的颜色。
We'll learn how to represent, more interestingly,
更有趣的是，我们要学习如何表示
full-fledged images that you might see on the web or your phone.
你可能在网页或手机上看到的完整的图像。
We'll talk about representing videos and even audio files.
我们会讨论如何表示视频，甚至音频文件。
So, by the end of today, alone, you will exit here
所以，仅仅到今天结束时，你将走出这里，
with a newfound mental model for how you can
拥有一个全新的思维模型，让你能够
represent all of today's media and multimedia that we take for granted
表示我们每天都习以为常的各种媒体和多媒体，
and use most every day.
并且每天都在使用它们。
But we'll also focus today, ultimately, on how
但今天，我们最终也会专注于如何
to write algorithms, like step-by-step instructions for solving
编写算法，就像解决某个问题的分步指令一样，
some problem, specifically, implementing algorithms with code.
特别是用代码实现算法。
And that's what we'll find.
这就是我们要发现的。
An algorithm is just something you can express
算法只是你能够表达的东西，
in English or any human language, but code is a translation of that
用英语或任何人类语言，但代码是对它们的翻译
to, presumably, the 0's and 1's that you've probably heard
到，可能，是你们可能听说过的 0 和 1
is all that computers ultimately speak.
是所有电脑最终使用的语言。
And if you're feeling like that's a lot for today,
如果你觉得今天学的东西太多了，
if you're feeling like that's a lot for the whole semester,
如果你觉得这整个学期学的东西太多了，
realize and take comfort in knowing that -thirds of you
要意识到并感到欣慰的是，你们三分之二的人
have never taken a CS course before.
以前从未上过计算机科学课程。
So even if you think, like I did all those years ago,
所以即使你像我多年前那样想，
that, surely, my friends, the kids I didn't even in the class,
我的朋友们，那些甚至不在课堂上的孩子们，他们一定比我知道得更多，
must know more than I, have been programming
一定比我更了解编程，他们从六岁就开始编程了
since they were six years old.
从六岁起就开始编程了。
That's just not the case.
事实并非如此。
You're in very much good company.
你们和许多人一样。
And within the class will you find different tracks,
在这个班里，你会发现不同的学习轨迹，
by way of the homework assignments, called "problem sets,"
通过作业，也就是所谓的“习题集”，
by way of the sections or recitations.
通过部分或朗读。
There will be different tracks for those of you
对于你们中
less comfortable, more comfortable, somewhere in between.
不太适应的、更适应的，以及介于两者之间的。
And if you really don't know why you are here today,
如果你真的不知道今天来这里的原因，
we'll even have sections for those least comfortable, where you just
我们甚至会为那些最不适应的人开设专门的部分，在那里你可以
don't necessarily feel ready to dive into CS or maybe STEM, more generally.
不一定感觉准备好深入计算机科学，或者更普遍地说，STEM 领域。
But we'll get you there by way of the course's support structure.
但我们会通过课程的支撑结构帮助你实现。
And it's very much grounded in this mindset.
这深深地植根于这种思维方式。
What ultimately matters in this class is not so much
这门课中最终重要的是，并非是
where you end up relative to your classmates,
你在班级中最终的排名，
but where you end up relative to yourself, when you began.
而是你在课程开始和结束时的进步。
So whether you have or have not prior programming or CSS experience,
所以无论你之前是否有编程或 CSS 经验，
it's not going to matter when it comes to evaluation, when
在评估方面，这并不重要，当
it comes to the output, be it a grade, or a satisfactory mark, or the like.
涉及到最终成果，无论是成绩、合格标记，还是其他类似的东西。
It's going to depend on, really, where you are today,
这实际上取决于你今天所处的位置，
in this, what we call week zero, versus the very end of the semester, when
也就是我们所说的第零周，以及学期结束时，
you will have built something grand, of your very own, in software.
你将用软件构建出你自己的伟大作品。
But CS50 is also characterized, fairly uniquely,
但 CS50 也具有相当独特的特点，
by its community, its culture.
它的社区，它的文化。
And along the way, you'll see that your experience
在学习过程中，你会发现你的经历
is punctuated by a lot of social and academic events alike.
充满了各种社交和学术活动。
CS50 lunches, most every Friday, we'll gather at a nearby restaurant
CS50 午餐，几乎每个星期五，我们都会在附近的一家餐厅
called Changsho where we'll have Chinese lunch together.
叫做昌盛的餐厅聚餐，一起吃中式午餐。
And as many of you as might want to attend
并且只要有兴趣参加的
that week will be able to join us, sit down, and chat casually with me,
那周就能加入我们，坐下来，和我一起轻松地聊天，
the course's teaching staff, friends of ours, alumni from industry, as well.
还有课程的教学人员，我们的朋友，以及来自业界的校友。
CS50 Puzzle Day, coming up this weekend, will be an opportunity,
CS50 谜题日，将在本周末举行，这是一个机会，
even if you have no prior CS experience, just to solve problems,
即使你没有计算机科学方面的经验，也可以解决问题，
not jigsaw puzzles, but puzzles in the logical sense.
不是拼图，而是逻辑上的谜题。
We'll hand you a packet of puzzles--
我们会发给你们一包谜题——
logic problems, or riddles, or the like--
逻辑问题、谜语或类似的东西——
that you, as teams, can solve together.
你们可以组成团队一起解决。
And at the very end, we'll walk you through.
最后，我们会带你们走完整个过程。
And along the way, there'll be not only these puzzles, but pizza, and prizes,
在整个过程中，不仅有这些谜题，还有披萨和奖品，
and so much more, as well.
以及更多其他东西。
Towards the end of the semester, we'll have a CS50 Hackathon whereby
学期结束时，我们将举办 CS50 黑客马拉松，
we'll get together around 7:00 PM, at the start of reading period,
我们将在阅读周开始的晚上 7 点左右聚在一起，
and we'll finish up around 7:00 AM the next morning.
并在第二天早上 7 点左右结束。
And it will be this opportunity to really bond
这是一个真正与你的同学、你的项目伙伴（如果你在团队中工作）
with your classmates, your project partners, if you work in a team,
建立联系的机会。
on your very own final project, which is meant
进行你自己的最终项目，它旨在
to be a capstone of the course, something you build, yourselves,
成为课程的顶峰，是你自己构建的，
that we don't hand you a specification for.
我们不会给你提供规格说明。
But it's your final offboarding, so that when you exit CS50,
但这是你的最终离职，所以当你离开 CS50 时，
you don't need CS50 anymore.
你不再需要 CS50。
You don't need me.
你不需要我。
You don't need your TF.
你不需要你的助教。
You can actually write code and solve problems on your own.
你可以自己编写代码并解决问题。
So this picture here is one of our past photos from earlier in the evening.
所以这张照片是我们之前晚上拍的照片之一。
Things get a little quieter as we then, around 5:00 AM,
之后，在凌晨 5 点左右，事情变得安静一些，
drive anyone who's still awake and energetic to a nearby IHOP
我们会开车送那些仍然清醒且精力充沛的人去附近的 IHOP
for pancakes, around then.
吃煎饼。
But here is how most of the evenings tend to end for at least some
但对于至少一些同学来说，大多数晚上都是这样结束的。
of your classmates prior.
你们之前
But at the very end of the class is the so-called CS50 Fair,
但课程的最后是所谓的 CS50 展览会，
an exhibition of all of your final projects for friends, faculty,
展示所有你的最终项目，面向朋友、教师、
students, and staff across campus, whereby
学生和校园里的工作人员，
you'll be invited to a space like this.
你们会被邀请到这样的地方。
Bring your laptop.
带上你的笔记本电脑。
Bring your phone, whatever it is you have built and created.
带上你的手机，你所构建和创造的任何东西。
And we'll just show it off for a bit of the afternoon,
我们将在下午展示一下，
complete with music, and friends from industry,
配上音乐，以及来自业界的朋友，
and candy, and all what makes gathering together at term's end fond.
以及糖果，以及所有让学期结束时聚在一起变得美好的事物。
And you'll wear, ultimately, very proudly,
最终，你会非常自豪地穿上，
we hope, your very own "I took CS50," stating, very matter of factly,
我们希望，你自己的 “我上了 CS50” T 恤，非常坦率地表明，
what I did some years ago; that, indeed, this was a course I, myself, took.
几年前我做过的事情；事实上，这门课是我自己上的。
So, today, let's focus, then, on computer science, like what is it.
那么，今天让我们专注于计算机科学，就像它是什么。
Well, it's really the study of information.
它实际上是信息的研究。
But, really, it's, more specifically, about solving problems,
但它实际上，更具体地说，是关于解决问题，
using certain ideas and techniques, all of which you'll exit the course with.
使用某些想法和技术，所有这些你都会在课程结束后掌握。
So, as such, problem solving is a goal that we'll
因此，像这样，解决问题是我们会
approach by way of something called "computational thinking."
通过一种叫做“计算思维”的方式来解决。
So computational thinking, you can oversimplistically think about it
所以计算思维，你可以简单地把它理解为
as thinking like a computer.
像计算机一样思考。
But it's really the application of ideas that we'll dive into today
但这实际上是我们在今天深入研究的想法的应用，
and we'll finish some weeks from now, that you
我们将在几周后完成，你会
can apply to problems from this field or most any other, but in a computational,
可以应用于该领域或大多数其他领域的问题，但以一种计算的方式，
that is, a very methodical, very careful way.
也就是说，一种非常有条理，非常谨慎的方式。
And that's what CS really did for me and does for a lot of people.
这就是计算机科学真正为我所做的，也为许多人所做的。
It helps clean up your thought processes.
它有助于理清你的思维过程。
Even if you go off into the real world and do nothing in tech,
即使你进入现实世界，并且在科技领域无所作为，
you have an ability, after classes like this,
在学习了这样的课程之后，你将拥有一种能力，
to express yourself a little more correctly, more
更准确地表达自己，更
precisely and, generally, having better command
精确地，而且通常来说，对自己的想法和语言有更好的掌控能力
of your own ideas and your language.
你自己的想法和你的语言。
So what's problem solving?
那么什么是解决问题呢？
Let me propose that this is it.
让我建议这就是它。
This is as simple as we can make today's goals and the semester's goals.
这是我们今天和本学期目标的最简单表达方式。
Problems to be solved look like this.
待解决的问题看起来像这样。
You've got some input, the problem to be solved.
你有一些输入，待解决的问题。
You've got a goal being the output, like the solution there, too.
你有一个目标，即输出，就像那里的解决方案一样。
And then somewhere in the middle is the secret sauce,
然后在中间某个地方是秘诀，
where we'll spend the next several weeks figuring out how
我们将花接下来的几周时间弄清楚如何
we can convert these inputs to outputs.
将这些输入转换为输出。
But before we can do that, we all just have
但在我们这样做之前，我们都必须
to agree on how to represent these inputs and outputs,
就如何表示这些输入和输出达成一致，
whether it's with English or, really, any type of language.
无论是用英语还是任何其他类型的语言。
But, as I spoiled earlier, you probably came in here already
但是，就像我之前剧透过的那样，你可能已经来到这里了
with a general sense that, yeah, computers somehow
有一种普遍的感觉，是的，计算机在某种程度上
only speak or know 0's and 1's, the so-called binary system.
只说或知道 0 和 1，即所谓的二进制系统。
But that's just one way of representing information.
但这只是表示信息的一种方式。
Even simpler than binary is unary.
甚至比二进制更简单的是一元。
So if you've ever, at this age or any prior age, counted on your fingers,
所以，如果你曾经，在这个年龄或任何之前的年龄，用手指计数，
this is unary notation, whereby each of your digits, your fingers
这就是一元记数法，其中你的每个数字，你的手指
literally represent some piece of information;
字面上代表一些信息；
taking attendance, like 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
点名，比如 1，2，3，4，5。
But on your one human hand, how high can you count in this unary notation?
但是，用你的一只手，你能用这种一元记数法数到多少呢？
AUDIENCE: Five.
观众：五。
DAVID J. MALAN: Five, I'm hearing five.
戴维·马兰：五，我听到的是五。
Six, I heard one six.
六，我听到一个六。
But I'm going to go further and say the answer, if you're clever about it,
但我还要更进一步说，如果你聪明的话，答案是
is actually--
实际上
AUDIENCE: 40?
观众：四十？
DAVID J. MALAN: Not quite 40.
戴维·马兰：不是四十。
You overbid, but--
你出价过高，但是
AUDIENCE: 31.
观众：三十一。
DAVID J. MALAN: 31 is as high as I can actually count.
戴维·马兰：三十一是实际上我能数到的最大数字。
And that's because if I actually-- and if you're thinking
这是因为，如果我实际上——如果你正在思考
this is weirdly painful now, it will be, but this
这现在很痛苦，这将是痛苦的，但这
is my hand representing the number 0.
是我的手代表数字 0。
Normally, in unary, this is 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, of course, obviously.
通常，在一元中，这是 1，2，3，4，5，当然，显然。
But what if I take into account the order in which I'm
但如果我考虑到我
putting my fingers up and down?
上下移动手指的顺序呢？
So maybe this is still 0.
所以，也许这仍然是 0。
Maybe this is still 1.
也许这仍然是 1。
But maybe this is now 2, where it's just the single second finger up,
但是也许这现在是2，只有第二根手指向上，
not two of them, total.
而不是两根，总共。
Maybe this is now 3.
也许现在是3。
Maybe this is now-- often offensive, with just the middle finger up.
也许现在是——通常很粗鲁，只有中指向上。
This is now [LAUGHS] 5.
现在是[笑声] 5。
This is now 6.
现在是6。
This is now 7.
现在是7。
And my hand just hurts too much if I try to count higher than seven.
如果我试着数到比七大的数字，我的手就太疼了。
But, theoretically, because each of my fingers can be down or up
但是，理论上，因为我的每根手指都可以向下或向上
and I've got five of them, that's actually 32 possible permutations,
而我有五根手指，实际上有32种可能的排列，
up and down.
向上和向下。
But wait a minute.
等等。
We said, 31, but if you start at 0.
我们说，31，但如果你从0开始。
You have to subtract 1 from the biggest possible value.
你必须从最大的可能值中减去1。
So this is to say you and I have been using unary because it's just simple,
所以这就是说你我一直在使用一元制，因为它很简单，
and it gets the job done.
并且它能完成工作。
But if we just think about representation a little more cleverly,
但是如果我们更聪明地思考一下表示方法，
we can do exactly what computers do, using not what mathematicians call
我们可以像计算机一样做，不使用数学家所说的
"base-1," where the finger is either there or it's not, but base-2.
"基数-1"，即手指要么在那里，要么不在那里，而是基数-2。
And in base-2, we just need two digits at our disposal.
而在基数-2中，我们只需要两个数字。
And we could call these digits 1 and 2, A and B, black or white.
我们可以称这些数字为1和2，A和B，黑色或白色。
We just need two words to describe two pieces of information.
我们只需要两个词来描述两条信息。
Computers keep it simple.
计算机保持简单。
And just like we humans start counting 0, 1, 2, 3 on up,
就像我们人类开始计数0、1、2、3一样，
computers use 0 and 1, and that's it.
计算机使用0和1，仅此而已。
But that's by convention.
但这只是约定俗成。
But why do they do that?
但他们为什么这样做？
Well, it turns out, when you use base-2, otherwise known as binary, well,
事实证明，当你使用基数-2，也称为二进制时，
it just maps really readily to the real world.
它与现实世界非常契合。
Because, at the end of the day, what do we all
因为，归根结底，我们所有人
do, if you've got a laptop, or a phone, or any device?
如果你的笔记本电脑、手机或任何设备？
You plug it into the wall because it needs electricity at some point.
你把它插到墙上，因为它在某个时候需要电。
And what if you have electricity or not?
而如果有电或没有电呢？
Well, there's your two possible values.
那么，你有两种可能的值。
Either it's there, or it's not.
要么它在那里，要么它不在那里。
And because computers are electrical devices,
而由于计算机是电子设备，
this is why binary is just useful.
这就是为什么二进制很实用。
It's nice and simple.
它简单易懂。
Either electricity is there, or it's not.
要么有电，要么没有电。
So when you plug this device in and you've
所以，当你把这个设备插上，并且你已经
got all these electrons or whatever flowing, maybe
得到了所有这些电子或任何正在流动的东西，也许
if we just hang on to some of that electricity,
如果我们只是保存一部分电力，
we can represent what we'll call a 1.
我们可以用它来表示我们所说的1。
And maybe if we let it dissipate or go away, that's a 0.
也许如果我们让它消散或消失，那就是0。
So on and off maps very readily to this idea of just 0's and 1's.
所以，开关对应着0和1的概念。
And if you've ever thought of this, now, as binary digits--
如果你曾经把这看作是二进制数字——
"bi" implying 2, 0 and 1-- well, if you've ever heard this term now,
"bi" 代表2，0和1——如果你曾经听说过这个词，
"bit," it just means binary digit.
"bit"，它只是意味着二进制数字。
A single bit is just a 0 or 1.
一个比特就是一个0或1。
But we could have called these things anything we want.
但我们可以随心所欲地称呼它们。
Now how does this map to be clear to the real world?
现在，如何才能让它清晰地映射到现实世界呢？
Well, we can't see the tiny little switches inside of our Macs,
好吧，我们看不到 Mac 内部那些微小的开关，
PCs, and our phones that are actually turning the electricity on
PC 以及手机内部，那些真正控制着电流的开关，
or off, storing electricity or not.
开着或者关着，存储着电或者不存储电。
But they're called transistors.
但它们被称为晶体管。
They've got millions of them in today's hardware.
现代硬件里拥有数百万个这样的晶体管。
And they're just on or off, like a switch or a light bulb.
它们要么开着，要么关着，就像一个开关或一个灯泡。
So, for instance, if there's no electricity,
例如，如果没有电，
the switch is off, we would call this, by convention, a 0.
开关是关闭的，按照惯例，我们称之为 0。
If, though, you throw the switch and it actually turns on, we would call this--
然而，如果你打开开关，它真的打开了，我们称之为——
AUDIENCE: On.
观众：开。
DAVID J. MALAN: --an "on," exactly, a 1.
大卫·马兰：没错，是“开”，就是 1。
We could have reversed it.
我们也可以反过来。
But this is just the way the world decided to standardize.
但这仅仅是世界决定采用的标准化方式。
And that's it.
就是这样。
So you've either got something on or off, a 1 or a 0.
因此，要么是开，要么是关，要么是 1，要么是 0。
And this, then, is this thing we know now as a binary digit or a bit.
这就是我们现在所知的二进制位或比特。
So once we've got these values, what about how--
那么，既然我们有了这些值，如何——
how can we go about, perhaps, representing things?
我们该如何去表示事物呢？
Well, you know what?
你知道吗？
It turns out we've got a lot of light bulbs right here.
事实证明，我们这里有很多灯泡。
Let me grab-- thanks.
让我拿一下——谢谢。
Excuse me, spot.
不好意思，地方。
Let me grab the little music stand here.
让我拿一下这里的小乐谱架。
Let me borrow a couple of these bulbs and see
让我借几个灯泡，看看
if we can't make clearer than my hand, alone, what's going on here.
我能不能比单靠我的手更清晰地解释这里发生了什么。
So I'm going to go ahead and grab two of these.
所以我打算拿两个。
And I'll just put them here.
然后我把它放在这里。
And I can turn these things on or off now.
我现在可以把它们打开或关闭。
So if I've got two bits, two switches, two transistors, if you will, well,
所以，如果我有两个比特，两个开关，或者两个晶体管，如果你愿意的话，那么，
if I go ahead and turn on this one, I'm representing what number in binary,
如果我打开这个，我在二进制中表示的是什么数字，
perhaps?
也许？
AUDIENCE: 1.
观众：1。
DAVID J. MALAN: So just 1.
大卫·马兰：所以是 1。
Now, if I'm using unary, I would turn this one on and be done with it.
现在，如果我使用一元制，我只需打开这个灯泡就行了。
And that's 2, but not in binary.
那是 2，但不是二进制。
Binary, it's the permutations, which ones are on and off, that matters.
二进制是关于排列组合的，哪些是开，哪些是关，才是重要的。
So what, now, am I representing here, perhaps?
那么现在，我可能在这里表示的是什么？
AUDIENCE: 2.
观众：2。
DAVID J. MALAN: 2.
大卫·马兰：2。
So this is when I put my single pointer finger up.
所以，当我只伸出一根手指的时候，
But then when I did this, in my human hand,
但当我用手做这个动作时，
this was like representing the number 3.
就相当于表示数字 3。
How do I represent the number 4.
我怎样表示数字 4 呢？
Yeah, I need another light bulb, so I need more hardware, so to speak.
没错，我需要另一个灯泡，所以需要更多硬件，可以这么说。
So if I turn--
所以，如果我打开——
if I leave this one-- if I turn this one on, this one off, this one off,
如果我留着这个——如果我打开这个，关闭这个，关闭这个，
now I have the number 4.
现在我得到了数字 4。
And someone tell me, saying the words "on"
还有，有人告诉我，用“开”
and "on" and "on," or "on," or "off," or "on,"
和“开”和“开”，或“开”，或“关”，或“开”，
using combinations of "on," "off" and-- "on"
使用“开”、“关”和“开”的组合
and "off," how do I represent 5, from your left to your right?
以及“关”，我该如何用从左到右的顺序表示5？
How about over here?
这边呢？
AUDIENCE: On, off, on.
观众：开，关，开。
DAVID J. MALAN: "On, off, on," I heard.
大卫·马兰：“开，关，开”，我听到了。
And that's exactly right.
没错。
And how do I represent, maybe, 6?
那么，我该如何表示，也许是6？
Over here?
这边？
AUDIENCE: Off, on, on.
观众：关，开，开。
DAVID J. MALAN: Off, on, on, not quite.
大卫·马兰：关，开，开，不太对。
From left to right?
从左到右？
AUDIENCE: Off-- the other way.
观众：关，反过来。
DAVID J. MALAN: The--
大卫·马兰：这——
[LAUGHS] OK, so from right to left.
[笑] 好吧，从右到左。
So I think we leave this one on.
我认为我们应该把这个开着。
This one, I'm going to claim, represents, now, 6 and 7.
我声称，现在这个表示6和7。
AUDIENCE: On, off.
观众：开，关。
DAVID J. MALAN: I'm just going to-- it's actually going to be "on, on, on."
大卫·马兰：我将——实际上应该是“开，开，开”。
Now, if you're wondering, where are these people coming up
现在，如果你想知道，这些人是怎么想出
with these combinations, there's actually a system here.
这些组合的，这里其实是有规律的。
It's actually hard for me to do it backwards.
对我来说，反过来做其实很难。
But it turns out there's actually a system that's not all that unfamiliar.
但事实证明，其实存在一个并不陌生的系统。
In fact, let me propose this.
事实上，我建议这样。
Let me propose that we consider what you and I all
我建议我们考虑你和我一起
learned in grade school, which was something like the base-10 system, 10
在小学学到的，就像十进制系统，10
meaning that you use 10 different digits, not two, 10.
意味着你使用10个不同的数字，而不是两个，而是10个。
So 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, that's the base-10 system, otherwise known
所以 0，1，2，3，4，5，6，7，8，9，这就是十进制系统，也被称为
as decimal, "dec" implying 10.
十进制，“dec” 表示10。
So that's what you and I use every day.
所以这就是我们每天都在使用的。
Well, let's think about how we represent numbers in decimal,
那么，让我们考虑一下我们如何在十进制中表示数字，
in the normal human way.
用正常的人类方式。
Well, here is a number.
这是一个数字。
It's what number, of course?
当然，它是什么数字？
AUDIENCE: 123.
观众：123。
DAVID J. MALAN: 123.
大卫·马兰：123。
So we all just have an intuition for that, obviously.
所以我们都对此有直觉，很明显。
But it's not necessarily 123.
但这不一定是123。
You're just assigning meaning to the positions of these digits.
你只是给这些数字的位置赋予意义。
This is really the pattern 1-2-3.
这实际上是1-2-3的模式。
But you immediately jump, mathematically, to 123, but why?
但你立即从数学上跳到123，为什么呢？
Well, odds are, in grade school, you learned that the rightmost digit is
好吧，很有可能，在小学，你学到的是最右边的数字是
the ones place or the ones column.
个位数或个位数列。
This is the tens place or the tens column.
这是十位数或十位数列。
This is the hundreds place.
这是百位数。
And so why is this relevant?
那么，为什么这很重要呢？
Well, this is like doing 100 times 1 plus 10 times
好吧，这就像做100乘以1加10乘以
2 plus 1 times 3 or, if we multiply that out, 100 plus 20 plus 3,
2加1乘以3，或者，如果我们把这些乘起来，100加20加3，
ergo, the number, now, that we just take for granted is 123.
因此，我们现在习以为常的数字就是123。
But that's in base-10, the so-called decimal system,
但那是十进制，也就是所谓的十进制系统，
whereby each of these digits is in a different column.
其中每个数字都在不同的列中。
And those columns are, again, ones place, tens, hundreds.
这些列分别是，再说一次，个位、十位、百位。
If we keep going, thousand, ten thousand, and so forth.
如果我们继续下去，千位、万位，等等。
But where did these come from?
但这些是从哪里来的呢？
Well, here's the base.
好吧，这是底数。
If you remember exponents and all of that,
如果你还记得指数和所有这些，
this is just 10 to the 0, 10 to the 1, 10 to the 2, ad infinitum.
这只是 10 的 0 次方、10 的 1 次方、10 的 2 次方，无限地。
And so, now, what if we just changed the base from 10, 0 through 9,
因此，现在，如果我们只是将底数从 10，0 到 9，
to just two digits, 0 and 1?
改为只有两位数，0 和 1 呢？
Well, now the math is fundamentally the same.
好吧，现在数学在根本上是一样的。
But it's 2 to the 0, 2 to the 1, 2 to the 2,
但它是 2 的 0 次方、2 的 1 次方、2 的 2 次方，
which gives us the ones place, twos place, and fours place.
这给了我们个位、两位和四位。
Now, why is this relevant?
现在，为什么这很重要呢？
If you've got three light bulbs or three bits that are off, off, off,
如果你有三个灯泡或三个位，它们都是关着的，关着的，关着的，
what have I done?
我做了什么？
4 times 0 plus 2 times 0 plus 1 times 0 is, obviously, the number
4 乘以 0 加 2 乘以 0 加 1 乘以 0，显然是，这个数字
you and I know, in decimal, as 0.
你和我知道，在十进制中，为 0。
This, though, represents the number you and I know as--
不过，这个数字代表着你和我知道的——
AUDIENCE: 1
观众：1
DAVID J. MALAN: This represents--
大卫·J·马兰：这个代表着——
AUDIENCE: 2.
观众：2。
DAVID J. MALAN: --3, 4.
大卫·J·马兰：——3、4。
And just to be clear, this is why, when I grabbed the additional light bulb,
为了说清楚，这就是为什么，当我抓起那个额外的灯泡时，
we claimed that this now was 4.
我们声称这个现在是 4。
Because we had "on, off, off," "on, off, off."
因为我们有“开着，关着，关着”，“开着，关着，关着”。
This now is 5.
这个现在是 5。
This now is 6.
这个现在是 6。
This now is 7.
这个现在是 7。
And if I wanted to count higher, what would the pattern of 0's and 1's be
如果我想数到更高的数字，0 和 1 的模式会是什么
for the number 8?
代表数字 8 呢？
AUDIENCE: 1, 0--
观众：1、0——
DAVID J. MALAN: 1, 0, 0, 0.
大卫·J·马兰：1、0、0、0。
So we just need more hardware, more bits.
所以我们只需要更多的硬件，更多的位。
So it wasn't arbitrary, even if it was non-obvious,
所以这不是随意的，即使它不明显，
what I was actually doing with turning these light bulbs on and off.
我实际上是用这些灯泡的开和关来做的事情。
Now, it turns out here we are talking about how to represent information,
现在，事实证明，我们正在谈论如何表示信息，
like numbers, but we could also use bits, 0's and 1's, light bulbs
比如数字，但我们也可以使用位，0 和 1，灯泡
to represent instructions, as well.
来表示指令。
Because, at the end of the day, that's all computers do.
因为，归根结底，这就是计算机所做的。
They process data, information of some sort, whether it's files,
它们处理数据，各种各样的信息，无论是文件，
or numbers, or images, or videos, or the like.
还是数字，还是图像，还是视频，或者类似的东西。
And you do things with those files.
然后你会用这些文件做一些事情。
You open them.
你打开它们。
You print them.
你打印它们。
You edit them and the like.
你编辑它们等等。
So there's this notion of instructions, what the computer can actually do.
所以，就有了指令的概念，计算机实际能做什么。
And I bet we could come up with some pattern of 0's and 1's
我相信我们可以想出一些 0 和 1 的模式
or, equivalently, light bulbs that tell even Spot what to do.
或者，等效地，灯泡，告诉 Spot 要做什么。
Maybe, go up, or down, or left, or right.
也许，向上，向下，向左，或向右。
And it could certainly do this autonomously by using various sensors.
它当然可以通过使用各种传感器自动完成这个任务。
We need to keep things safe today.
我们今天需要确保安全。
We're using Wi-Fi in sending Spot these very instructions.
我们正在使用 Wi-Fi 向 Spot 发送这些指令。
But what's happening, wirelessly, with our friend Andrew, here, is,
但是，我们的朋友 Andrew 正在无线地做的事情是，
essentially, he's sending Spot instructions just encoded, wirelessly,
本质上，他只是无线地将指令编码发送给 Spot，
somehow, as patterns of 0's and 1's.
以某种方式，以 0 和 1 的模式形式。
And the folks at Boston Dynamics, who built this robot, programmed
而波士顿动力公司的人员，他们制造了这个机器人，他们对
Spot to recognize certain patterns as meaning "up,"
Spot 进行了编程，让它识别某些模式，代表着“向上”，
a certain pattern as meaning "down," "left," "right,"
某个模式代表着“向下”、“向左”、“向右”，
and any number of other things.
以及其他任何数量的事情。
So, in fact, Spot, come on over here, if you could.
所以，实际上，Spot，如果你可以的话，到这边来。
Come on, Spot.
来吧，Spot。
[FOOTSTEPS]
[脚步声]
OK.
好的。
So Spot, for instance, may very well have a pattern
所以，例如，Spot 可能会有一个
of 0's and 1's that represents shake.
由 0 和 1 组成的模式，代表着“摇动”。
Shake, Spot.
摇动，Spot。
So he could do that and any number of other movements, as well.
所以他可以做到这一点，以及其他任何数量的动作。
And maybe, especially with sensors here and also a little human help over here,
也许，尤其是在这里有传感器，也有一点人类的帮助，
for today, what if we went ahead and did something-- maybe
今天，如果我们继续做一些事情——也许
ask Spot some questions?
问 Spot 一些问题？
So let's go ahead, and we'll start simple.
所以我们继续吧，从简单的问题开始。
Spot, here we have some bits, "off, off, on."
Spot，这里我们有一些比特，“关、关、开”。
Spot, what [LAUGHS]-- OK.
Spot，什么[笑]——好的。
Spot, what is this representing, "off, off, on"?
Spot，这代表什么，“关、关、开”？
[SPOT TAPS STAGE]
[Spot 轻敲舞台]
Correct?
正确吗？
I think so.
我认为是的。
Very horse-like, OK.
非常像马，好的。
Thank you.
谢谢。
All right, so a round of applause for Spot here.
好的，让我们为 Spot 鼓掌。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
All right.
好的。
So, Spot, what if we [LAUGHS] turn--
所以，Spot，如果我们[笑]把——
OK.
好的。
We'll turn that one off here.
我们将把这个关掉。
How about if we turn this one on?
如果我们把这个打开怎么样？
So it's "off, on, off."
所以是“关、开、关”。
Spot, what's this number?
Spot，这个数字是多少？
[SPOT TAPPING STAGE]
[Spot 轻敲舞台]
Is that correct?
正确吗？
Nice.
不错。
OK.
好的。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
[LAUGHS] How about one final flourish?
[笑] 最后再做个收尾动作怎么样？
How about, Spot, instead of "off, on, off,"
怎么样，Spot，而不是“关、开、关”，
let's go ahead and do "off, on, on"?
我们来做“关、开、开”吧？
So think, in your mind's eye, what the answer should be.
所以，在你的脑海里想一下答案应该是什么。
All right, Spot, "off, on, on."
好的，Spot，“关、开、开”。
[SPOT LANDING ON THE STAGE]
[Spot 落在舞台上]
OK.
好的。
And a round of applause for, Spot, as well.
也让我们为 Spot 鼓掌。
[LAUGHS]
[笑声]
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
So this is to say, no matter how--
所以，无论怎样——
thank you, Spot.
谢谢，Spot。
No matter how fancy today's hardware or software is,
无论今天硬件或软件有多么复杂，
it really just boils down to representing
它实际上只是归结为表示
information and instructions.
信息和指令。
And computers, and phones, and the like really are just
而计算机，手机等等，实际上只是
operating on those same pieces of information,
操作着那些相同的信息，
whether implemented in 0's and 1's or with, really, anything else.
无论这些信息是以 0 和 1 实现的，还是以其他任何方式实现的。
All right.
好的。
So, where can we take this, once we have this agreed-upon system
那么，当我们有了这个大家认可的系统，我们能做些什么呢？
for representing [LAUGHS] information?
来表示 [笑声] 信息呢？
Well, it turns out that using three bits, three 0's and 1's, at a time,
嗯，事实证明，一次使用三个比特，三个 0 和 1，
isn't actually all that useful.
实际上并不是那么有用。
And you and I, even in conversation, don't often say the word "bit."
你和我，即使在对话中，也不常说“比特”这个词。
We say the word "byte."
我们说“字节”这个词。
And what is a byte, if familiar?
如果你熟悉的话，什么是字节？
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: It's eight bits.
观众：它是八个比特。
DAVID J. MALAN: So it's just eight bits.
DAVID J. MALAN：所以它就是八个比特。
It's just a more useful unit of measure.
它只是一个更有用的计量单位。
And it happens to be a power of 2, 2 to the third,
而且它恰好是 2 的幂，2 的三次方，
which just makes math work out cleanly.
这使得数学计算很干净利落。
But it's just a convention, to have more interesting units of measure
但这只是一个约定，为了有更有趣的计量单位
than individual bits.
而不是单独的比特。
So a byte is eight bits.
所以一个字节是八个比特。
So, for instance, this represents, using eight bits, eight light bulbs,
例如，这个使用八个比特，八个灯泡，
the number you and I know is 0.
表示你我所知的数字 0。
And this byte of all 1 bits--
而这个全是 1 的字节——
now you've got to do some quick math-- represents what number, instead?
现在你得做一些简单的数学运算——它表示什么数字呢？
So it's all 1's; eight of them, total.
所以它全是 1；总共有八个。
How about over here, on the end?
这边怎么样？
AUDIENCE: 255.
观众：255。
DAVID J. MALAN: So it's, indeed, 255.
DAVID J. MALAN：所以它确实是 255。
Now, that's not the kind of math that you
现在，这并不是你
need to do in your head for a class like this, but you could.
需要在头脑里计算的，但你可以做到。
This is the ones place, twos, fours, eight, 16, 32, 64, 128.
这是个位、二位、四位、八位、十六位、三十二位、六十四位、一百二十八位。
And because they're all 1, you just have to add up all of those columns' values.
由于它们都是 1，你只需要将所有这些列的值加起来。
And you get 255.
你会得到 255。
But a little mental trick, too, is that, if you've got eight bits
但还有一个小的技巧，如果你有八个比特
and each of them can be two possible values, 0 or 1,
并且它们中的每一个都有两种可能的值，0 或 1，
that's like 2 possibilities here times 2 times 2 times 2 times 2, eight times.
这就像这里有 2 种可能性，乘以 2 乘以 2 乘以 2 乘以 2，八次。
So that's 2 to the eighth, so that is maybe a little easier to do.
所以这是 2 的八次方，所以这可能更容易一点。
That's 256.
那是 256。
Or easier, in the sense that you get used to seeing these numbers in CS.
或者说更容易，因为你在 CS 中会习惯看到这些数字。
That's 256.
那是 256。
But wait a minute.
等等。
How do I reconcile this with your 255?
我怎样才能将这个与你的 255 联系起来呢？
Because you start at 0.
因为你从 0 开始。
So you lose one on the high end because we started counting and representing
所以，你在高端失去了一位，因为我们开始计数和表示
the number, like 0.
数字，比如 0。
All right.
好的。
Questions on how we've represented just numbers or, for instance,
对于我们如何仅仅表示数字，或者，例如，
instructions to Spot, thus far?
到目前为止，对 Spot 的指令，你们有什么问题吗？
Any questions on binary, unary, or the like?
关于二进制、一元制或类似的内容，还有其他问题吗？
No?
没有？
All right, so seeing none, let's let things escalate a bit.
好的，既然没有，让我们把事情升级一下。
So how do you represent letters because, obviously, this
那么，你如何表示字母呢？因为，很明显，这
makes our devices more useful, whether it's
让我们的设备更有用，无论是
in English or any other human language.
英语还是其他任何人类语言。
How could we go about representing the letter A, for instance?
例如，我们该如何表示字母 A 呢？
If, at the end of the day, all our computers,
如果，归根结底，我们所有的计算机，
all our phones have access to is electricity; or, equivalently,
我们所有的手机，所能接触到的只有电力；或者，等效地，
switches; or, metaphorically, tiny little light bulbs
开关；或者，比喻地说，微小的灯泡
inside of them that can be on and off-- that's it.
在它们内部，可以开和关——就这些了。
There's no more building blocks to give you.
没有更多给你搭建的模块了。
How could we represent something like the letter A?
我们该如何表示像字母 A 这样的东西呢？
Yeah, how about here?
嗯，这里怎么样？
Yeah?
嗯？
AUDIENCE: You could assign a number.
观众：你可以分配一个数字。
DAVID J. MALAN: Perfect.
大卫·J·马兰：完美。
So we could just assign every letter a number.
所以我们可以给每个字母分配一个数字。
And we could do this super simply.
而且我们可以非常简单地做到这一点。
Maybe 0 is A, and 1 is B. Or maybe 1 is A,
也许 0 是 A，1 是 B。或者也许 1 是 A，
and 2 is B. It doesn't really matter, so long as we all agree and we all
2 是 B。这并不重要，只要我们都同意，我们都
use the same types of computers, in some sense, ultimately.
在某种程度上，最终使用相同类型的计算机。
Well, for various reasons, the humans that designed this system,
嗯，由于各种原因，设计这个系统的人类，
they went with the number 65.
他们选择了数字 65。
So, nowadays, anytime your computer is showing you the capital letter
所以，如今，每当你的电脑向你展示大写字母
A on the screen, underneath the hood, so to speak,
A 在屏幕上，在引擎盖下，可以这么说，
it's actually storing a pattern of 0's and 1's that represents the number 65.
实际上，它存储着一组 0 和 1 的模式，代表数字 65。
And it tends to use seven bits or, typically, eight bits, total,
而且它倾向于使用 7 位，或者通常是 8 位，总共，
even if it doesn't need all of those bits in total.
即使它并不需要所有这些位。
So how do we get there?
那么我们如何得到它呢？
Well, here, for instance, is that same pattern.
嗯，这里，例如，是相同的模式。
Here is that pattern of bits that represents 65.
这里就是表示 65 的位的模式。
And why?
为什么呢？
Well, quick check here.
嗯，这里快速检查一下。
This is the ones place, twos, fours, eights, 16, 32, 64's place.
这是个位，两位，四位，八位，十六位，三十二位，六十四位。
OK, so 64 plus 1 gives me 65.
好的，所以 64 加 1 等于 65。
So that is to say here's how a computer, using some light switches, so to speak,
也就是说，这是一台计算机，使用一些开关，可以这么说，
would represent the number 65.
将表示数字 65。
And our Macs, our PCs, our phones just all know this.
而且我们的 Mac，我们的 PC，我们的手机都知道这一点。
So whenever they see that in their memory, so to speak,
所以每当它们在它们的内存中看到它，可以这么说，
they show a capital letter A on the screen.
它们就在屏幕上显示一个大写字母 A。
So that's it.
就是这样。
That's the system known as ASCII, the American Standard
这就是被称为 ASCII 的系统，美国标准
Code for Information Interchange.
信息交换码。
And the A is actually operative there because we're only talking, thus far,
而 A 实际上在那里是有效的，因为到目前为止，我们只讨论了，
about English letters in our alphabet.
关于我们字母表中的英文字母。
And, in fact, I claimed, a moment ago, that we only use
事实上，我刚才声称，我们只使用
seven, maybe eight bits to represent letters of an alphabet.
七个，也许八个比特来表示字母表中的字母。
So, just to come back to you, if I may, how many
所以，如果可以的话，我想问问，多少
possible letters of the alphabet could-- how
字母表中可能的字母，多少个，
many possible letters of any alphabet could we represent with eight bits?
任何字母表中可能的字母，我们用八个比特可以表示多少个？
AUDIENCE: 256.
观众：256。
DAVID J. MALAN: 256, the numbers 0 through 255.
大卫·马兰：256，从 0 到 255 的数字。
Now, that's more than enough for English because we've
现在，这对于英语来说已经绰绰有余，因为我们
got A through Z, uppercase, lowercase, a bunch of numbers,
有 A 到 Z，大写，小写，一大堆数字，
a bunch of punctuation symbols.
一大堆标点符号。
But in a lot of languages, with accented characters, a lot of Asian characters,
但在很多语言中，带重音的字符，很多亚洲字符，
this is not nearly enough memory or bits with which
这远远不够内存或比特，
to represent all of those possible values.
来表示所有这些可能的值。
So we need to do a little better than ASCII,
所以我们需要比 ASCII 好一点，
but we can build on top of what they did years ago.
但我们可以在此基础上，利用他们多年前做的事情。
So here is a chart of ASCII codes.
这是一个 ASCII 码的图表。
It's just a bunch of columns showing us the mapping between letters
它只是一堆列，显示了字母之间的映射
and numbers.
和数字。
So, for instance, up here is the capital letter A, 65; capital B, 66;
例如，这里是大写字母 A，65；大写字母 B，66；
capital C, 67; dot, dot, dot.
大写字母 C，67；等等。
72 is H. 73 is I and so forth.
72 是 H，73 是 I，以此类推。
There's some weird things over here, like special symbols,
这里有一些奇怪的东西，比如特殊符号，
that we'll learn about over time.
我们以后会学到。
But there's a mapping between every English letter
但是每一个英文字母
of the alphabet and some number, just as you'd propose,
都对应一个数字，正如你所建议的，
both for uppercase and lowercase.
大写和小写都是这样。
So, for instance, if we highlight just a few of these for now
例如，现在如果我们只突出显示其中的几个
and I say that I've just received a text message or an email that,
我说我刚收到了一条短信或一封电子邮件，
underneath the hood, so to speak, if I have the ability
从本质上讲，如果我有能力
to look at what switches are on and off, I received this message here.
查看哪些开关是开着的，哪些是关着的，我收到了这里的信息。
Well, first-- and this is not what CS is about, but just fun fact.
嗯，首先，这不是计算机科学的重点，而是一个有趣的事实。
Does anyone know what number this would represent in decimal,
有人知道这个二进制模式用十进制表示是什么数字吗？
if this is the binary pattern, like ones place, twos place?
比如个位数，两位数？
AUDIENCE: 72?
观众：72？
DAVID J. MALAN: 72 is correct.
大卫·马兰：没错，是 72。
And again, not, intellectually, all that interesting
再说一次，从智力角度来说，这并不算有趣
and this is not the kind of math that we spend all day as CS--
这也不是我们作为计算机科学家整天都在做的那种数学。
a computer scientist doing.
计算机科学家所做的事情。
But it's just following the same darn pattern, which
但这只是遵循同样的模式，
is to say it might look cryptic, but, conceptually,
也就是说，它可能看起来很神秘，但从概念上讲，
intellectually, it ultimately is exactly as we did before.
从智力上讲，它最终和我们以前做的一样。
So, yes, I'll spoil the rest of the math.
好吧，我会透露剩下的数学内容。
It's 72, 73, 33.
是 72，73，33。
Now, anyone remember, in your mind's eye, what message we just spelled?
现在，有人记得我们刚刚拼出的信息吗？
AUDIENCE: Hi.
观众：嗨。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, so it is, in fact, "Hi!"
大卫·马兰：没错，它确实是 “嗨！”
Though, no one really said that excitedly.
虽然，没有人真的那么激动地说。
What's the 33, if you noticed?
你有没有注意到 33 代表什么？
AUDIENCE: Exclamation point.
观众：感叹号。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK, so a lot of people noticed.
好的，所以很多人注意到了。
Yes, it's an exclamation point.
是的，它是一个感叹号。
And that's, indeed, noticeable right here.
而且这确实在这里很显眼。
33 is the exclamation point.
33 就是感叹号。
And that's just something, eventually, that might sink in.
这只是最终可能会逐渐理解的东西。
But, for the most part, if you remember capital A is 65,
但总的来说，如果你记得大写字母 A 是 65，
you can figure out at least 25 other answers to these kinds of questions
你可以找出至少 25 个这类问题的其他答案
because they're all contiguous like that.
因为它们都是像这样连续的。
So there's the exclamation point.
所以这就是感叹号。
But at the end of the day, we might just have this mapping known as ASCII.
但最终，我们可能只需要知道这种称为 ASCII 的映射。
And it's how our phones, and computers, and devices, more
这正是我们的手机、电脑和设备，更
generally, actually store information.
一般来说，存储信息的方式。
So we thought we'd make--
所以我们想做——
maybe take a little pressure off of me here.
也许减轻我这里的一些压力。
And could we maybe flip things around?
我们能不能把事情颠倒过来？
How about we try applying this newfound knowledge--
我们试试运用这种新学到的知识——
if it's, indeed, new to you-- with seven volunteers, seven bits, if we could?
如果你真的没学过——我们可以找七名志愿者，七个比特吗？
OK.
好的。
I saw your hand first.
我看到你的手举得最快。
Come on down.
请过来。
Maybe your hand, there.
也许是你，那边举手的。
OK, three, come on down over here.
好的，第三位，请到这边来。
How about four and five?
第四位和第五位呢？
Yep, come on down.
好的，请过来。
Yep, in the black shirt, yep.
是的，穿黑色衬衫的，是的。
How about let me go farther back?
我能不能往后退一点？
How about in the green, over there?
穿绿衣服的，那边那位呢？
And how about you, seven, over here?
第七位，这边那位呢？
All right.
好的。
Come on down.
请过来。
[CHATTER]
[闲聊声]
Come on down.
请过来。
So a round of applause for our brave volunteers.
让我们为我们勇敢的志愿者们鼓掌。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
All right.
好的。
So if you'd like to stand, roughly, side by side, here in the middle
所以请你们站在一起，大约并排，这里在舞台中央
of the stage.
的位置。
First of all, thank you.
首先，谢谢你们。
Let's see.
让我们看看。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, perfect.
1、2、3、4、5、6、7，完美。
OK.
好的。
And let's go all the way over to this place, here.
让我们走到这里，这边来。
If you would like to introduce yourself to the class.
请你向同学们介绍一下自己。
RACHEL RICHEY: I'm Rachel Richey.
瑞秋·里奇：我叫瑞秋·里奇。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
大卫·J·马兰：好的。
And what year?
你是什么年级？
Anything about you?
关于你，还有什么想说的吗？
RACHEL RICHEY: Oh, first year, concentrating in CS.
瑞秋·里奇：哦，大一，主修计算机科学。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
大卫·马兰：好的。
Welcome to the stage.
欢迎上台。
Next.
下一个。
SPEAKER: Hi.
演讲者：嗨。
I'm [? Kang. ?] Also a first-year concentrating in CS.
我叫[？康？]，也是一名专注于计算机科学的大一学生。
SPEAKER: Hello.
演讲者：你好。
My name is [? Lam. ?] I'm a [INAUDIBLE] student from education department.
我叫[？林？]，是教育系的一名[听不清]学生。
DAVID J. MALAN: Nice.
大卫·马兰：不错。
OK.
好的。
Next.
下一个。
JORDAN MITTLER: Hi.
乔丹·米特勒：嗨。
I'm Jordan Mittler, concentrating in economics and maybe some CS.
我叫乔丹·米特勒，主修经济学，也许还有一些计算机科学。
SPEAKER: So, hi.
演讲者：所以，嗨。
I'm [? Natalia. ?] First year, and I want to do CS.
我叫[？纳塔莉亚？]，大一，我想学计算机科学。
SPEAKER: Hi.
演讲者：嗨。
I'm [? Khadija. ?] I'm a first-year, and I want to do CS.
我叫[？哈迪娅？]，大一，我想学计算机科学。
DAVID J. MALAN: [LAUGHS].
大卫·马兰：[笑]。
SPEAKER: Hello.
演讲者：你好。
I'm [? Caleb. ?] And, once again, first year, concentrating in CS.
我叫[？凯勒布？]，再次强调，大一，主修计算机科学。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
大卫·马兰：好的。
Wonderful.
太棒了。
A pattern, yes.
一个模式，没错。
Thank you.
谢谢。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
So, if you haven't guessed already, each of these volunteers
所以，如果你还没有猜到，这些志愿者
is going to represent a bit, from left to right, or right to left,
将代表一个位，从左到右，或从右到左，
in this case.
在这种情况下。
So let's see.
让我们看看。
If you want to represent-- how about the twos place?
如果你想代表——二位怎么样？
How about the fours place, the eighths place, 16ths place, 32's, 64, and 128?
四位怎么样，八位，十六位，三十二位，六十四位，一百二十八位？
Although, wait a-- I think I screwed up.
虽然，等等——我想我搞错了。
We needed one-- eighth volunteer.
我们需要一个——第八个志愿者。
I think you know-- well, I think--
我想你应该知道——好吧，我认为——
[CLEARS THROAT] Spot?
[清嗓子]斑点？
OK.
好的。
Come on over.
过来吧。
If you guys could step forward a little bit, and then scooch this way,
如果你们能往前走一点，然后往这边挪一下，
just to give Spot some room.
只是给斑点一些空间。
[FOOTSTEPS]
[脚步声]
So Spot will represent the ones place.
所以斑点将代表个位。
Now, what our volunteers have on the back of their sheets of paper
现在，我们的志愿者在纸张的背面
are little instructions.
有一些小说明。
We're going to spell out a three-letter word in English by using three bytes,
我们将用三个字节拼出一个英文三字母单词，
from left to right, because now we have eight volunteers.
从左到右，因为我们现在有八个志愿者。
I'm going to propose that you raise your hand, if you're
我建议如果你是
supposed to represent a 1.
应该代表1。
Or you just stand there, without raising your hand,
或者你就站在那里，不要举手，
if you're meant to represent a 0.
如果你要代表0。
And what we'll have the audience do is do the quick math
我们将让观众做的就是快速计算
to figure out-- one, two, three-- each letter, what number is it.
找出每个字母对应哪个数字，一个一个数，一、二、三。
What letter is it?
对应哪个字母？
And we'll see what word that we have finally spelled.
我们就能看到最后拼出来的单词。
All right.
好的。
So, in round one--
所以，第一轮。
you have instructions on your back of your sheet that will tell you to--
你的纸张背面有指令，告诉你要。
what your number is.
对应哪个数字。
If you're 0, stand there.
如果你是0，就站在那里。
If you're a 1, raise your hand.
如果你是1，就举手。
[PAPER RUSTLING]
[纸张沙沙作响]
What number do these guys seem to be representing?
这些家伙看起来代表哪个数字？
AUDIENCE: 68.
观众：68。
DAVID J. MALAN: 66, I think.
大卫·马兰：我觉得是66。
64 plus 2, so 66, which is the letter--
64加2，所以是66，对应的字母是。
AUDIENCE: B.
观众：B。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK, so, B. OK, so, B. All right.
大卫·马兰：好的，是B，好的，是B。好的。
Hands down.
把手放下。
Second letter is going to be spelled how?
第二个字母怎么拼？
[SPOT LANDS ON THE STAGE]
[斑点出现在舞台上]
AUDIENCE: Whoa.
观众：哇。
DAVID J. MALAN: [LAUGHS] All right.
大卫·马兰：[笑] 好的。
What are we spelling now?
我们现在正在拼什么？
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[模糊的交谈声]
I think-- psst, yep, OK.
我觉得——嘘，是的，好的。
Yeah, I think you're one.
是的，我觉得你是1。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
OK.
好的。
Now what number are we spelling?
现在我们正在拼哪个数字？
AUDIENCE: 79
观众：79
DAVID J. MALAN: 79, I heard, which is the letter?
大卫·马兰：我听到是79，对应哪个字母？
AUDIENCE: O.
观众：O。
DAVID J. MALAN: O. OK.
大卫·马兰：O。好的。
So hands down.
把手放下。
Thank you, Spot.
谢谢你，斑点。
One final flourish.
最后装饰一下。
So we've spelled B-O--
所以我们已经拼出了B-O。
third letter, go ahead.
第三个字母，继续。
[SPOT LANDS ON THE STAGE]
[斑点出现在舞台上]
What number, now, is this?
现在，这个是什么数字？
AUDIENCE: 87.
观众：87。
DAVID J. MALAN: I heard it here, 80--
大卫·马兰：我听到的是80。
AUDIENCE: Seven.
观众：七。
DAVID J. MALAN: --seven, which is?
大卫·马兰：七，对应的是？
AUDIENCE: W.
观众：W。
DAVID J. MALAN: W, which, of course, spells "bow."
大卫·马兰：W，当然，拼出来就是“bow”。
So if our volunteers could take a bow, Spot included.
所以，如果我们的志愿者们可以鞠躬谢幕，包括斑点。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
So this will make more sense in week one,
这在第一周会更有意义，
when we have an assignment involving a certain someone from the Nintendo
当我们有一个作业涉及任天堂的某个人时
World.
世界。
But we have a lovely parting gift for each of you.
但我们为你们每个人准备了一份可爱的临别礼物。
SPEAKER: Thank you.
演讲者：谢谢。
[LAUGHS]
[笑声]
DAVID J. MALAN: Thank you for volunteering.
大卫·J·马兰：感谢您的志愿服务。
SPEAKER: Thanks.
演讲者：谢谢。
DAVID J. MALAN: You might need to share it with the folks next to you.
大卫·J·马兰：你可能需要与你旁边的人分享。
[CHATTER]
[闲聊声]
Oop, here we go.
哎，开始了。
There we go.
来了。
Thank you--
谢谢--
SPEAKER: Thank you.
演讲者：谢谢。
RACHEL RICHEY: Thank you.
瑞秋·里奇：谢谢。
DAVID J. MALAN: --so much.
大卫·J·马兰：--非常感谢。
One more round of applause, if we could, for our volunteers.
如果可以的话，让我们再次为我们的志愿者鼓掌。
Thank you.
谢谢。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
Did you lose something?
你丢了什么吗？
OK.
好的。
All right.
So, [LAUGHS] Spot's had it.
所以，[笑声]斑点已经有了。
So let's see, then, if we've solved, now,
所以让我们看看，我们是否已经解决了，现在
the problem of representing English letters of the alphabet,
表示英语字母表的问题，
being able to spell out words like "bow," B-O-W. What if we actually do
能够拼出像“bow”这样的单词，B-O-W。如果我们实际上
have accented characters?
有重音字符？
What if we do have other glyphs that we want to represent?
如果我们确实有其他我们想要表示的字形？
Well, here, of course, is a standard US English keyboard, which a lot of you
当然，这里是一个标准的美国英语键盘，你们中很多人
might have.
可能拥有。
But there's also characters that you can type much more
但还有你可以更轻松地键入的字符
easily if you have a foreign keyboard, relative to the US,
如果你有一个外国键盘，相对于美国来说，
or with certain keystrokes on your own Mac, PC, and phone.
或者在你的 Mac、PC 和手机上使用某些按键。
But, nowadays, too, there's this menu that, probably, you've
但现在，也有这个菜单，你可能
used in the past hour or two to actually send some emoji.
在过去的一两个小时里使用过，实际上发送了一些表情符号。
An emoji, even though they look like pictures
表情符号，即使它们看起来像图片
and they actually are pictures on the screen,
它们实际上是屏幕上的图片，
they're, technically, just characters, characters of an emoji alphabet
从技术上讲，它们只是字符，表情符号字母表中的字符
that happened to use a certain pattern of 0's and 1's to represent
恰好使用了一种特定的 0 和 1 模式来表示
each of these faces, each of these people, and places, and things.
每张脸，每个人，每个地方，每件事。
And it turns out that one of the reasons that we have just
事实证明，我们现在有这么多[笑声]字符的原因之一是
so many [LAUGHS] such characters nowadays is because we now
现在我们使用的是 Unicode，而不是 ASCII。
use Unicode instead of ASCII.
使用 Unicode 而不是 ASCII。
So Unicode is a superset, so to speak, of ASCII,
所以 Unicode 可以说是 ASCII 的超集，
which is to say that we, humans, realized, some time ago, that just
也就是说，我们人类很早以前就意识到，仅仅
using eight bits to represent letters of the alphabet
使用八位来表示字母表中的字母
certainly isn't very good when we want to represent
当我们想要表示时，肯定不太好
other, non-English languages.
其他非英语语言。
So Unicode doesn't just use eight bits.
所以 Unicode 不仅仅使用八位。
It sometimes uses 16 bits per character, sometimes 24 bits per character,
它有时每个字符使用 16 位，有时每个字符使用 24 位，
and sometimes even 32 bits per character.
有时甚至每个字符有32位。
Now, why those numbers?
为什么是这些数字？
That's just one byte, two bytes, three bytes, or four bytes.
那只是一个字节，两个字节，三个字节或四个字节。
And that gives us--
这给了我们——
does anyone know?
有人知道吗？
That gives us the ability to represent as many as 4
这让我们能够表示多达4
billion possible characters.
十亿个可能的字符。
Because if the longest one is 32 bits, that's 2 to the 32,
因为如果最长的一个是32位，那就是2的32次方，
which, if you do out the math, trust me, is roughly 4 billion.
如果你算一下，相信我，大约是40亿。
So that's a lot of characters.
所以有很多字符。
And we've got a lot of room, then, for these emoji.
然后，我们就有很多空间来容纳这些表情符号。
But it's not just about having fun, pictorially, on the screen.
但这不仅仅是在屏幕上进行图片上的娱乐。
Unicode's mission really is to represent and to preserve all human languages
Unicode的使命确实是代表和保存所有的人类语言
digitally, both past, present, and future.
以数字形式，过去、现在和未来。
So it is really about capturing the entirety of human knowledge,
所以它实际上是关于捕捉人类知识的全部，
as we've expressed it in language, but also
正如我们在语言中表达的那样，但也
giving this newfound ability that's been used centuries ago, too-- in writings,
赋予了这种新发现的能力，几个世纪前也使用过——在写作中，
on walls, and the like-- pictograms via which
在墙壁上等等——象形文字，通过它们
we can still communicate, even independently
我们仍然可以交流，即使是独立地
of our own human language.
摆脱我们自己的语言。
So we'll reduce it, today, to just patterns of 0's and 1's, but
所以今天，我们将它简化为0和1的模式，但是
the problem being solved is much greater and well-beyond CS, itself, there.
要解决的问题要大得多，远远超出了计算机科学本身。
So here is a pattern of 0's and 1's using
所以这里有一个使用0和1的模式
Unicode, so more than eight bits, that represents a very popular emoji, which
Unicode，所以超过8位，它代表了一个非常流行的表情符号，它
might be a bit of a hint.
可能有点提示。
This is the most popular emoji, as of last year, at least,
至少到去年为止，这是最受欢迎的表情符号，
statistically, internationally.
在统计上，在国际上。
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[插话的声音]
DAVID J. MALAN: Does this help?
大卫·J·马兰：这有帮助吗？
It's, roughly, this number here.
它大约是这里这个数字。
No?
没有？
It's this one here.
是这里这个。
So this is the most popular emoji, by most measures, as of last year.
所以这是去年根据大多数衡量标准得出的最受欢迎的表情符号。
But it doesn't always look like this.
但它并不总是这样。
Those of you who have a Mac or an iPhone recognize this symbol, perhaps,
你们中那些拥有Mac或iPhone的人可能认识这个符号，
immediately.
马上就认出来了。
Those of you with Android devices or other platforms
你们中那些使用Android设备或其他平台的人
might notice that it's the same idea, but it's a little bit different.
可能会注意到它是一样的意思，但有一点不同。
And this is because, too, emojis, at the end of the day,
而这也是因为，归根结底，表情符号
just represent character, but those characters can be drawn,
仅仅代表字符，但这些字符可以被画出来，
can be painted in different ways.
可以用不同的方式描绘。
And reasonable people will interpret differently
而理智的人会对这个表情符号进行不同的解读，它的官方名称是“喜极而泣的脸”。
this emoji, whose official name is "face with tears of joy."
And, indeed, Google interprets it a little differently
事实上，谷歌对它的解读与苹果、微软、Meta和其他公司略有不同。
from Apple, versus Microsoft, versus Meta, versus other companies, as well.
So you can almost think of those different companies
所以你几乎可以把这些不同的公司
as having different fonts for emoji.
看作是拥有不同的表情符号字体。
And that really starts to connect things to the world of text and characters.
这实际上开始把这些东西与文字和字符的世界联系起来。
So, just so you've seen it.
所以，你只要见过它就可以了。
More on this, another time.
我们下次再聊这个。
It turns out that emoji and, really, characters, in general,
事实证明，表情符号，以及一般意义上的字符，
we don't use binary 0's and 1's to represent them
我们不会使用二进制的 0 和 1 来表示它们，
because no one, myself included, is going to recognize what's what.
因为没有人，包括我自己，会认出它们是什么。
It's just too much math.
这太数学了。
It's not interesting.
这没有意思。
And even decimal numbers-- that was 4 billion or some--
甚至十进制数字——那是 40 亿或什么的——
I don't remember which number is which.
我不记得哪个数字是哪个了。
So we represent things a little more compactly.
所以我们用更紧凑的方式来表示事物。
And this, too, admittedly, still looks cryptic,
而且这，也不得不承认，看起来仍然很神秘，
but this is a Unicode code point that uses another system, mathematically,
但这是一个 Unicode 代码点，它使用另一个数学系统，
called base-16 or hexadecimal.
叫做十六进制或十六进制。
More on that, another time.
我们下次再聊这个。
But it's just a way of representing numbers even more succinctly,
但这只是一种更简洁地表示数字的方法，
writing less on the screen, because you're using not just 0
在屏幕上写得更少，因为你使用的不仅仅是 0
through 9, as in decimal.
到 9，就像十进制一样。
But you're using A through F, as well, so a few letters
但你也在使用 A 到 F，所以一些字母
of the English alphabet come into play.
也开始发挥作用。
But, for now, that's just a little easier
但现在，这更容易记住一些
to remember, too, for people who care, that that is the number that
对那些关心的人来说，记住，那就是代表
represents "face with tears of joy."
“喜极而泣” 的数字。
But what if we want a customized emoji?
但如果我们想要一个自定义的表情符号呢？
And this, increasingly, is the case.
这种情况越来越普遍了。
Here, for instance, are the five skin tones
例如，这里有五种肤色
that phones, and laptops, and desktops, nowadays, support.
现在手机、笔记本电脑和台式机都支持。
It's based on something called the "Fitzpatrick scale," which essentially
它是基于一个叫做“Fitzpatrick 尺度”的东西，它本质上
categorizes human skin tone into six or, in this case, five
将人类肤色分为六类，或者说是五类
different categories, from lighter to darker.
不同的类别，从浅到深。
But this suggests that, wow, if we want to represent people
但这也说明，哇，如果我们想用
with five different skin tones, like this, that could significantly
五种不同的肤色来表示人，像这样，这可能会显著
increase how many unique patterns of 0's and 1's we
增加我们需要多少个独特的 0 和 1 模式
need for every possible face.
才能表示每张可能的 faces。
But if we think about it from an engineering perspective,
但如果我们从工程的角度考虑，
we can actually just think of skin tone as modifying some default
我们实际上可以把肤色看作是对默认值的一种修改
color, for better or for worse.
颜色，无论好坏。
And yellow is the de facto default, Simpson style.
黄色是事实上的默认值，辛普森一家风格。
But to modify it to look more genuinely human-like, from lighter to darker,
但为了修改它，使其看起来更像人，从浅到深，
well, maybe we just use the same pattern of bits
那么，也许我们只需要使用相同模式的比特
to represent a human thumb, for instance, thumbs up or thumbs down.
来表示一个人的拇指，比如竖起大拇指或竖起大拇指。
And we just, then, modify that character to be displayed with a different skin
然后，我们只需修改那个字符，使其以不同的肤色显示
tone.
色调。
So, for instance, here, then, is the "thumbs up"
例如，这里就是你可能在各种平台上使用的“竖起大拇指”。
that you might use on various platforms.
你可能在各种平台上使用。
And let me just stipulate that this is the Unicode code point.
我需要说明的是，这是一个 Unicode 代码点。
That is the number that Macs, PCs, and phones
这是 Mac、PC 和手机使用的数字
use underneath the hood to represent the default yellow "thumbs up."
在幕后用于表示默认的黄色“竖起大拇指”。
But if you want to give it a medium skin tone,
但如果你想给它一个中等肤色，
you still use that same number, that same pattern of 0's and 1's,
你仍然使用相同的数字，相同的 0 和 1 模式，
or switches, underneath the hood.
或者开关，在引擎盖下面。
But you use a few more switches that the computer or phone
但你需要使用更多的开关，让电脑或手机
will interpret as, "Oh, you don't want to see the default in yellow
理解为，“哦，你不想看到默认的黄色
because of this second number that's in the computer's memory somewhere.
因为在电脑内存中的某个地方，有第二个数字。
You want me to adjust it to be the medium skin tone or any
你想让我把它调整为中等肤色，或者任何
of the other values, instead."
其他值，而不是。”
So that's the engineering solution to this problem
所以这就是这个问题的工程解决方案
of just trying to represent different ranges of emoji here.
就是试图在这里表示不同范围的表情符号。
Well, what about something like this?
好吧，像这样的东西怎么样？
There's a lot more combinatorics, nowadays,
现在，你的键盘上有更多的组合学，
on your keyboard for relationships, for instance.
例如，用于描述关系。
So here is a "couple with heart" here.
所以这里有一个“带心心的情侣”。
So the couple, here, of course, is represented with, apparently,
当然，这里的情侣是用这个数字来表示的，
this number here.
这里这个数字。
But that's it.
但就是这样。
But if you want to be more specific-- like man and woman,
但如果你想更具体——比如男人和女人，
or man-man, woman-woman-- it's the same idea,
或者男男、女女——都是一样的想法，
but we just need to express ourselves a little-- with a little
我们只需要稍微表达一下——用一点
more information.
更多的信息。
So, for instance, the way the Unicode folks came up with,
例如，Unicode 人们想出来的办法是，
years ago, to represent, for instance, a woman with a heart and a man,
几年前，用来表示，例如，一个女人和一个男人，
from left to right, would be using these values.
从左到右，将使用这些值。
So things just escalated quickly, but only
所以事情很快就升级了，但只是
in the sense that we're using more bits, more 0's and 1's, to represent,
从某种意义上说，我们正在使用更多的比特，更多的 0 和 1 来表示，
more expressively, this particular combination.
更富有表现力地，这个特定的组合。
So this happens to be the number in Unicode
所以这恰好是 Unicode 中的数字
that represents the woman at left.
表示左边的女人。
This is the number that represents the man at right.
这是表示右边男人的数字。
And this is the pair of numbers that represents
而这组数字代表着
the heart in the middle, sometimes red, sometimes pink, displayed here as pink.
中间的心，有时是红色，有时是粉色，这里显示的是粉色。
But if we want to change the combination, for instance, to be,
但是如果我们想改变组合，例如，是，
say, woman--
比如，女人——
if we want to change the combination to be woman-woman,
如果我们想改变组合为女女，
notice that, now, the left and the rightmost numbers match.
请注意，现在，最左边和最右边的数字匹配。
Or if we flip it back to man-man, it's just using different numbers
或者如果我们把它翻回到男男，只是使用了不同的数字
on the tail end again.
在末尾。
And meanwhile, if I rewind, there's these two identical values here.
同时，如果我倒回，这里有两个相同的数字。
These are called zero-width joiners or ZWNJ characters.
它们被称为零宽连接符或 ZWNJ 字符。
It just is a special number that humans reserve to say,
它只是一个特殊的数字，人类保留它来表示，
glue the emoji at the left to the emoji on the right and so forth.
将左边的表情符号粘到右边的表情符号上，等等。
So it connects ideas in this way.
所以它以这种方式连接想法。
So there's actually a lot of emojis, nowadays,
所以现在有很多表情符号，
that are a combination of different things.
是不同事物的组合。
"Heart on fire" is one that's, technically,
“心着火了”从技术上讲，
the combination of a heart emoji, the fire emoji,
是心形表情符号和火焰表情符号的组合，
joined together, numerically, in this way.
以这种方式在数字上连接在一起。
So computer scientists who come up with these things
所以想出这些东西的计算机科学家们
are just reducing things to representations.
只是将事物简化为表示。
All we have at our disposal are 0's and 1's.
我们所能利用的只有 0 和 1。
So we all just need to agree, ultimately--
所以我们都需要达成一致，最终——
whether we're Google, Microsoft, or the like-- how we're going to standardize
无论是谷歌、微软还是其他公司——我们要如何标准化
these kinds of things as information.
这些信息。
Questions, then, on how characters are represented in a computer,
那么，关于如何在计算机中表示字符，
be it English or any other language?
无论是英语还是其他任何语言？
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: How is the plus a number?
观众：加号怎么会是一个数字呢？
DAVID J. MALAN: How is the what?
大卫·J·马兰：什么是什么？
AUDIENCE: The plus, the U+.
观众：加号，U+。
DAVID J. MALAN: Oh, the U+ is just a convention, really.
大卫·J·马兰：哦，U+ 只是一个约定俗成的符号，实际上。
So U+ represents a special Unicode character,
所以 U+ 代表一个特殊的 Unicode 字符，
which is a U with a plus in the middle.
它是一个中间带加号的 U。
And this is just the convention for saying,
而这只是一个约定俗成的说法，
hey, everyone, here comes a number that represents a Unicode code point.
嘿，大家好，这里有一个数字代表一个 Unicode 码点。
The U and the 1 have no-- sorry.
U 和 1 没有——抱歉。
The U and the plus have no mathematical significance.
U 和加号没有数学意义。
It's just a visual clue to folks.
它只是给人们一个视觉提示。
Other questions on representing text in this way?
关于以这种方式表示文本的其他问题吗？
All right.
好的。
So what about colors?
那么颜色呢？
We've already started looking at pictures.
我们已经开始看图片了。
Well, how are those pictures, be it emojis or anything else, represented?
那么这些图片，无论是表情符号还是其他任何东西，是如何表示的呢？
One of the most common ways is just with RGB--
最常见的方法之一就是 RGB——
red, green, and blue.
红、绿和蓝。
It turns out that if we just keep track of how much red should
事实证明，如果我们只记录屏幕上应该显示多少红色
be on the screen, and how much green, and how much blue, combined together,
多少绿色，多少蓝色，加在一起，
that gives us every color of the rainbow,
就能得到彩虹的所有颜色，
from white to black and everything in between.
从白色到黑色，以及所有介于两者之间的颜色。
So how do we represent an amount of red, and green, and blue?
那么我们如何表示红色、绿色和蓝色的数量呢？
Well, frankly, just with three different numbers.
坦率地说，就用三个不同的数字。
And this is how computers typically represent colors.
这就是计算机通常表示颜色的方式。
Every one of the dots on your computer screen or your phone screen
您电脑屏幕或手机屏幕上的每一个点
is called a pixel.
被称为像素。
And every single dot underneath the hood has three numbers associated with it,
而每一个点在内部都与三个数字相关联，
so three numbers, three numbers, three numbers for every little dot.
因此，每个小点都有三个数字、三个数字、三个数字。
And those three numbers, together, say how much red, green, and blue
这三个数字加在一起，说明了设备应该在该位置显示多少红色、绿色和蓝色。
should the device display at that location.
应该在该位置显示多少红色、绿色和蓝色。
So, for instance, if you had a dot on your screen
例如，如果你屏幕上有一个点
that said, "use this much red, this much green this much blue," because each
上面写着“使用这么多红色，这么多绿色，这么多蓝色”，因为每一个
of these numbers, I'll tell you, are one byte or eight bits,
这些数字，我告诉你，都是一个字节或八位，
which means the total possible values is 0 to 255--
这意味着可能的总值是 0 到 255——
let me just ballpark that the 72, it feels like a medium amount of red
我估计 72 感觉像是中等量的红色
because it's in between 0 and 255.
因为它介于 0 和 255 之间。
73 is a medium amount of green, and 33 of blue is just a little bit.
73 是一种中等量的绿色，而 33 的蓝色只是一点点。
So if you combine a medium amount of red, green, and a little bit of blue,
因此，如果你将中等量的红色、绿色和一点点蓝色结合起来，
anyone want to guess what color of the rainbow this is?
有人想猜一下彩虹的这种颜色是什么吗？
AUDIENCE: Brown.
观众：棕色。
DAVID J. MALAN: Sorry?
大卫·马兰：你说什么？
AUDIENCE: Brown.
观众：棕色。
DAVID J. MALAN: Brown?
大卫·马兰：棕色？
So, close.
所以，很接近。
It's a little more yellow than it is brown.
它比棕色更偏向黄色。
But if we combine them, it looks a little something like this.
但如果我们把它们结合起来，它看起来有点像这样。
This is just CS trivia, not something that even
这只是计算机科学的小常识，甚至不是
I would be able to eyeball, unless I came up with that particular example.
我能凭肉眼判断出来的，除非是我自己想出了这个特定的例子。
But wait a minute.
等等。
We've seen these numbers before.
我们之前见过这些数字。
72, 73, 33 represented what--
72，73，33 代表什么——
AUDIENCE: Hi!
观众：嗨！
DAVID J. MALAN: --a few minutes ago?
大卫·马兰：——几分钟前？
So it meant "Hi!" but here I am, claiming, no, no, no, no,
所以它代表的是“嗨！”，但现在我说，不，不，不，不，
that means yellow.
它代表的是黄色。
How do you reconcile this?
你如何调和这一点？
Well, at the end of the day, this is all we have,
说到底，这就是我们拥有的全部，
0's and 1's, whether you think of them as numbers,
0 和 1，无论你把它们看作是数字，
or letters, or even colors now.
还是字母，或者现在甚至颜色。
But it depends on the context.
但它取决于上下文。
So if you've received a text message or an email,
因此，如果你收到了短信或电子邮件，
odds are the pattern of 0's and 1's that the computer
很有可能，计算机显示给你的 0 和 1 的模式，将会被解释为文本，因为
is showing you are going to be interpreted as text because that's
短信或电子邮件的全部目的就是如此。
the whole point of a text message or an email.
如果，你打开了 MacOS、iOS、Windows 或 Android 的
If, though, you opened up MacOS's or iOS's or Windows's or Android's
计算器应用程序，相同的 0 和 1 模式可能会
calculator app, the same pattern of 0's and 1's might
被解释为一些加法、减法或其他运算的数字。
be interpreted as numbers for some addition, or subtraction, or whatever.
如果你在 Photoshop 之类的图像处理程序中打开相同的 0 和 1 模式，
If you open the same pattern of 0's and 1's in Photoshop,
它们将在那个上下文中被解释为
like a graphics program, they're going to be interpreted, in that context,
颜色。
as colors.
所以，上下文很重要。
So context matters.
并且，确实，从下周开始，当你
And, indeed, as soon as next week, when you
开始用 C 语言编写代码的时候，
start writing code in that language called C,
你将需要告诉计算机，把
the onus will be on you, the programmer, to tell the computer, interpret
以下位序列解释为数字、字母或其他东西。
the following sequence of bits as a number, or a letter, or something else.
你甚至不需要担心 0 和 1 是什么，
And you won't have to even worry about what the 0's and 1's are,
但你需要给计算机一个提示，告诉它你正在表示什么类型的文件
but you need to give the computer a hint as to what type of file
或数据。
or piece of data you're representing.
这样我们就有了位。
So that gives us bits.
你实际上可以在屏幕上看到这些点，这些像素。
And you can actually see these dots, these pixels on the screen.
让我放大，放大。
Let me zoom in, zoom in.
有了，就用这个表情符号，说到底，它就是一张图片，是苹果公司的人画的。
And here we have it, just with this emoji, which, at the end of the day,
如果你真的放大，或者拿着手机或电视机，
And you can see-- if you really zoom in, or take your phone or TV
离你的脸很近，你就会看到所有的点，
and really put it close to your face, you'll see all of these dots,
这取决于硬件。
depending on the hardware.
每个点，每个方格，都存储着
And each of these dots, these squares, is
24 位，或者 3 个字节，24 位，24 位，24 位。
storing 24 bits or three bytes, 24 bits, 24 bits, 24 bits.
And each of these dots, these squares, is
每一个点，每一个方格，
storing 24 bits or three bytes, 24 bits, 24 bits, 24 bits.
都存储着24位或3字节的信息，24位、24位、24位。
And that's whey, dot, dot, dot, if you've
所以，如果你的
got a photograph, for instance, that's three megabytes, which
照片比如是3兆字节，
is 3 million bytes, well, odds are there's 1 million pixels therein
也就是300万字节，那么很可能里面就有100万像素
because you're using three bytes per pixel
因为你每个像素使用了3个字节
to represent each of those colors.
来表示每一种颜色。
That's a bit of an oversimplification, but that's
这有点过于简化了，但这是
why images and photos are getting bigger and bigger nowadays.
如今图像和照片越来越大的原因。
Because we're throwing even more pixels into the file.
因为我们把更多的像素放进了文件里。
Music--
音乐 -
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
--how could you represent music, digitally,
--如何用数字的方式来表示音乐，
using just 0's and 1's, or numbers, really?
只用0和1，或者说数字？
Any instinct, whether a musician or not?
无论是否音乐家，有什么想法吗？
Yeah.
对。
AUDIENCE: The notes could be represented by a number.
观众：音符可以用数字来表示。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, so we can just represent notes by a number.
大卫·马兰：对，我们可以用数字来表示音符。
So A is some number, and B. And maybe sharp or flat is some other number.
所以A是某个数字，B也是，升音或降音可能是另一个数字。
But note might not be quite enough for some--
但对于一些情况来说，音符可能还不够 -
yeah?
对吧？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Ah, OK.
大卫·马兰：啊，好的。
So one note-- one number to represent the note, itself,
所以一个音符 - 一个数字来表示音符本身，
the sound or the pitch; one other number to represent the duration.
声音或音高；另一个数字来表示持续时间。
In the context of piano, how long is the human holding the key down?
在钢琴的语境下，人按住琴键的时间有多长？
And maybe I can think of a third, the loudness.
也许我可以想到第三个，音量。
How hard has the person played that note?
这个人弹奏音符的力量有多大？
So, minimally, with three numbers, you could
所以，至少需要三个数字，你就可以
imagine representing music, as well.
想象用数字来表示音乐。
And, indeed, that's very well might be what computers
确实，计算机可能就是这样做的
are doing when you listen to sound.
当你听声音的时候。
What about video?
视频呢？
How could you represent videos, as well?
如何用数字来表示视频？
Yeah?
对吧？
AUDIENCE: Through many images.
观众：通过很多图像。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, many images.
大卫·马兰：对，很多图像。
So if you've ever produced a film or looked at some of the fine print,
所以如果你曾经制作过电影或看过一些细则，
30 frames per second, FPS, or 29 frames per second
每秒30帧，FPS，或每秒29帧
is just how many pictures are flying across the screen.
只是指有多少张图片在屏幕上飞过。
But that's really all a video file is on a computer,
但实际上，计算机上的视频文件就是这样的，
lots of pictures moving so quickly in front of us that you and I, our brains,
很多图片在你我面前快速移动，我们的大脑
interpolate that as being actual motion.
把它解读为真实的运动。
And, in fact, from yesteryear, motion pictures,
事实上，从过去，电影，
it's like pictures that are giving the illusion of motion,
就像一些图片在制造运动的错觉，
even though there's only 30 or so of them flying across the screen.
即使实际上只有30张左右的图片在屏幕上飞过。
So we have a way, now, to represent information, both as
所以我们现在有了一种方式，来表示信息，既作为
input and output, whether it's numbers, letters, images, anything else.
输入，也作为输出，无论是数字、字母、图像还是其他任何东西。
Let's now focus on what's inside of that black box,
现在让我们专注于那个黑盒子里面，
so to speak, wherein we have algorithms, step-by-step instructions
可以这么说，我们拥有算法，也就是一步一步的指令
for solving some problem.
用于解决某个问题。
Now, what do I mean by "algorithms" or "step-by-step instructions"?
现在，“算法”或“一步一步的指令”是什么意思呢？
Well, maybe, if we were to turn this into code--
好吧，也许，如果我们要把这个变成代码——
and that's how we'll connect the dots, ultimately, today.
这将是今天我们将最终连接点的方式。
Code is just the implementation, in computers, of algorithms.
代码只是在计算机中对算法的实现。
An algorithm can be something we do in the physical world.
算法可以是我们物理世界中做的事情。
Code is how we implement that exact same idea, in the context of a computer,
代码是我们如何在计算机环境中实现这个相同的想法，
instead.
而不是。
And here, for instance, is a very common application inside of a computer,
例如，这里是在计算机内部非常常见的应用程序，
for your context.
适用于你的背景。
This is the iOS version of the icon.
这是 iOS 版本的图标。
And, typically, if you click on that icon,
通常，如果你点击那个图标，
you'll see something like all of your contacts here,
你会看到所有你的联系人在那里，
typically, alphabetical, by first name or last name.
通常按姓名首字母或姓氏进行字母排序。
And your phone or your computer lets you often search for someone's name
你的手机或电脑通常允许你搜索某个人的姓名
at the very top.
在最上面。
And it will autocomplete, and it'll be pretty darn fast.
它会自动完成，而且速度会很快。
But it'll be pretty darn fast because the programmers who
但速度很快是因为那些
implemented that application are looking for someone quickly for you.
实现这个应用程序的程序员正在为你快速搜索某人。
Now, I can do this old school style, whereby we have one of these things
现在，我可以像老式一样做，我们有一样东西
from yesteryear, an actual phone book.
来自过去，一本真实的电话簿。
So, in a physical phone book like this, you might have 1,000 pages.
所以，在一个像这样的真实的电话簿中，你可能拥有 1000 页。
And on every page are a bunch of names and a bunch of numbers.
每一页都有很多姓名和号码。
And as I flip through this, I could look for someone specific.
而当我翻阅它时，我可以寻找某个特定的人。
So suppose I want to call John Harvard, who's-- the first name, of course,
假设我想打电话给约翰·哈佛，他——当然，名字
starts with a J. Well, I could just turn, page by page,
以 J 开头。好吧，我可以一页一页地翻，
looking for John Harvard.
寻找约翰·哈佛。
And if he's not there, I keep turning and turning.
如果他不在那里，我就继续翻阅。
So this is an algorithm.
所以这就是一个算法。
I'm stepping through the phone book, one page at a time.
我一次翻阅一本电话簿，一次一页。
Is it correct, this algorithm, assuming I'm looking down?
这个算法正确吗，假设我向下看？
So, yeah.
所以，是的。
I mean, it's stupidly slow because why am
我的意思是，它很慢，因为我为什么要
I wasting my time with the A's, and the B's, and the so forth?
浪费时间在 A、B 和其他字母上？
I could probably take bigger bites out of it.
我可能可以更快速地找到它。
But it is correct.
但它确实是正确的。
And that's going to be one of the goals of writing code, is to, of course,
编写代码的目标之一，当然是要
solve the problem you care about correctly.
正确地解决你关心的问题。
So correctness goes without saying, or else what's
所以正确性不言而喻，否则什么
the point of writing the code or solving-- or implementing
编写代码或解决——或实现的意义何在？
the algorithm?
这个算法？
All right.
好吧。
Well, let me at least speed things up.
好吧，至少让我加快速度。
So, instead of one page at a time, so, two, four, six, eight--
所以，不是一次翻一页，而是翻两页、四页、六页、八页——
no, ignore that-- 10, 12, 14, 16, and so forth.
不，忽略那——十页、十二页、十四页、十六页，等等。
It's a little hard to do, physically, but it sounded faster.
物理上做起来有点困难，但听起来更快。
It was twice as fast, theoretically, but is it correct?
理论上来说，速度快了一倍，但是正确吗？
AUDIENCE: No.
观众：不。
DAVID J. MALAN: So, no.
大卫·J·马兰：所以，不。
Why?
为什么？
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah, you might [INAUDIBLE].
观众：是啊，你可能会 [听不清]。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, I might miss John Harvard because, just by accident,
大卫·J·马兰：是的，我可能会错过约翰·哈佛，因为仅仅是偶然，
he might get sandwiched between two pages.
他可能被夹在两页之间。
But do I have to throw the algorithm out altogether?
但是我需要完全放弃算法吗？
Probably not.
可能不会。
Once I reach the K section, which is past the J section,
一旦我到达K部分，也就是过了J部分，
I could double back at least one page, at least, [PATS TELEPHONE BOOK]
我至少可以往回翻一页，至少，[拍拍电话簿]
and just make sure I didn't blow past him completely.
并且确保我不会完全错过他。
So that is twice as fast, because I'm going two pages
所以速度快了一倍，因为我一次翻两页，
at a time, plus one extra step.
同时还要加上一步。
So it's still an improvement.
所以仍然是改进。
So the first algorithm, worst case, if it's
所以第一个算法，最糟糕的情况，如果它不是
not John, but someone whose name starts with Z,
约翰，而是名字以Z开头的某人，
that might take me a full 1,000 steps.
可能需要我翻1000页。
The second algorithm is just 500 steps because I'm
第二个算法只需要翻500页，因为我
going two pages at a time plus one, in case I have to double back,
一次翻两页，再加上一页，以防我需要往回翻，
but that's in the worst case.
但是那是最糟糕的情况。
But most of us in the-- in yesteryear, and what Apple, and Google, and others
但是我们大多数人，在过去，以及苹果、谷歌和其他公司
are actually doing is, in software or here, physically,
实际做的是，在软件中或在这里，在物理上，
we're typically going, roughly, to the middle.
我们通常是，大体上，翻到中间。
Especially if there's no cheat sheet on the side, like A through Z,
特别是如果旁边没有备忘单，比如A到Z，
I'm just going to go to, roughly, the middle.
我就直接翻到，大体上，中间。
And, oh, here I am, not surprisingly, in the M section.
然后，哦，我在这里，不出所料，在M部分。
But what do I now know.
但是我现在知道了什么。
If this is the M section, where is John Harvard?
如果这是M部分，约翰·哈佛在哪里？
So, clearly, to the left, alphabetically.
所以，很明显，在左边，按字母顺序。
And so here is where we can take a much bigger bite out of the problem.
所以这里就是我们能够更有效地解决问题的地方。
We can really divide and conquer this problem
我们真的可以将这个问题分而治之，
by tearing [TEARS BOOK] the problem in half, throwing half of it
通过撕裂[撕开书]问题，丢掉一半，
away, 500 pages away, leaving me with a smaller problem,
丢掉，丢掉500页，留下一个更小的问题，
half as big, that I can really just now repeat.
规模小一半，我就可以重复这个过程。
So I go, roughly, here, and now I'm in the E section.
所以我翻到，大体上，这里，现在我在E部分。
So I went a little too far back.
所以我翻过头了。
But what do I now know?
但是我现在知道了什么？
If this is the E pages, where's John?
如果这是E部分，约翰在哪里？
AUDIENCE: To the right.
观众：在右边。
DAVID J. MALAN: So now he's to the right.
大卫·J·马兰：所以他现在在右边。
So I can-- again, hopefully, he's not on that page.
所以我可以-- 再次，希望他不在那页。
I can tear the problem in half again, throw that 250 pages away.
我可以再次将问题一分为二，扔掉那250页。
And now I've gone from 1,000 to 500 to 250 pages.
现在我已经从1000页变为500页，再变为250页。
Now I'm moving because the first algorithm was one page at a time,
我现在正在移动，因为第一个算法是一次翻一页，
second was two.
第二个算法是一次翻两页。
This is hundreds of pages at a time.
现在是一次翻几百页。
And if I go, roughly, again, to the middle; roughly,
如果我再次，大体上，翻到中间，大体上，
to the middle; roughly, to the middle, hopefully, I'll
翻到中间，大体上，翻到中间，希望我能
find John Harvard on one final page.
在最后一页找到约翰·哈佛。
Can only do this once, but one final page.
只能做一次，但只有一页。
So that invites the question, I would think,
我认为这引出了一个问题，
if the phone book does have 1,000 or so pages,
如果电话簿确实有大约1000页，
how many times can I divide the problem in half to get down to one last page?
我需要将问题分成多少次才能剩下最后一页？
So it's, roughly, 10.
所以大约是10次。
And the quick math is 1,000 goes to 500 to 250 to 125 to 67 something.
快速计算一下，1000 变 500 变 250 变 125 变 67 等等。
So we have to deal with rounding issues, eventually.
所以我们最终需要处理舍入问题。
But assuming we work out the math, it's, roughly, 10 page tears.
但假设我们能算出来，大约需要撕10页。
And that's crazy faster than 1,000 pages and still faster than 500 pages.
这比1000页快很多，而且也比500页快。
So it's fundamentally better.
所以从根本上说，这种方法更好。
And, indeed, if I finally get to that final page, in the software world,
事实上，如果我在软件世界里最终找到了最后一页，
you'd see something like this, John Harvard and his number,
你会看到类似这样的东西，约翰·哈佛和他的号码，
which you're welcome to call or text.
欢迎您打电话或发短信。
But that's how we now have our answer, much like the single page there.
但这就是我们现在得到答案的方式，就像那一页一样。
But let's consider just how efficient that actually is.
但让我们考虑一下它的效率到底有多高。
So here's a very rough, broad-- with broad strokes, a chart.
这是一个非常粗略的图表，用宽泛的笔触绘制。
So here's an xy plot.
这是一个XY图。
So here, on the horizontal, is going to be the size of the problem.
横轴表示问题的大小。
And, by that, I mean, how many pages are we trying to go through?
我的意思是，我们要翻阅多少页？
This would be zero pages.
这里代表0页。
This would be a lot of pages.
这里代表很多页。
How much time does it take to solve the problem?
解决问题需要多长时间？
How long does it take to find John Harvard or anyone else?
找到约翰·哈佛或其他人需要多长时间？
This means no time.
这里代表不需要时间。
This means a lot of time.
这里代表需要很长时间。
So what's the relationship among these algorithms?
那么这些算法之间有什么关系呢？
Well, the first one is actually just a straight line.
第一个算法实际上是一条直线。
If there's n pages in the phone book, well, I
如果电话簿有n页，那么我
claim that it's a one-to-one relationship.
认为它是一一对应的关系。
Because if Verizon or the phone company adds another page next year,
因为如果Verizon或电话公司明年增加了一页，
that just means I might have one more step next year,
就意味着我明年可能要多走一步，
as well, to find John Harvard or anyone else.
才能找到约翰·哈佛或其他人。
But the second algorithm, it's also a straight line,
但是第二个算法也是一条直线，
but it's lower, even though it might not look obvious.
但它更低，尽管可能不太明显。
And what do I mean by that?
我的意思是？
Well, let me just draw some temporary lines.
好吧，让我画一些临时的线。
If this is how many pages are in the phone book-- dot,
如果这是电话簿中的页数 - 点，
dot, dot-- notice that it takes this much time, on the red line,
点，点 - 注意，在红线上，解决问题需要这么长时间。
to solve the problem.
解决问题。
But if I, instead, use the second algorithm,
但如果我使用第二个算法，
it takes me half as much time.
我需要的时间只有原来的一半。
So, even though they're both straight lines,
所以，尽管它们都是直线，
one is strictly lower than the other, which means it's faster.
但其中一个严格低于另一个，这意味着它更快。
It's better.
它更好。
But the third algorithm is a fundamentally different shape,
但第三个算法的形状完全不同，
and it looks a little something like this.
看起来有点像这样。
And it looks like it's going to flatten, flatten, flatten out,
看起来它会越来越平坦，越来越平坦，越来越平坦，
but it never does.
但它从未做到。
It just rises ever so slowly.
它只是非常缓慢地上升。
And what this means is that if maybe Cambridge and Allston, here
这意味着，如果也许剑桥和奥尔士顿，在这里
in Massachusetts, merge next year, so we go from 1,000 page phone book
在马萨诸塞州，明年合并，所以我们会从 1000 页的电话簿
to a 2,000 page phone book, that means, if we're here this year,
变成 2000 页的电话簿，这意味着，如果我们今年在这里，
we're over here next year.
我们明年就在这里。
It's not all that much higher.
它并没有高出那么多。
But it would be much higher if we were using the first two algorithms.
但如果我们使用前两个算法，它会高很多。
Why?
为什么？
It'd be an extra 1,000 steps to find someone in that combined phone
在那个合并后的电话簿中找到一个人，需要额外 1000 步
book or maybe another 500 steps.
或者可能是另外 500 步。
But, to be clear, if we're using my third and final algorithm,
但是，明确地说，如果我们使用我的第三个也是最后一个算法，
how many more steps will it take me next year,
明年我需要多走几步，
when Cambridge and Allston merge into one 2,000-page phone book?
当剑桥和奥尔士顿合并成一本 2000 页的电话簿时？
Just one more step, no big deal.
只多走一步，没什么大不了的。
It's one more page tear.
多翻一页。
And this is what we mean, ultimately, about not just writing
最终，这就是我们所说的，不仅仅是编写
code or implementing algorithms that are correct, but, now,
代码或实现正确的算法，而是现在，
that are well-designed or efficient, specifically.
设计良好的或高效的算法，具体来说。
And this is what makes someone a better programmer, perhaps,
这就是也许让某个人成为比其他人更好的程序员的原因，
than someone else, or a better problem-solver than someone else,
或者成为比其他人更好的问题解决者，
is acquiring, over time, these skills.
是随着时间的推移，掌握这些技能。
So that, sure, you could solve the problem quickly and dirtily,
所以，当然，你可以快速而粗糙地解决问题，
so to speak, but if you're going to have a lot of data
可以这么说，但如果你要处理大量数据
eventually, be it in your phone book or maybe your Google website index,
最终，无论是你的电话簿，还是你的谷歌网站索引，
if you're searching the web, you're going
如果你在搜索网页，你将
to want to try to think about how to design algorithms that look like this.
想要尝试思考如何设计看起来像这样的算法。
Mathematically, this is called a logarithm.
从数学上讲，这被称为对数。
And it's log base 2 because I'm halving, halving, halving, again and again.
它是以 2 为底的对数，因为我一直在不断地二分。
But, for now, just know that it's a fundamentally faster and different
但现在，只要知道它本质上更快，并且形状不同
shape.
即可。
So, among our goals in CS50, ultimately, is not just
所以，CS50 的目标之一，最终不仅仅是
to write and solve problems correctly, but, ultimately, ever more efficiently,
编写并正确解决问题，而是最终，越来越高效，
as well.
也是。
Any questions, then, on these ideas of efficiency and design?
那么，关于效率和设计的想法，有什么问题吗？
Any questions here?
这里有人有疑问吗？
Yeah, in back?
好的，后排？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: A good question.
大卫·J·马兰：好问题。
Just to repeat it, can a graph like this capture the accuracy of the algorithm?
我再说一遍，这样的图表能反映算法的准确性吗？
Short answer, no.
简单来说，不能。
For instance, if I drew a straight line that
例如，如果我画一条直线，
is super low on this graph, which would imply that the algorithm takes
在这张图上很低，这意味着算法所用时间
the same amount of time, no matter how many pages there are,
与页数无关，始终相同，
my algorithm might actually be to just pull a random page from the phone
我的算法实际上可能是从电话簿中随机抽取一页，
book, one step, and say, here it is.
一步，然后说，就是它了。
But that's not necessarily going to be accurate,
但这不一定准确，
unless I get really, really lucky.
除非我真的很幸运。
So the graph really only speaks to efficiency
所以图表只反映了效率
and the design of the algorithm, not the correctness of it.
以及算法的设计，而不是它的正确性。
To analyze the correctness, you need to use another mechanism altogether,
要分析正确性，你需要使用完全不同的机制，
namely, logic.
即逻辑。
Other questions now, on efficiency, in this way?
现在还有其他关于效率的问题吗？用这种方法？
No?
没有？
All right.
好的。
So, with that in mind, let's begin to translate this to some actual code.
有了这些，让我们开始把这些翻译成一些实际的代码。
And, in fact, before we look at, today, one actual programming language,
事实上，在我们今天看一种实际的编程语言之前，
albeit a graphical one, let's consider something called pseudocode.
尽管是一种图形化的语言，让我们考虑一下叫做伪代码的东西。
So pseudocode has no formal meaning.
所以伪代码没有正式的含义。
Generally, you write it in English or whatever your own human language is.
通常，你用英语或你自己的语言来写它。
But you write your thoughts down tersely, succinct, but precisely.
但你要简洁、简明、精确地写下你的想法。
You try to really convey your thoughts, not with a wave of the hand,
你要努力地传达你的想法，而不是用手势，
metaphorically, but step by step, precisely.
用比喻的方式，而是一步一步地，精确地。
So what do I mean by this?
我的意思是什么呢？
Here might be some representative pseudocode
这里可能有一些代表性的伪代码
via which I describe that third and final algorithm in a way
通过它，我用一种方法描述了第三个也是最后一个算法
that I could hand it to you and you could do the same at home.
我可以把它交给你，你也可以在家里做同样的事。
Or I could hand it to someone at Google, and they could implement it in Android.
或者我可以把它交给谷歌的人，他们可以在安卓上实现它。
Or I could hand it to someone at Apple, and they could implement it in iOS.
或者我可以把它交给苹果的人，他们可以在 iOS 上实现它。
So, step one, I claimed, was "Pick up phone book."
所以，第一步，我声称是“拿起电话簿”。
Step two was "Open to the middle of the phone book."
第二步是“打开电话簿的中间”。
Step three, "Look at the page," as I did.
第三步，“看看那页”，就像我做的那样。
And now things get a little more interesting.
现在事情变得有趣起来。
Step four, "If person is on page," I have to make a decision.
第四步，“如果这个人在这页上”，我必须做出决定。
Presumably, what should I do if John Harvard is on the page I'm looking at?
我想，如果我正在看的页面上有约翰·哈佛，我应该怎么办？
So stop and probably make the call, or email, or whatever the goal might be.
所以停下来，可能要打电话，或者发邮件，或者无论目标是什么。
And so I'm going to actually indent this, visually, by a few spaces,
所以我要用一些空格来缩进它，在视觉上，
just to make clear that you should only do line five if the answer to line four
只是为了说明，你只有在第四行的答案是
is yes.
是“是”的时候，才能做第五行。
Otherwise, you don't bother.
否则，你就别管了。
The next thing I'm going to do, line six, is consider another possibility.
接下来我要做的是，第六行，考虑另一种可能性。
"If the person I'm looking for is earlier
“如果我正在找的人在
in the book," what do I want to do?
书里，”我想要做什么？
Well, I could write--
好吧，我可以写——
I could describe this in a bunch of ways.
我可以用很多方法来描述它。
I'm going to do this tersely, as follows.
我将用以下简洁的方式来做。
"Open to the middle of the left half of the book,
“打开书的左边一半的中间，
so it's open to the middle of the left half of the book.
这样它就打开了书的左边一半的中间。
And then, what am I going to do?
然后，我要做什么？
Well, I've just divided the problem into something smaller.
好吧，我刚刚把问题分解成更小的一部分。
But it's fundamentally the same problem.
但它基本上是同一个问题。
It's just a fewer number of pages.
只是页数更少。
So I'm just going to go back to line three and do it again
所以我只需要回到第三行，再做一遍
because the problem is just getting smaller and smaller, presumably.
因为这个问题正在不断变小，可以推测。
Else, if the person I'm looking for is later in the book,
否则，如果我要找的人在书的后面，
open to the middle of the right half of the book,
翻到书右边一半的中间，
and, also, "Go back to line 3."
并且，还要“回到第3行”。
But there's a fourth possibility and its failure
但是还有第四种可能性，而且它也无法实现，
to realize, sometimes, that there's other possible outcomes that
有时候，无法意识到还存在其他可能的结果，这些结果
make computers crash, or spinning beach balls, or the like,
会导致电脑崩溃，或者出现转圈的沙漏，或类似情况，
if a programmer doesn't anticipate some situation.
如果程序员没有预料到某种情况的话。
What's the fourth possible situation, when looking for John Harvard?
当要寻找约翰·哈佛时，第四种可能的状况是什么？
AUDIENCE: If they're not in the book.
观众：如果他不在书里。
DAVID J. MALAN: If they're not in the book, at all.
大卫·马兰：如果他根本不在书里。
And, indeed, I might get to the very last page and John Harvard's not even
事实上，我可能会翻到最后一页，但约翰·哈佛甚至
on that one.
不在那一页上。
I'd better handle that and say, else, as a catchall, just quit altogether.
我最好处理这种情况，并用一个万能方法，直接退出程序。
And, truly, often, in your Macs, PCs, phones,
实际上，在你的Mac、PC、手机中，
when they freeze, or, again, spinning beach ball, or the like,
当它们卡住，或者再次出现转圈的沙漏，或类似情况时，
and just weird things happen, that's just
而且出现一些奇怪的情况，这仅仅是因为
because some human made a dumb mistake.
某些人犯了一个愚蠢的错误。
And they didn't realize that you could somehow get your phone or your laptop
他们没有意识到你可能以某种方式让你的手机或笔记本电脑
into a configuration that they didn't anticipate.
进入他们没有预料到的配置。
So we're going to try to handle that here.
所以我们将在代码中尝试处理这种情况。
Now this is just one way of writing pseudocode.
这仅仅是编写伪代码的一种方法。
There's no one way to do this.
没有唯一的正确方法。
All of us in this room could come up with slightly different pseudocode.
我们每个人都可以想出略微不同的伪代码。
But I think you'll find characteristic are certain building
但我认为你会发现，在所有人的答案中，某些基本
blocks in all of our answers.
模块是相同的。
Here, in yellow, are what, as of today, we're
这里，用黄色标注的，就是我们今天开始称之为“函数”的东西，严格来说。
going to start calling "functions," technically speaking.
它们就像动作或动词，在本例中，它们实际上告诉我
These are like actions or verbs that literally, in this case, tell me
该做什么。
what to do.
下一步，我们将介绍这些叫做“条件语句”的东西，
Next, we're going to have these things, conditionals,
它们就像岔路口，将我引向不同的路径，
forks in the road, so to speak, that take me down this path or another,
打个比方。
metaphorically.
所以我做这件事，或者做其他事。
So I do this thing or something else.
但我该如何决定是想走这条路，还是走那条路，
But how do I decide if I want to go this way, or this way,
还是走这条路，还是走那条路呢？
or this way, or this way?
我需要问一个问题。
I need to ask a question.
在编程中，我们通常使用叫做布尔表达式的东西，
And in programming, we'll typically use what
以一位数学家布尔的姓名命名。
are called Boolean expressions, named after a mathematician, Boole.
布尔表达式本质上只是一个
And a Boolean expression is essentially just a question
带有是/否答案，真/假答案，1/0答案的问题。
with a yes/no answer, a true or false answer, a 1 or 0 answer.
无论你如何思考，它都有两种可能的答案。
It doesn't matter how you think about it, but it's got two possible answers.
所以你可以将它们看作带有问号的表达式，
And so you can think of these as being expressions with question marks,
尽管我没有画出来。
even though I didn't draw such.
“人是否在该页上”、“人是否在书的前半部分”、“人是否在书的后半部分”，
Person on page, person earlier in book, person later in book,
这些都是布尔表达式。
those are Boolean expressions.
它们告诉我应该走哪一条岔路。
And they tell me whether I should go down one fork in the road or another.
And, lastly, there's this, "Go back to line 3," in two different places.
最后，这里有两处写着“返回第 3 行”。
That represents what we call a "loop," some kind of cycle that's
它们代表着我们所说的“循环”，某种周而复始的循环，
doing something again and again.
一遍又一遍地执行某件事。
Now these are just a few building blocks here--
这些只是一些简单的构建模块——
functions, conditionals, Boolean expressions, loops.
函数、条件语句、布尔表达式和循环。
But you'll find that they're characteristic of so
但你会发现它们是如此多
many different languages, one of which we'll look at today, another of which
不同语言的特征，其中一种我们将今天学习，另一种我们将在下周学习。
we'll look at next week.
下周我们将学习。
And those include, indeed, C, and Python, and other languages still.
它们确实包括C语言、Python语言以及其他语言。
And so this is why we focus on these basics
所以这就是为什么我们在这些早期阶段专注于这些基础知识
and fundamentals in these early days because we're
和基础原理，因为我们将会
going to see them again and again.
一遍又一遍地看到它们。
So even if you feel like that fire hose is hitting you sometime,
所以即使你感觉有时像水管一样喷到你身上，
we'll give you, today, ultimately, more visuals
我们今天最终会给你更多视觉效果
by which you can hang onto, so as to actually write code, ultimately,
让你可以抓住，以便最终实际编写代码，
in different languages and solve all sorts of problems.
用不同的语言解决各种问题。
Now, we'd be remiss in not bringing up what's behind characters like Spot,
现在，我们不提像Spot这样的角色背后的东西是不对的，
and ChatGPT, and other software, artificial intelligence.
还有ChatGPT以及其他软件，人工智能。
And it turns out, to get to the point of AI,
事实证明，要达到人工智能的水平，
we're actually going to need more building blocks than just
我们实际上需要更多构建模块，而不仅仅是
functions, and loops, and conditionals.
函数、循环和条件语句。
It's not going to be quite that simple.
这并不像看起来那样简单。
But this has been a lot, so far.
但到目前为止，这已经很多了。
Let's go ahead, here, and take a five-minute break.
让我们现在就休息五分钟。
And when we resume, we'll take a look not only at AI,
休息过后，我们不仅要看看人工智能，
but also a specific language called Scratch.
还要看看一种叫做Scratch的特定语言。
So no cake, just yet, but we'll come back in five.
所以现在还没有蛋糕，但我们五分钟后回来。
Before we dive back in, I just wanted to call out a special guest
在我们深入研究之前，我想介绍一位特殊的嘉宾
that we have here today, beyond Spot, someone
今天，除了Spot之外，还有人
who's come from even farther away.
来自更远的地方。
And, in fact, if any of you have taken CS50x, the OpenCourseWare version
事实上，如果你们中有任何人在过去几年里参加过CS50x，也就是开放课程项目版本
of the class, or dabbled in it over the past few years
的课程，或者在过去几年里尝试过它
in some of CS50's online social communities,
在CS50的一些在线社交社区里，
you might have had your questions answered
你可能得到了你的问题的解答
by a certain human from New Zealand.
来自新西兰的某个人。
And she's come all this way, today, to spend this lecture with us.
她今天不远千里来到这里，和我们一起听课。
This is CS50's own Brenda Anderson.
她是CS50自己的Brenda Anderson。
If you might come up for acknowledgment from all of us here.
如果你愿意的话，可以上来让我们大家认识一下。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
It's not much, but just a little token of our thanks.
这不算什么，只是我们的一点谢意。
Brenda has helped, truly, thousands of students online
多年来，Brenda在线上帮助了成千上万的学生。
for the past many years.
多年来，她帮助了成千上万的学生。
And, in fact, her own daughter has been the artist
事实上，她的女儿一直是
behind the duck that's about to loom large in CS50 this year and beyond.
CS50今年及以后将会出现的鸭子的艺术家。
So, thank you to Brenda.
所以，感谢Brenda。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
All right.
好的。
So it's hard to escape a discussion of artificial intelligence, nowadays,
如今，人们很难回避关于人工智能的讨论，
but we thought we'd use this as an opportunity
但是我们想借此机会
to connect some of these dots.
将这些点连接起来。
Because, indeed, over the course of the semester,
因为，事实上，在整个学期中，
we'll be-- not only be talking about artificial intelligence or AI,
我们将不仅仅谈论人工智能或AI，
but really using it all the more constructively
而是真正更具建设性地使用它
to help you solve problems, help you get unblocked
帮助你解决问题，帮助你克服障碍
when you hit a wall, cognitively or syntactically, when writing code.
当你遇到障碍时，无论是认知上的还是语法上的，无论何时在写代码。
And, indeed, it's no accident that we have this duck here,
而且，事实上，我们在这里有这只鸭子并非偶然，
looming large, which is really the embodiment of the sort of AI
它占据着很大空间，它真正体现了今年 CS50 中的 AI 类型。
that you'll experience within CS50, itself, this year.
今年在 CS50 本身中，你会体验到这种 AI。
So let's talk about the so-called chatbots that
所以让我们谈谈所谓的聊天机器人，
inspired some of those headlines with which we began
激发了我们开始上课时的一些标题，
class, that weren't quite on the nose.
这些标题并不完全切题。
So the class will still be taught by us humans,
所以这门课仍然由我们人类教授，
but helped by this CS50 duck, a chatbot of sorts.
但在某种程度上，由这只 CS50 鸭子提供帮助。
Now what do I mean by this?
我现在是什么意思？
Well, it turns out that, when it comes to implementing something
事实证明，当谈到实现某件事时
like an artificial intelligence, we don't quite
比如人工智能，我们并不完全
have all of the building blocks yet, certainly after just today's week zero,
拥有所有构建块，当然，仅仅过了今天的第零周，
to implement something like that.
要实现这样一件事。
But I think we can skate in that direction, intellectually.
但我认为我们可以在智力上朝那个方向前进。
So, for instance, if we were to take a stab at implementing our own chatbot--
例如，如果我们要尝试实现我们自己的聊天机器人——
some interactive text-based program that talks to us,
一些与我们交谈的交互式基于文本的程序，
and answers questions, and the like-- we could
并回答问题等等，我们可以
try borrowing some of today's ideas already, those functions, conditionals,
尝试借用一些现有的想法，比如函数，条件语句，
loops, and more.
循环等等。
And I could write something like this.
我可以写一些类似的东西。
If I am writing code or pseudocode for a chatbot,
如果我正在为聊天机器人编写代码或伪代码，
I could program the chatbot to do something like this.
我可以编写聊天机器人做一些类似的事情。
If the student says, hello, to the chatbot,
如果学生对聊天机器人说，你好，
then the chatbot should say, hello, back.
那么聊天机器人应该回答，你好。
Else, if the student says, goodbye, well, the chatbot
否则，如果学生说再见，那么聊天机器人
should say, goodbye, back.
应该回答再见。
Else, if the student asks how you are, the chat bot should say that it's well.
否则，如果学生问你好吗，聊天机器人应该说它很好。
But things get a little harder when you start
但当你开始时，事情就变得有点难了
asking more interesting questions, like, else,
问一些更有趣的问题，比如，否则，
if the student asks why 111 in binary is 7 in decimal.
如果学生问为什么二进制的 111 等于十进制的 7。
Now, you could imagine that we just have a conditional,
现在，你可以想象我们仅仅有一个条件语句，
with this Boolean expression, that programs the chatbot to just give you
使用这个布尔表达式，让聊天机器人直接给你
the answer and explain, in an English sentence, why that, in fact, is.
答案，并用英文句子解释为什么它是这样。
But what if you, the student, asks why 110 is 6 in decimal or why 010 is 2?
但如果你是学生，问为什么 110 等于十进制的 6 或者为什么 010 等于 2 呢？
I mean, you can just imagine the explosion in the amount of code
我的意思是，你可以想象，我们必须编写大量的代码来预测你可能问的每一个问题，
that we would have to write to just anticipate every darn question that you
不仅是关于今天和每节课的，而且还包括宇宙中所有知识。
might ask about today and every other class, not to mention all
可能问到的每一个问题，不仅是关于今天和每节课的，而且还包括宇宙中所有知识。
of the knowledge in the universe.
So, surely, there are other ways to implement algorithms
因此，当然，还有其他方法可以实现算法
that allow something like a chatbot or AI,
允许像聊天机器人或人工智能这样的东西
more generally, to be fed input, still, like all of the internet, all
更普遍地说，是向其提供输入，仍然，就像互联网一样，所有
of the worldwide web, all of the pages and textual content therein,
万维网，所有其中的页面和文本内容
but to let it just figure out how to answer our questions based
但是让它只是弄清楚如何根据我们的问题来回答
on those kinds of inputs, assuming the inputs, themselves, are accurate.
这些类型的输入，假设输入本身是准确的。
So "large language models" is a term you might
所以“大型语言模型”是一个你可能
have heard bandied about over the past several months, or LLMs.
在过去几个月听到过，或 LLMs。
And a large language model really is an implementation, in software,
而大型语言模型实际上是在软件中实现的
of code that actually takes, as input, lots and lots of language--
代码，它实际上以输入的形式接受大量语言——
like the text of lots and lots of web pages, dictionaries, encyclopedias,
像大量网页、词典、百科全书的文本
Wikipedias, and the like--
维基百科等
and infers, from the patterns of English words or any human language,
并从英语单词或任何人类语言的模式中推断出
what a typical human might actually say when asked a question.
当被问到问题时，一个普通人实际上会说些什么。
And some of these questions are easy, right?
其中一些问题很简单，对吧？
Probably, on the internet, alone, not to mention everyday life, if someone
可能，仅在互联网上，更不用说日常生活了，如果有人
extends their hand and says, "Hi.
伸出手说，“你好。
How are you," odds are, with 90% probability, you're going to say,
你好吗，”很有可能，有 90% 的概率你会说
"Good.
“很好。
Thanks.
谢谢。
How are you?"
你好吗？”
So I bet we could write software that just
所以，我敢肯定我们可以编写软件，它只是
infers what it should say, probabilistically, statistically, based
根据这些模式，在概率上、统计上推断出它应该说些什么
on those kinds of patterns online.
在那些网络模式上。
And that's, indeed, where the world is starting
而这确实是世界正在开始的地方
to go, when it comes to the most sophisticated
前进，当谈到最复杂的
of algorithms, where you and I, the humans,
算法，你和我，人类
we don't try to anticipate every possible input.
我们不试图预料所有可能的输入。
Rather, we give it a more general purpose
相反，我们给它一个更通用的目的
input, like all human knowledge, and ideally just let it figure things out.
输入，就像所有的人类知识一样，理想情况下，只让它自己弄清楚。
Now, we're not quite there, yet.
现在，我们还没有完全做到。
And odds are you've heard of hallucinations or just mistakes
而且，你很可能听说过幻觉或这些大型语言模型犯的错误
that these large language models make.
这些大型语言模型所犯的错误。
But their inputs are imperfect.
但它们的输入是不完美的。
And sometimes there's a bit of randomness sprinkled
有时，会有一些随机性散布在其中
in because you don't want the thing to always say the exact same thing.
因为你不想让它总是说完全一样的话。
Even you and I might say, "Eh, I'm not that great today" 10% of the time.
即使你和我都可能说：“嗯，我今天不太好。” 10% 的时间。
So you need to perturb the output in some way.
所以你需要以某种方式扰乱输出。
But within CS50 and within this world of large language models,
但在 CS50 以及大型语言模型的世界中
we do have these tools like ChatGPT, and Bing, chat, and others.
我们确实拥有像 ChatGPT、Bing Chat 以及其他工具。
And we'll stipulate that, for CS50's purposes,
并且我们规定，为了 CS50 的目的
the direction we're going this year is that this
我们今年的方向是，这
is what's in the syllabus, dot, dot, dot;
是课程大纲中的内容，等等；
that it will not be allowed, it will be considered
不允许使用它，它将被认为
not reasonable to use AI-based software, other than CS50's own.
使用基于人工智能的软件是不合理的，除了 CS50 自己开发的软件以外。
So the goal here is not to simply take away
所以这里的目标不是简单地拿走
tools that are clearly inevitable, in my view, and clearly helpful
在我看来，这些工具是不可避免的，而且非常有用
and productivity savers.
并且可以提高生产力。
But we'd like there to be some guardrails, intellectually, on just how
但是，我们希望在智力上对这些聊天机器人到底有多有用设置一些限制。
helpful these chatbots are.
这些聊天机器人到底有多有用。
Because as you've probably seen, if you ask it a question,
因为你可能已经看到了，如果你问它一个问题，
these chatbots are already pretty good at not just helping
这些聊天机器人已经很擅长不仅仅帮助你完成当前的想法，而且
you finish your current thought, but it'll
帮助你完成当前的想法，而且
hand you your second and your third thought and do the assignment for you.
它会帮你完成第二个、第三个想法，并替你完成作业。
But I think, through prompting, so to speak,
但我认为，通过提示，可以这样说，
we'll be able to coax some of our own tools,
我们将能够引诱一些我们自己的工具，
being computer scientists, ourself, in a direction
作为计算机科学家，我们自己，朝着一个方向
that you actually find to be the right balance, akin to having
一个你认为是正确平衡的方向，就像有一个
a good tutor by your side 24/7, who doesn't just hand you answers,
一个全天候在你身边的好导师，他不会直接给你答案，
but, indeed, tries to lead you to the same.
而是试图引导你得到同样的答案。
So you actually get something out of the experience,
所以你真的从这次经历中得到了些什么，
and, ideally, three-plus months from now,
而且，理想情况下，三个多月后，
those training wheels can come off, too.
这些辅助轮也可以脱掉了。
And you're able to still stand on your own.
你仍然能够独立站立。
So it will be reasonable to use CS50's own AI-based software which
所以，使用 CS50 自行研发的基于 AI 的软件是合理的，它
will actually take the form of a CS50 duck, which is actually available now--
实际上会以一只 CS50 鸭子的形式出现，它现在已经可以使用了——
and we'll use it throughout the term-- at CS50.ai, a web-based application
并且我们将在整个学期使用它——在 CS50.ai，一个基于 web 的应用程序
that's quite similar to ChatGPT, but that
非常类似于 ChatGPT，但是
has the personality of a CS50 teaching fellow or TF, or teaching assistant,
拥有一个 CS50 教学助理或 TF，或教学助理的个性，
TA, that also happens to think of itself as a duck.
TA，它恰好把自己当作一只鸭子。
And for reasons we'll get to in a couple of weeks time,
至于原因，我们将在几周后谈到，
but rubber ducks, in particular, are a thing in programming.
但橡胶鸭子，尤其是在编程中，是件大事。
But more on that, before long, as you can even see from the one
但很快就会有更多关于这方面的内容，你甚至可以从我桌上那只
there on my desk.
我桌上的那只看到。
With that said, too, well, I'm going to call out CS50's own Brenda
话虽如此，我还要提到 CS50 的布伦达
Anderson, whose daughter, Sophie, kindly not only created
安德森，她的女儿索菲，不仅好心地创造了
the first incarnation, digitally, of this duck, but also,
这只鸭子的第一款数字版本，而且，
most recently, once it actually did more than quack a random number
最近，当它不再只是对问题进行随机次数的嘎嘎叫时，它现在
of times in response to questions, has now
对问题的回答不再是随机次数的嘎嘎叫，它现在
been virtually brought to life, too.
也变成了虚拟生命。
So, all that and more, over the coming weeks, but you'll find, ultimately,
所以，所有这些以及更多，将在接下来的几周内出现，但你最终会发现，
that the goal is to really bring to life the availability of an AI-based tutor
目标是真正实现一个基于 AI 的导师的可用性，
that you have access to, a friend in your--
你可以访问它，一个你的朋友，在你的——
next to you, that will help guide you through a lot of the course's
旁边，它将帮助你克服课程中的许多
challenges along the way.
挑战。
And we actually rolled it out this past summer,
我们实际上在过去夏天就推出了它，
already, with some of your predecessors, through the Harvard Summer School.
已经，与你们的一些前辈，通过哈佛暑期学校。
One student wrote, at summer's end, that this duck
一位学生在夏天结束时写道，这只鸭子
"felt like having a personal tutor--
“感觉就像有一个私人导师——
I love how AI bots will answer questions without ego and without judgment
我喜欢 AI 机器人回答问题的方式，没有自负，也没有评判，
generally entertaining even the stupidest of questions
总体来说很有趣，即使是那些最愚蠢的问题
without treating them like they're stupid.
都不会让人觉得他们在被愚弄。
It has, as one could expect, an inhuman level of patience."
它正如你所想的那样，拥有超乎常人的耐心。”
So there's actually something really there because as many teachers
所以确实有一些东西在那里，因为像CS50一样多的老师
as there are in CS50--
在CS50中——
myself, the course's preceptors, teaching fellows, teaching assistants,
我自己，课程的指导老师，助教，教学助理
and course assistants-- there's only so many of us.
以及课程助理——我们的人数是有限的。
And we're only awake so many hours of the day.
而且我们一天只能清醒那么长时间。
And I think you'll find, too, that we're on the cusp of something
而且我认为你也会发现，我们正处于某种事物即将到来的边缘
pretty remarkable, in the coming years, where
在未来几年里，它将非常显著，那里
it's going to get a lot more enabling, now, to learn material
现在将变得更加容易，学习材料
not only within the confines of a class, but on your own, ultimately, as well.
不仅限于课堂，最终也可以自学。
And as one other student put it, at summer's end, with respect to the duck,
正如一位学生在夏天结束时谈到鸭子时所说，
"Love love loved the duck.
“爱爱爱鸭子。
We're friends now."
我们现在是朋友了。”
So that, too, awaits.
所以，这也等待着你。
But, first, we're going to need to start with the basics.
但是，首先，我们需要从基础开始。
And we started today by talking about binary.
我们今天开始谈论二进制。
And darn it, here it is again.
而且，它又出现了。
So we can't actually get to the point of using, or solving, or implementing AI
所以我们实际上还不能使用，解决，或者实现AI
until we understand this.
直到我们理解它。
And odds are most of you won't know, at a glance, what this piece of software
而且很有可能，你们中的大多数人乍一看不会知道这部分软件
does.
做什么。
But these are the 0's and 1's that represent, perhaps,
但这些是代表的0和1，也许是，
the first program that any programmer writes, which is now a clue to some
任何程序员编写的第一个程序，现在这对你们中一些之前接触过代码的人来说是一个提示。
of you who have dabbled in code before.
你们中之前接触过代码的人来说是一个提示。
What does this pattern of 0's and 1's tell a typical computer to do?
这个0和1的模式告诉典型的计算机做什么呢？
Might someone guess?
有人能猜出来吗？
AUDIENCE: "Hello, world."
观众：“你好，世界。”
DAVID J. MALAN: It's going to have it say, "hello, world,"
大卫·J·马兰：它会让它说，“你好，世界，”
which is one of the very first programmer-- programs
这是大多数程序员编写的第一批程序之一
that most any programmer writes.
这是大多数程序员编写的第一批程序之一。
Should you be able to recognize these 0's and 1's?
你应该能认出这些0和1吗？
Do I recognize these 0's and 1's?
我能认出这些0和1吗？
No, not at all.
不，完全不能。
I just happen to know that they are the same.
我碰巧知道它们是一样的。
And that was a leading question.
那是一个诱导性问题。
But they are representing data and instructions, ultimately,
但最终它们代表的是数据和指令，
data like H-E-L-L-O, comma, W-O-R-L-D and an instruction like,
比如像H-E-L-L-O，逗号，W-O-R-L-D这样的数据，以及类似于
"Print that data to the screen."
“将数据打印到屏幕上。”这样的指令。
As for what these patterns of 0's and 1's are,
至于这些0和1的模式是什么，
this is not something that a computer scientist or programmer worries about.
这并不是计算机科学家或程序员担心的问题。
We just stipulate that, OK, someone, somewhere knows how to do this.
我们只是规定，好的，有人，在某个地方知道怎么做。
And it's probably someone like Intel, who makes
而且很可能像英特尔这样的人，他们生产
the hardware inside of the computers.
电脑里的硬件。
But you and I, starting now, already, in week zero,
但你我，从现在开始，已经从零周开始，
can start to view binary more abstractly.
可以开始更抽象地看待二进制。
We don't care about the 0's and 1's.
我们不关心0和1。
We only care that you can use 0's and 1's
我们只关心你能使用 0 和 1
to represent more useful quantities, like numbers,
来表示更有用的量，比如数字，
and letters, colors, and more.
字母、颜色等等。
So this, next week, is going to be the code we actually
所以下周，我们将开始写实际的代码
start writing at a keyboard.
在键盘上编写。
And this is that language called C. It's the same language I, myself, learned
而这门语言叫做 C。它和我自己当年学习的时候一样，
years ago, when taking CS50, when all we learned at the time was C.
多年前，在学习 CS50 的时候，我们当时只学了 C 语言。
But this, too, has some crypticness to it.
但它也有一些神秘之处。
And if you've never programmed before, you can probably wrap your mind around,
如果你以前从未编程过，你可能可以理解，
OK, I'm guessing the "printf" prints out the "hello, world."
好吧，我猜“printf”会打印出“hello, world”。
But what's with the semicolon, the quotes, the backslash,
但分号、引号、反斜杠是什么？
and the curly braces, the #include, and all of this stupid syntax?
还有花括号、#include 以及所有这些愚蠢的语法？
A lot of this, in the beginning of any class, is really a distraction.
在一门课的开始阶段，这些东西真的很让人分心。
It is not intellectually interesting.
它们在智力上并没有什么有趣的地方。
But it's the stupid kind of stuff that's going to trip you up quite often.
但这些愚蠢的东西会经常让你绊倒。
And so, today, what we'll do is focus not
所以今天，我们将重点放在
on syntax, characters on the keyboard, but ideas
语法，键盘上的字符，而是思想
because what really matters in this program
因为在这个程序中真正重要的是
is that "printf" is a function here for our purposes.
“printf”在这里是为我们服务的函数。
And that function is to display information on the screen.
这个函数的作用是将信息显示在屏幕上。
Everything else, as we'll soon see, has value
其他一切，正如我们很快就会看到，都有价值
and will be understood by you, before long, but for now, it's a distraction.
你很快就会理解，但现在，它们是令人分心的事情。
Let's focus on those building blocks.
让我们关注这些构建块。
When it comes time to write code, though, for the curious,
当需要编写代码时，对于好奇的人来说，
especially if you've programmed before, we'll
特别是如果你之前做过编程，我们会
use a very popular free and open-source tool
使用一个非常流行的免费开源工具
called Visual Studio Code, or VS Code.
叫做 Visual Studio Code，或者 VS Code。
We'll use a cloud-based version of it that we pre-install everything
我们将使用它的云端版本，我们在其中预先安装了所有东西
you need in the cloud for you so you don't
你在云端需要的東西，所以你不需要
have to deal with headaches like getting your Mac or PC to work.
处理诸如让你的 Mac 或 PC 正常工作之类的麻烦事。
You'll use instead this URL, cs50.dev, but more
你将使用这个 URL，cs50.dev，但更多
on that in next week, week one.
关于这个的内容将在下周，第一周。
For now, we'll use another cloud-based editor called Scratch.
现在，我们将使用另一个名为 Scratch 的云端编辑器。
And odds are some number of you use this probably
你们中有些人可能在
as early as like middle school or the like.
初中或类似的时期就使用过这个。
And that was fine to create your own animations, games,
这很适合创建你自己的动画、游戏，
interactive art, or the like.
互动艺术等等。
But we'll use it today for just a bit.
但今天我们只用它一会儿。
And we'll use it in the course's first homework,
我们将在课程的第一次作业中使用它，
AKA problem set 0, to explore now some of these same ideas.
也就是问题集 0，去探索这些相同的想法。
And among the goals today for the remainder of today
而今天剩余时间的目标之一
is not to focus so much on Scratch and the particulars
不是过度关注 Scratch 和细节
because this is not a language that you're
因为这并不是你经常会用到的语言
going to use often but to give you very visual representations of ideas
而是让你对这些思想有一个直观的认识
so that when things do escalate next week to C, to the more cryptic,
这样，当事情在下周升级到 C 语言，也就是更神秘的语言时，
it's the same ideas just typed out instead of dragged and dropped.
它就是同样的想法，只是用打字的方式来表达，而不是用拖放的方式。
So by that, I mean this.
我的意思是这个。
I'm going to go ahead and share in just a moment the user interface of Scratch.
我马上就要分享一下Scratch的用户界面。
But what's nice about Scratch is that this
Scratch的优点在于，它
is how we're going to implement that same program today.
是我们今天要实现同一个程序的方式。
These are two blocks or puzzle pieces on the screen,
屏幕上有两个积木块或拼图块，
and they've been interconnected to tell the computer to say "hello, world"
它们相互连接，告诉计算机说“hello，world”
on the screen.
在屏幕上。
The user interface that we're about to use
我们即将使用的用户界面
will look generally something like this.
大体上会像这样。
It's a web-based editor that you can also
这是一个基于网络的编辑器，你也可以
download it locally to use offline.
下载到本地离线使用。
And you'll see that at the left here are a whole bunch of puzzle pieces
你会看到左边有很多拼图块
or blocks.
或积木块。
They're categorized by color, and the blue ones
它们按颜色分类，蓝色的那些
tend to relate to motion, for instance.
通常与运动相关，例如。
The purple ones represent looks.
紫色代表外观。
The pink one represents sounds.
粉色代表声音。
The yellow one represents events.
黄色代表事件。
More on that soon.
稍后再说。
The orange ones represent control, and then
橙色的代表控制，然后
there's operators, variables, my blocks, and even some extensions
还有运算符、变量、我的积木块，甚至一些扩展
we can install as well.
我们也可以安装。
So it just categorizes things visually and colorfully so that you
所以它只是用视觉和颜色对事物进行分类，以便你
can find what you're looking for.
可以找到你想要的东西。
But we're going to use these puzzle pieces to drag and drop them
但我们将使用这些拼图块来拖放它们
onto this area here.
到这个区域。
And we're going to connect them when we want them to do something.
当我们想要它们做一些事情时，我们将把它们连接起来。
What can they do?
它们能做什么？
Well, by default, Scratch comes with this cat here, otherwise known
默认情况下，Scratch 带有这只猫，也称为
as a sprite, which is a character in a game or in a graphics context.
精灵，它是游戏或图形环境中的角色。
And this cat lives in this two-dimensional world in which
这只猫生活在这个二维世界里，在这个世界里
the cat can go up, down, left, right.
猫可以上下左右移动。
And you can actually change the cat's costume
你实际上可以改变猫的服装
to be a dog, a bird, or anything else.
变成狗、鸟或任何其他东西。
It really is more of an idea than it is a specific animal in this case.
实际上，在这个例子中，它更像是一个想法，而不是一种特定的动物。
But the world that Scratch lives in looks a little something like this.
但Scratch所处的世界看起来有点像这样。
It's like a Cartesian plane with x-coordinates and y-coordinates.
它就像一个笛卡尔坐标系，有x坐标和y坐标。
And the numbers don't so much matter fundamentally,
而数字本身并不那么重要，
except that when you want the cat or any character to go up,
除了当你想要猫或任何角色向上移动时，
down, left, or right by some amount, it's
向下、向左或向右移动一定距离时，它
useful to know, for instance, that 0, 0 is the middle, 0 comma 0 for x comma y.
知道例如0,0是中间，0,0代表x,y是有用的。
All the way up is a y value of 180.
一直向上是y值为180。
All the way down is -180.
一直向下是-180。
All the way to the left is -240.
一直向左是-240。
All the way to the right is 240.
一直向右是240。
And generally, you're not going to have to worry about numbers.
一般来说，你不必担心数字。
You're going to use these relatively-- go right, go left, go up, or down.
你会相对地使用这些——向右、向左、向上或向下。
But that's just the world that Scratch itself lives in here.
但这就是 Scratch 本身所处的世界。
So let's go about using Scratch here.
所以让我们开始使用 Scratch。
I'm going to change over to my cloud-based editor
我将切换到我的云端编辑器
here, where I've gone to scratch.mit.edu.
这里，我访问了 scratch.mit.edu。
And I've clicked Create in order to create a project.
我点击了创建来创建一个项目。
And that gives me this blank canvas here.
这给了我一个空白画布。
And I'm going to do these somewhat quickly because I kind of know
我会快速地操作，因为我有点了解
what I'm looking for.
我要找什么。
But part of the process with problem set zero is going to be clicking,
但问题集零的一部分将是点击，
and dragging, and sort of scrolling around
拖动，以及滚动查看
to see what building blocks exist.
哪些积木存在。
But I know under Events there's this puzzle piece here
我知道在事件中有一个拼图块
when green flag clicked.
当绿色旗帜被点击时。
Why is that germane?
为什么这很重要？
Well, if I zoom out, and go back to Scratch's world at the right here,
如果我缩小，回到这里右侧的 Scratch 世界，
notice that above Scratch's world there's
注意 Scratch 世界上方有一个
a green flag, which is going to mean go, and a red stop sign, which,
绿色的旗子，代表开始，红色的停止标志，代表
of course, is going to mean stop.
停止。
So if I drag this puzzle piece anywhere into the middle,
所以，如果我将这个拼图块拖到中间任何地方，
it's just going to plop where I put it.
它就会落在我放置的位置。
But what that means semantically is when someone clicks that green flag,
但从语义上来说，当有人点击那个绿色的旗子时，
I want Scratch the cat to do this other thing.
我希望 Scratch 猫做另外一件事。
Well, what do I want it to do?
它应该做什么？
Well, let me go under Looks.
让我看看外观。
And looks here in purple have some puzzle pieces like this.
外观里有一些紫色的拼图块，像这样。
Well, I can say hello for some number of seconds,
我可以说“你好”持续几秒钟，
or I can just go ahead and say hello.
或者我可以直接说“你好”。
So let's do that.
就做吧。
I'm going to drag this say block.
我要拖动这个“说”块。
And notice that as soon as I get close enough,
注意，当我足够靠近时，
it's going to magnetically want to connect.
它会磁性地想要连接。
So I can let go, and they snap together automatically
所以我松开手，它们会自动连接在一起
because they're the right shape.
因为它们的形状正确。
I don't have to say hello, exclamation point.
我不必说“你好，感叹号”。
I can change it to the more canonical, hello comma world.
我可以把它改成更规范的“你好，世界”。
So anything in this white oval is editable
在这个白色的椭圆形中，任何东西都可以编辑
that you can change as just text there.
你可以直接在那里更改文本。
If I now zoom out, let me go ahead and click the green flag.
现在我缩小，点击绿色的旗子。
And voila-- this should be my first program in Scratch.
瞧，这应该是我在 Scratch 中的第一个程序。
Hello, world.
你好，世界。
Without any of the distractions of syntax
没有语法方面的干扰
or weird characters on the screen, it's just done what I want it to do.
或屏幕上的奇怪字符，它只是做了我想要它做的事情。
All right.
好的。
Let me go ahead and click Stop there.
我点击停止。
And let me make it a little more connected
让我把它与我们之前讨论的内容联系起来
to what we've discussed thus far.
到目前为止。
So this puzzle piece here, say hello, world,
所以，这个拼图块，“说你好，世界”，
represents what type of building block using the vocabulary of today?
使用今天的词汇，它代表哪种类型的积木？
So it's a function.
所以它是一个函数。
So these purple blocks are functions, say, hello, world.
所以这些紫色的块是函数，例如“说，你好，世界”。
And let me give you another piece of terminology.
让我再给你介绍另一个术语。
These white ovals that take textual input--
这些白色椭圆形，它们接受文本输入——
in general, those are called parameters or arguments.
通常，它们被称为参数或参数。
And they customize the behavior of a function.
它们自定义函数的行为。
So a parameter or an argument customizes,
所以参数或参数自定义，
modifies the default behavior of a function, like in this case, say.
修改函数的默认行为，比如在这个例子中，就是说。
Similarly, in the C code from earlier that we'll see next week,
类似地，在之前我们将在下周看到的 C 代码中，
the printf function took a quoted phrase like, hello, world, similarly as input.
printf 函数将一个引用的短语，比如“hello, world”，类似地作为输入。
But more on that in the future.
但以后会详细介绍。
So how does this connect to the mental model we presented earlier?
那么这如何与我们之前介绍的心理模型联系起来呢？
Well, here's problem-solving as I described it earlier, inputs to outputs
好吧，这就是我之前描述的解决问题的方式，输入到输出
with algorithms or code in the middle.
中间有算法或代码。
Well, what we've got here really is an input of, hello, world, the white oval.
好吧，我们这里实际上是“hello, world”的输入，也就是这个白色的椭圆形。
The function or algorithm that it's going into as input is the say block.
它作为输入进入的函数或算法是这个“说”块。
And what is the output of using this say block, the say function?
那么使用这个“说”块，也就是“说”函数的输出是什么呢？
It's the visual effect of having the cat have the little speech bubble appear
它是在猫头上出现一个小气泡的视觉效果
above its head, saying, hello, world.
上面写着“hello, world”。
So everything we do, in fact, can be mapped back
所以我们所做的每件事，事实上都可以映射回
to that very simple idea of inputs and outputs.
那个非常简单的输入和输出的概念。
Well, let's make it a little more interesting, though.
好吧，让我们让它更有趣一点吧。
It's a little boring to just say "hello, world" all the time.
一直说“hello, world”有点无聊。
Let me go ahead and drag this away.
让我把它拖走。
And if you just drag it to the left and let go, it gets automatically deleted.
如果你把它拖到左边并松开，它就会自动删除。
Let me go under Sensing in light blue here.
让我去这里浅蓝色的“感知”下面。
And you'll see there's a bunch of blocks, one of which
你会看到有一堆积木，其中一个是
is an ask block, an ask function, which is going to prompt
一个“询问”块，一个“询问”函数，它将提示
the human, me, for some input.
人类，也就是我，输入一些东西。
So let me go ahead and drag that over here, and it snaps together.
所以让我把它拖到这里，它就卡在一起了。
I could change the question, but I'm OK with that question.
我可以修改问题，但我觉得这个问题很好。
We'll use what's your name.
我们将使用“你叫什么名字”。
But notice that this block, ask, is a little special.
但请注意，这个“询问”块有点特殊。
It is not just going to display like a speech bubble on the screen.
它不仅会在屏幕上显示成气泡。
It's actually going to return a value, and this is
它实际上会返回一个值，而这就是
another term of art today and onward.
从今天开始，另一个专业术语。
A return value is some value that can be handed back to you conceptually
返回值是指可以从概念上返回给你的某个值
from a function so that you can do something with it.
来自函数，这样你就可以用它来做一些事情。
It's as though the ask function asks someone for their name,
就好像“询问”函数询问某人的名字，
writes it down on a piece of paper, and hands you the piece of paper.
写在一张纸上，然后把那张纸交给你。
You can do anything now that you want with that name.
你现在可以用这个名字做任何你想做的事情。
And here is how you access the name in this special block called
而这里就是你访问这个名为
answer, which, again, will start calling a return value.
“答案”的特殊块的方法，它再次开始被称为返回值。
So if I want to say "hello" to someone specific, I'm going to do this.
所以如果我想对某个特定的人说“hello”，我会这样做。
Let me zoom out.
让我缩小一点。
Let me go back to Looks, and let me go back to Say.
让我回到“外观”，然后回到“说”。
And I'm going to change the say block here to "hello, comma."
我要把这里说的话块改成“你好，逗号”。
Then I'm going to zoom out.
然后我要缩小。
Well, I need two inputs, I think.
嗯，我想我需要两个输入。
So I'm going to grab another say block, and I'm going to put it below.
所以我要再拿一个说的话块，然后把它放到下面。
And I could just type "David," but this is
我可以直接打“David”，但这样
going to defeat the whole point of asking me for the name.
会毁掉向我询问名字的整个目的。
And it will only work for me.
而且它只会对我有用。
So I don't want to do that.
所以我不想那样做。
So let me go back to Sensing, and notice the shape is important here.
所以让我回到“感知”，注意这里形状很重要。
Even if it's not quite the same size, the shape matters.
即使它不是完全相同的大小，形状也很重要。
And I can actually drag this and change the input of this say function
我实际上可以拖动它，更改这个说的话函数的输入
to be whatever that return value is, that piece of paper
变成那个返回值，那张纸
that has the person's name on it.
上面写着那个人的名字。
And it grows to fill, but now we have a program
它会扩大以填充，但现在我们有一个程序
that I think when I click the green flag-- watch-- is going to prompt me.
我认为当点击绿旗的时候——看——它会提示我。
What's your name?
你的名字是什么？
And now I have room to type down here.
现在我有空间在下面打字。
So I'm going to type D-A-V-I-D. I'm going to hit Enter,
所以我要打 D-A-V-I-D。我要按回车键，
and it should say "hello, Dave."
它应该说“你好，戴夫”。
Wait.
等等。
Hmm.
嗯。
Huh.
Maybe it was-- didn't work.
也许它是——没有用。
D-A-V-I-D. Here we go.
D-A-V-I-D。开始了。
Hello, David.
你好，大卫。
Hmm.
嗯。
It's missing the hello, but I'm quite sure we have a hello right there.
它缺少“你好”，但我非常确定我们有“你好”就在那里。
So what explains this bug or mistake?
那么什么解释了这个错误或失误？
Yeah.
是啊。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众：[听不清]。
So they overlap.
所以它们重叠了。
DAVID J. MALAN: Exactly.
大卫·J·马兰：没错。
Put another way, my Mac, my PC, it's just so darn
换句话说，我的Mac，我的电脑，它就是太
fast that it did exactly what it was supposed to.
快了，以至于它精确地完成了它应该做的事情。
But it said "hello, David" so fast that we didn't even see, we being the human,
但它说“你好，大卫”太快了，我们甚至没有看到，我们指人类，
the slowest part of the puzzle, see the actual hello.
谜题中最慢的部分，看到真正的“你好”。
So there's a few different ways to fix this, as you know.
所以有很多不同的方法可以解决这个问题，如你所知。
We could have it say "hello" for some number of seconds.
我们可以让它说“你好”几秒钟。
So I could kind of do that.
所以我可以那样做。
So let me do this.
所以让我这样做。
I can decouple these by just dragging and letting it go
我可以通过拖动并释放它们来分离它们
so that they're magnetically far apart.
这样它们在磁性上相距甚远。
Let me go ahead and drag this one, say hello for two seconds.
让我继续拖动这个，说“你好”两秒钟。
I'm going to change the grammar here to be hello comma again.
我要把这里的语法改回“你好，逗号”。
I'm going to go ahead and disconnect these two.
我要继续断开这两个。
I'm going to throw away the old one that I don't want to use.
我要扔掉我不想要用的旧的那个。
And I'm going to reconnect this so that now--
我要重新连接它，这样现在——
OK.
好的。
It's going to say hello for two seconds and then my name, hopefully.
它会说“你好”两秒钟，然后是我的名字，希望如此。
So let me click Stop and Start.
所以让我点击停止并开始。
D-A-V-I-D. Enter.
D-A-V-I-D。按回车键。
OK.
好的。
So it's better, but it's kind of poorly implemented.
所以它更好，但是实现得有点糟糕。
Like, come on.
拜托。
I just wanted to say hello comma David.
我只是想说“你好，大卫”。
Why is that hard?
为什么这很难？
Well, maybe we can actually combine these a little differently.
好吧，也许我们可以用不同的方式将它们组合起来。
And let me propose this.
让我提议一下。
Let me actually get rid of these blocks again.
让我再次去掉这些块。
And let me go ahead and just say one thing.
让我先说一件事。
But can I somehow combine this to say hello comma David all in one breath?
但是我是否可以以某种方式将它们组合起来，用一口气说出“你好，大卫”？
Well, it turns out if I go under Operators,
嗯，事实证明，如果我进入运算符选项卡，
I know from having played with this before that there's this puzzle
我之前玩过这个，我知道这里有一个叫做“连接”的拼图。
piece down here called join.
它在下面。
It's an oval.
它是一个椭圆形。
It's a little big, but, again, it will grow to fill.
它有点大，但是，它会自动扩展。
And by default, it wants to join two words, "apple" and "banana."
默认情况下，它想将两个单词“苹果”和“香蕉”连接起来。
But those are just placeholders.
但这些只是占位符。
So let me go ahead and drag this over the default hello.
所以，让我将它拖到默认的“你好”上。
Let me change "apple" to hello comma space and then banana.
让我将“苹果”改为“你好，”加空格，然后是“香蕉”。
Let me go back to Sensing.
让我回到“感知”选项卡。
Let me grab answer and drag and drop that.
让我抓住“答案”并将其拖放。
So now notice that I'm kind of layering my ideas.
现在注意，我正在将我的想法分层。
And put another way, the output of this join block
换句话说，这个“连接”块的输出
is presumably going to join two things together,
应该是将两个东西连接起来，
apple and banana or hello comma David.
“苹果”和“香蕉”，或者“你好，大卫”。
And then the output of join is going to become the input to say.
然后，“连接”的输出将成为“说”的输入。
So aesthetically, it just looks better.
所以从美学上来说，它看起来更好。
It's still correct, but it's just better.
它仍然是正确的，但它只是更好。
So if I type "David," and hit Enter, hello, David.
所以，如果我输入“大卫”，然后按回车键，就会显示“你好，大卫”。
This is what a normal program would presumably
这是一个正常的程序应该
do, not show you part of the phrase and then the rest of the phrase.
做的事情，而不是只显示部分短语，然后显示剩下的短语。
Like, it's just better in this way.
就像，这样更好。
So let's connect this now to this same puzzle piece and this methodology.
所以，让我们将它连接到这个相同的拼图和方法。
So here's that same puzzle piece, ask.
所以，这是同一个拼图，询问。
How do we fit it into this input and output flow with algorithms?
我们如何使用算法将其融入这个输入和输出流？
Well, the input to that puzzle piece is something like, what's your name,
嗯，这个拼图的输入类似于“你的名字是什么”，
question mark.
问号。
Then the algorithm or the code implementation thereof
然后是算法，或者说代码实现，
is this ask block and wait so the human has a moment to type their response in.
就是这个“询问”块和“等待”，这样人类可以有时间输入他们的回复。
The output of that function recall is a return value.
回想一下，那个函数的输出是一个返回值。
You don't see anything on the screen by default because we've not used say yet,
默认情况下，你在屏幕上看不到任何东西，因为我们还没有使用“说”，
but we get this return value.
但我们得到了这个返回值。
And let me scooch everything over now so that we can now
让我现在将所有东西都移过来，这样我们现在就可以
join those inputs together.
将这些输入连接在一起。
So here's this puzzle piece.
所以，这是这个拼图。
Let me go ahead and propose that the inputs now to the join block
让我提议一下，现在连接块的输入
are two arguments or two parameters, so to speak, hello and answer.
是两个参数，或者说两个参数，分别是“你好”和“答案”。
They go into that join puzzle piece, whose purpose in life
它们进入这个连接拼图，它存在的意义
is to return one joined version thereof.
目的是返回一个合并版本。
Let me slide this all over logically now so
现在让我从逻辑上将它全部滑动过去，以便
that now that output becomes the input to the say block
现在该输出变成say块的输入。
and now is why the cat has the speech bubble saying all at once,
现在这就是为什么猫的语音气泡会同时说，
hello comma David.
你好，大卫。
So what we've done here is kind of composed the output
所以我们在这里做的是将输出进行组合
and from one function into the input of another.
并将一个函数的输出作为另一个函数的输入。
And you can think of this in a couple of different ways,
你可以从几个不同的角度思考这一点，
left to right, as I did there, or kind of
从左到右，就像我刚才那样，或者
like stacking these things on top of one another.
像将这些东西叠在一起。
But at the end of the day, even as programming
但归根结底，即使编程
gets more and more powerful for us, it's just inputs and outputs, inputs
变得越来越强大，它仅仅是输入和输出，输入
and outputs.
和输出。
And thankfully, with built-in functionality from our friends
值得庆幸的是，我们来自麻省理工学院的朋友们为我们提供了内置功能
at MIT who designed Scratch, I can even do something playful like this.
设计了Scratch，我甚至可以做一些像这样有趣的事情。
I can go to that Extensions button at the bottom.
我可以点击底部的扩展按钮。
And there's a lot of fancy things I can add here, like text-to-speech.
这里还有很多很酷的功能，比如文字转语音。
So let me go ahead and choose text-to-speech.
所以让我选择文字转语音。
And let me go ahead here and change the say block in purple.
让我在这里改变紫色say块。
Let me get rid of the say block, and let me borrow this.
让我去掉say块，让我借用这个。
Let me get the speak block like this.
让我得到speak块，像这样。
And now let me drag and drop this oval.
现在让我拖放这个椭圆形。
It's going to grow to fill.
它会扩展以填满。
And I think it's just about to be a little more interesting.
我认为它即将变得更有意思。
Let me click Play now, and hopefully this isn't too loud.
让我现在点击播放，希望这不会太大声。
D-A-V-I-D. Enter.
D-A-V-I-D。 输入。
SPEAKER: Hello, David.
语音：你好，大卫。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
大卫·J·马兰：好的。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
Thank you.
谢谢。
That's a low bar.
这可是低要求啊。
[CHUCKLES] Let me go ahead and set the voice too.
[轻笑] 让我继续设置语音。
And you might now remember how we began class, where
现在你可能会记得我们开始上课的方式，那时
we had a robotic, computerized voice.
我们使用的是一个机器人般的计算机合成语音。
Well, we didn't use Scratch at the time, but we could change this in Scratch
嗯，我们当时没有使用Scratch，但我们可以在Scratch中改变它
alone to be a little different.
让它有点不一样。
So D-A-V-I-D.
所以D-A-V-I-D。
SPEAKER: Hello, David.
语音：你好，大卫。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
大卫·J·马兰：好的。
Little creepy, but we can play all day long with that.
有点毛骨悚然，但我们可以整天玩这个。
But the point is that these functions are just
但重点是这些函数只是
now doing something a little different.
现在做了一些不同的事情。
But it's just these inputs and outputs.
但这只是输入和输出。
Well, let's make the cat more like a cat.
好吧，让我们让猫更像猫。
Let me go ahead and throw away all of this asking question stuff.
让我继续丢弃所有这些问问题的东西。
Let me go up to Sound, and let me go ahead
让我去声音，让我继续
and drag the play sound meow until done.
拖动播放声音喵直到完成。
And here too it comes with meow.
这里也带着喵。
You can add your own sounds as well.
你也可以添加自己的声音。
But I'm just going to use the default meow and here too.
但我只是使用默认的喵声，在这里也是。
Hopefully, this won't be too loud.
希望声音不会太大。
Let's make the cat meow by clicking Play.
点击播放，让猫叫一声。
[MEOWING]
[喵]
OK.
好的。
It's a little piercing, but it's cute.
声音有点刺耳，但很可爱。
And if I want the cat to meow twice, I could just play the game twice.
如果我想让猫叫两次，我可以玩两次游戏。
[MEOWING]
[喵]
All right.
好的。
But it would be nice to just get it to meow automatically two, or three,
但如果能自动让它叫两声、三声，
or more times.
或者更多次就好了。
So you know what I could do?
所以你知道我可以做什么吗？
I could just drag a second one of these.
我可以拖动一个新的到这边。
Actually, you know what?
事实上，你知道吗？
I could even just right-click or Control-click and duplicate them.
我甚至可以直接右键点击或使用组合键 Ctrl + 点击来复制它们。
But I'll just keep dragging and dropping.
但我还是会继续拖放。
There's different ways to solve problems.
解决问题的方法有很多。
And now let me click Play.
现在让我点击播放。
[MEOWING]
[喵]
OK.
好的。
Cat does not sound particularly happy.
这猫听起来不太高兴。
So we could go under--
所以我们可以去下面——
how about Control?
控制怎么样？
We could wait one second.
我们可以等待一秒钟。
Now, there's no room, but it will sort of expand to give room for me.
现在没有空间了，但它会扩展，给我腾出空间。
So let me try this.
所以让我试试这个。
And now it's going to wait one second in between meows.
现在它会在两次喵声之间等待一秒钟。
[MEOWING]
[喵]
OK.
好的。
Let me stipulate that is correct.
我要声明这确实是正确的。
If my goal is to get the cat to meow three times, it meowed three times.
如果我的目标是让猫叫三声，它就叫了三声。
But per our discussion earlier of algorithms and the design thereof,
但根据我们之前关于算法及其设计的讨论，
this is not the best design.
这不是最好的设计。
[MEOWING]
[喵]
OK?
好吗？
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
Thank you for playing along at home.
感谢大家在家玩耍。
Yeah.
是的。
In what sense is this arguably not well-designed?
从某种意义上来说，这为什么不能算是好的设计？
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: You repeated yourself.
观众：你重复了自己。
DAVID J. MALAN: I repeated myself, which actually in programming
大卫·J·马兰：我重复了自己，这在编程中实际上
tends not to be a good thing.
往往不是一件好事。
Now, it was easy.
现在，这很容易。
I almost resorted to copy-paste, which saves me time upfront.
我几乎要用到了复制粘贴，这可以节省我最初的时间。
But just imagine a contrived scenario.
但想象一下一个虚构的场景。
Now, what if I want it to wait like two seconds in between?
现在，如果我想让它在两次喵声之间等待两秒钟呢？
All right.
好的。
It's not that big a deal.
这没什么大不了。
I change it here, and I change it here.
我在这里改变它，在这里改变它。
But what if the program is meant to meow 10 times?
但是如果程序需要喵叫 10 次呢？
Then I have to change it here, and here, and here, and here, and here.
那么我必须在这里改，在这里改，在这里改，在这里改，在这里改。
And eventually I'm going to screw up.
最终我会搞砸的。
Humans are fallible.
人是会犯错的。
I'm going to overlook one of them.
我会漏掉其中一个。
One time, it's going to be one second.
有一次，它会差一秒。
Another is going to be two, and just stupid things will happen.
再有一次，它会差两秒，就会发生一些愚蠢的事情。
You're setting yourself up for failure if you design things poorly.
如果你设计的东西很糟糕，你就是在自寻失败。
And so I would propose that we use another type of building block
所以，我建议我们使用另一种类型的积木
to solve this instead.
来解决这个问题。
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah.
大卫·马兰：是的。
So we could use a loop and just write minimal code
所以我们可以使用循环，并只写最少的代码
but to accomplish even more functionality.
但实现更多功能。
So let me throw away most of these blocks.
所以让我扔掉大部分这些积木。
And let's go and grab this repeat block, which we haven't used yet,
然后让我们去抓取这个重复块，我们还没有用过，
but it's right there.
但它就在那里。
And as the name suggests, this will allow
正如名字所暗示的那样，这将允许
me to repeat something some number of times.
我重复某些内容多次。
Let me put these two puzzle pieces inside.
让我把这两块拼图放进去。
It'll grow to fill.
它会自动填满。
Let me reconnect it to the green flag.
让我把它重新连接到绿色旗帜上。
I'll change the default 10 to a 3.
我将把默认的 10 改为 3。
And now--
现在——
[MEOWING]
[喵叫]
It's just sort of better because if now you want it to meow more times,
这更好，因为如果你现在想要它喵叫更多次，
you change it one place.
你只需在一个地方修改它。
If you want it to slow down, you change it in one place.
如果你想让它慢下来，你只需在一个地方修改它。
There's no room for error.
没有出错的空间。
And that's generally a good thing.
一般来说，这是一件好事。
But this is silly.
但这是愚蠢的。
Like, Scratch comes with a cat.
就像，Scratch 带有一只猫。
Why didn't MIT give us a puzzle piece called "meow?"
为什么麻省理工学院没有给我们一个叫做“喵”的拼图？
Like, why am I implementing the idea of meowing myself?
就像，为什么我要自己实现喵叫的想法？
Like, that took me what?
就像，那花费了我什么？
1, 2, 3, 4 puzzle pieces.
1、2、3、4 块拼图。
Why isn't there just one puzzle piece that meows for me?
为什么没有一块拼图可以为我喵叫？
This too we can do in code, be it in Scratch, or C, or other languages too.
我们也可以在代码中做到这一点，无论是在 Scratch、C 还是其他语言中。
I'm going to go down to these pink my blocks here,
我将进入这里这些粉红色的我的积木中，
where I can create my own puzzle piece.
在那里我可以创建我自己的拼图。
And I'm going to call this literally "meow."
我将把它命名为“喵”。
And I'm going to go ahead and just click OK.
然后我将点击确定。
And notice that it's given me this new type of start connector.
注意，它给了我这种新型的起始连接器。
It's a start puzzle piece that nothing goes above it.
它是一块起始拼图，上面什么都没有。
But you can put anything you want below it.
但你可以把任何你想要的东西放在它下面。
And I'm going to go ahead and cheat here.
我将在这里作弊。
I'm just going to grab my existing code, so to speak.
我将使用我现有的代码，这么说吧。
This is code I'm writing, even though it's puzzle pieces.
这是我正在编写的代码，即使它是由拼图块组成的。
And now let me just claim, and I'll move this aside.
现在让我声明，然后把这个移开。
Here is now an implementation of my own function,
现在我将实现我自己的函数，
my own block called "meow," whose purpose in life
我自己的积木块叫做“喵”，它存在的意义
is to meow until done and then wait one second.
就是一直叫喵，直到完成，然后等待一秒。
But what's powerful now is notice at top left, now that I've made the block,
但现在强大的是，请注意左上角，现在我创建了积木块，
I can use it any number of times.
我可以使用它任意多次。
So I can grab this meow block, drag it over here, and you know what?
所以我可以抓住这个喵的积木块，把它拖到这边，你知道吗？
Now that "meow" exists as an idea, I can abstract that away.
现在“喵”已经存在于我的脑海中了，我可以把它抽象出来。
And I'm just going to arbitrarily drag it way to the bottom.
我打算随意把它拖到最下面。
I'm not deleting it.
我没有删除它。
I'm just putting it out of sight, out of mind so
我只是把它藏起来，从我的脑海中移除，这样
that we can focus now on this idea.
我们现在可以集中精力关注这个想法。
And I claim that this implementation of meowing
我声称这种叫喵的实现方式
is sort of better because it's more compact, it does what it says,
稍微好一些，因为它更紧凑，它做到了它所宣称的，
and I don't care about the implementation details of "meow."
而且我不关心“喵”的实现细节。
So this idea of abstraction, something we're going to use frequently.
所以这个抽象的概念，是我们将会经常使用到的东西。
To abstract something away is to simplify.
抽象某个东西就是将其简化。
Don't think about the underlying implementation details.
不要去思考底层的实现细节。
Just care about what it does or what it's called.
只需要关心它做了什么或者它叫什么名字。
Someone has to care about the implementation details,
总得有人去关心实现细节，
like me 30 seconds ago.
比如30秒前的我。
But here on out, I don't need to care.
但是从现在开始，我不需要再关心这些。
And so in fact, you and I are using the abstraction
事实上，你和我都正在使用抽象，
that is Scratch because I don't know how to put a speech bubble on the screen.
那就是Scratch，因为我不知道如何在屏幕上放置一个对话框。
I don't know how to create that sound, meow.
我不知道如何创建那个声音，喵。
MIT did that, and they abstracted those pieces
麻省理工学院做到了，他们将那些部分
of functionality away already for us by just giving us
的功能抽象出来，直接给了我们
these puzzle pieces we see here.
这些我们在这里看到的积木块。
So the code will work the exact same.
所以代码会以完全相同的方式工作。
[MEOWING]
[喵喵叫]
But it's sort of better designed now because now I've
但现在设计得稍微好一些，因为我已经
abstracted away the idea of meowing.
将叫喵的想法抽象了出来。
But I bet I can improve this further.
但我敢说我还能进一步改进。
Can I get rid of the repeat block altogether?
我能完全移除重复积木块吗？
And let me just tell the meow block how many times to meow.
我可以直接告诉喵积木块叫多少次喵吗？
Well, let me go down to the bottom and look at the implementation details.
好吧，让我去最下面看看实现细节。
I'm going to right-click or Control-click on this,
我要右键单击或 Control-单击它，
and I'm going to edit it.
然后我要编辑它。
So I'm going to make a change.
所以我要进行修改。
And I didn't do this before, but I'm going to call it "meow," as before.
我之前没有这样做，但我打算像之前一样把它叫做“喵”。
I'm going to add an input.
我要添加一个输入。
And just so I know what it says what it does,
为了让我知道它说的是什么，它做了什么，
I'm going to add the word "times" here.
我打算在这里添加“次”这个词。
And I'm going to change this placeholder to n.
我打算把这个占位符改成n。
n for "number" is the go-to placeholder any time
n代表“数字”，是我们在计算机科学中谈论数字时使用的首选占位符。
we want to talk about a number in CS.
我们在计算机科学中谈论数字时使用的首选占位符。
So now notice the puzzle piece looks a little different.
所以现在请注意，这个积木块看起来有点不一样了。
It takes an argument or a parameter called
它接收一个参数，叫做
n, which represents the number of times you want the thing to meow.
n，它代表你想让它叫喵的次数。
Now, that doesn't do that yet.
现在，它还没有这样做。
So let me go back to my other code.
所以让我回到我的其他代码。
Let me just decouple these temporarily.
让我暂时将它们分离。
I'm going to move my loop into my implementation of meowing.
我将把我的循环移到我的喵喵叫的实现中。
But I don't want to hard code, that is literally write the number 3 anymore.
但我不希望硬编码，也就是不再直接写数字 3。
I'm going to grab this oval and put it there.
我将抓住这个椭圆形并把它放在那里。
So now I've generalized the function.
所以现在我将函数泛化了。
So now it will meow any number of times, 0 on up, by executing that loop
所以现在它会喵叫任意次数，从 0 开始，通过执行循环
and now more powerfully.
现在更强大。
Out of sight, out of mind.
眼不见心不烦。
Notice that my code just became so darn simple.
请注意，我的代码变得如此简单。
Like, my function is called "meow."
比如，我的函数叫做 "喵叫"。
It meows some number of times.
它喵叫几次。
All I have to do is type a number there, and it just works.
我只需要在那里输入一个数字，它就会工作。
And I don't care any more about those lower-level, so to speak,
我再也不关心那些低级的，可以说是
implementation details.
实现细节。
So here, no surprise.
所以这里，毫不意外。
If I type in the number 3, zoom out, and hit Play--
如果我输入数字 3，缩小，然后点击播放 -
[MEOWING]
[喵叫声]
--it still works just fine.
它仍然运行良好。
So any questions on what we've just done here?
所以，关于我们刚刚在这里做的事情，有什么问题吗？
It's still just meowing, but that's besides the point.
它仍然只是喵叫，但这并不重要。
It's this creation of our own functions, this modularity,
这是我们创建自己的函数，这种模块化，
this abstraction that's going to be the idea that keeps coming back to us.
这种抽象，将是我们一直反复提到的概念。
No?
没有？
All right.
好的。
So let's make this a little more cat-like.
让我们让它更像猫一点。
Let me throw away all of this code.
让我扔掉所有这些代码。
And let me go ahead--
让我继续 -
oops-- let me throw away this code first and then the rest of this code.
哦 - 让我先扔掉这段代码，然后扔掉剩下的代码。
And let me go ahead and give myself another green flag block.
让我继续，给自己再添加一个绿色旗帜块。
And let me go ahead, and let's create a cat that allows us to pet it
让我继续，让我们创建一个猫，它允许我们抚摸它
by moving my cursor over the cat.
通过将我的光标移到猫的上面。
And maybe it likes that, so it'll meow when I do that.
也许它喜欢这样，所以我这样做的时候，它会喵叫。
So let me go under Control, and let me grab this if conditional,
所以让我进入控制，让我抓住这个 if 条件，
which we talked about as a building block earlier.
我们之前把它当作一个构建块讨论过。
Let me go to Sensing, and we haven't used this before.
让我进入感知，我们以前没有用过它。
But here is a weird sort of diagonal shape
但这里有一个奇怪的斜角形状
that says touching mouse pointer question mark.
上面写着接触鼠标指针问号。
So that's a Boolean expression.
所以这是一个布尔表达式。
So I'm going to drag that, and it's definitely the wrong size.
所以我要拖动它，它的大小肯定不对。
But it is the right shape, so it will grow to fill.
但它的形状是对的，所以它会长大以填满。
And the question I want to ask is if the cat is touching the mouse pointer,
我要问的问题是，如果猫触碰了鼠标指针，
then go ahead and meow happily.
那么就继续开心地喵叫。
So let me grab the meow sound, put it in there.
所以让我抓住喵叫声，把它放在那里。
And so I think when I click the green flag to start the program,
所以我认为，当我点击绿色旗帜开始程序时，
and now I let the mouse pointer touch the cat, we should hear--
现在我让鼠标指针触碰猫，我们应该听到 -
huh.
嗯。
Doesn't seem to be working.
似乎没有工作。
There's a bug or a mistake in this program too.
这个程序也有一个错误或漏洞。
What did I do wrong?
我做错了什么？
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: You didn't specify the sprite [INAUDIBLE]..
观众：你没有指定精灵 [听不清] ..
DAVID J. MALAN: I don't need to specify the sprite explicitly
大卫·J·马兰：我不需要明确地指定精灵
because a detail I didn't discuss earlier.
因为我之前没有讨论过一个细节。
In the bottom right of the screen, notice
请注意屏幕右下角
that the cat is already selected.
猫咪已经被选中了。
So this code relates to that cat.
所以这段代码与那只猫咪有关。
So your instinct is good if we had two or more sprites,
所以如果我们有两个或多个精灵，你的直觉是正确的，
but I just have one, so I'm covered there.
但我只有一个，所以在这方面我已经覆盖了。
Other thoughts.
还有其他想法吗？
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: It only checks once.
观众：它只检查一次。
DAVID J. MALAN: It only checks?
大卫·J·马兰：它只检查？
AUDIENCE: Once.
观众：一次。
DAVID J. MALAN: Once.
大卫·J·马兰：一次。
So I click the green flag.
所以我点击了绿色旗帜。
The computer did what I told it to do.
计算机做了我让它做的事情。
The mouse pointer was not touching the cat at that moment
那时鼠标指针没有触碰猫咪
because it was touching the green flag.
因为它触碰了绿色旗帜。
So, of course, it didn't meow.
所以，当然，它没有喵喵叫。
So what maybe is the fix here?
那么这里可能有什么解决办法呢？
What puzzle piece can we add?
我们可以添加什么拼图块？
AUDIENCE: After the green flag is [INAUDIBLE]..
观众：绿色旗帜之后是 [听不清] ..
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
大卫·J·马兰：好的。
OK.
好的。
Interesting solution.
有趣的解决方案。
So let me go ahead, and under Control let me grab a-- wait one second.
所以让我继续，在控制下面让我抓一个——等等。
I'm going to change the 1 to 5, and now I'm going to click the green flag.
我要把1改成5，现在我要点击绿色旗帜。
So here we go.
好了，开始了。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
1、2、3、4、5。
Damn it.
该死。
[MEOWING]
[喵喵叫]
OK.
好的。
That was yours, not mine.
那是你的，不是我的。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
It didn't work.
它不起作用。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Sorry?
大卫·J·马兰：你说什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Oh, maybe forever.
大卫·J·马兰：哦，也许永远。
So your approach would work, but it's very much a hack, if you will.
所以你的方法可以奏效，但它更像是一种黑客，如果你愿意。
Like, I would have to time it perfectly so that the mouse pointer is touching
就像，我必须精确地计时，这样鼠标指针才会触碰到
it, or, conversely, I have to drag it there and just
它，或者相反，我必须把它拖到那里，然后
leave it there for five seconds.
把它放在那里五秒钟。
And that's a little weird because you don't just touch a cat
这有点奇怪，因为你不会仅仅触碰一只猫
and then five seconds later it meows at you.
然后五秒钟后它就对你喵喵叫。
Like, presumably, we want it to be more interactive.
就像，我们希望它更具交互性。
So I like this idea of a loop.
所以我喜欢循环这个想法。
Right?
对吧？
Why don't we just tell the cat to forever listen for the cursor
我们为什么不直接告诉猫永远监听光标呢
as by using not repeat but forever?
通过使用“forever”而不是“repeat”？
Let me move this in here.
我把它移到这儿。
So now the cat's going to be told when the green flag is clicked just forever,
所以现在猫会永远被告知，当绿旗被点击时，
if touching, if touching, if touching.
如果碰到，如果碰到，如果碰到。
Oh, meow when actually touched.
哦，当真正碰到时喵叫。
So now if I zoom out and hit Play, nothing's happening.
所以现在如果我缩小并点击播放，什么也没发生。
I don't have to wait any number of seconds.
我不必等待任何秒数。
But when I do touch the cat--
但当我触摸猫时——
[MEOWING]
[喵叫]
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
[CHUCKLES] Fan section here.
[笑声] 这里有粉丝区。
Thank you.
谢谢。
[MEOWING]
[喵叫]
So now it's actually working quite well.
所以现在它实际上运行得相当好。
So there we have sort of a logical bug.
所以我们有一个逻辑错误。
But it does make sense if you think about what it was
但如果你考虑一下你告诉电脑实际做的，那就说得通了
you told the computer to actually do.
你告诉电脑实际做的。
Well, let's make things even more interesting
好吧，让我们让事情变得更有趣
by using one of these extensions.
通过使用其中一个扩展。
In this bottom left corner, this is how I got to text-to-speech earlier.
在这个左下角，这就是我之前使用文字转语音的方式。
Let me go to Video Sensing over here too.
让我去看看这里的“视频感测”。
And I can actually-- there we go-- literally, the video has come on.
我实际上可以——好了——视频确实启动了。
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我来做这件事。
Get rid of this code, and let me step out of the frame.
删除这段代码，让我离开画面。
When video motion is greater than--
当视频运动量大于——
well, this is CS50, so let's just type in 50,
好吧，这是 CS50，所以我们输入 50，
which is just a measure of motion.
这仅仅是运动的度量。
Let me go and play sound meow.
让我去播放声音“喵”。
OK.
好的。
And let me stop and restart.
让我停下来并重新启动。
All right.
好的。
So there's the cat.
所以猫就在那里。
[MEOWING]
[喵叫]
OK.
好的。
It worked.
它奏效了。
The cat's a little insensitive.
猫有点迟钝。
[MEOWING]
[喵叫]
There we go.
好了。
Actually, you know what?
实际上，你知道吗？
Maybe it's just-- let me put-- let's change it.
也许它只是——让我输入——让我们改变它。
20.
20。
Oh, my God.
哦，我的天啊。
Oh, that's OK.
哦，没关系。
[MEOWING]
[喵叫]
There we go.
好了。
All right.
好的。
There we go.
好了。
So now it's a little more sensitive to the petting by using the camera.
所以现在它对使用相机抚摸它更加敏感了。
Now, this is kind of a weird example.
现在，这是一个有点奇怪的例子。
And if I just start moving around crazily, like,
如果我开始疯狂地四处乱动，就像，
it's just going to meow incessantly, which was what was happening--
它就会不停地喵喵叫，这就是当时发生的事情。
[MEOWING]
[喵喵叫]
Stop.
停下来。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
OK.
好的。
When in doubt, this is when you reload the page.
有疑问的时候，就是你重新加载页面的时机。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
All right.
好的。
So now we're back to where we wanted to be.
所以现在我们回到了我们想要的位置。
But where can we now use these kinds of building blocks?
但是我们现在可以在哪里使用这些积木呢？
Like, we were doing such tiny little programs.
就像，我们正在做一些非常小的程序。
But even that we could turn into a whole game, I bet.
但我敢打赌，即使这样我们也可以把它变成一个完整的游戏。
Could we get like one volunteer to come on up?
我们可以找一个志愿者上来吗？
One volunteer?
一个志愿者？
Everyone's looking down.
每个人都低头看着。
OK.
好的。
On the end here.
在这边的尽头。
Come on down.
快下来。
Yeah.
是啊。
All right.
好的。
Round of applause for our one brave volunteer here.
让我们为我们这位勇敢的志愿者鼓掌。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
All right.
好的。
These Super Mario cookies are on the line for you,
这些超级马里奥饼干就等着你呢，
depending on how this goes.
取决于事情的结果。
So I'm going to have you come over here.
所以我要让你过来这里。
And in advance on Scratch's website, we have some pre-made games,
而且，在 Scratch 网站上，我们提前准备了一些预制的游戏，
one of them written by one of your predecessors, a former student,
其中一个是由你的前辈，一位前学生编写的，
that they implemented this sort of "Whac-A-Mole" game.
他们实现了一种类似“打地鼠”的游戏。
So what you're about to see is the camera turn on on you.
所以你将看到摄像头对着你打开。
And you're going to see four moles above, below, left, and right.
你将看到四个地鼠，分别在你的上方、下方、左侧和右侧。
And using only your head--
并且只使用你的头部——
up, down, left, right-- the goal is to whack a mole
上下左右——目标是打地鼠
to get a point every time your head touches one of these sprites.
每次你的头部碰到其中一个精灵，你就能获得一分。
So you're about to see things get very interesting very quickly.
所以你将看到事情很快变得非常有趣。
But using these building blocks, just those simple
但是使用这些积木，仅仅是那些简单的
blocks but have four sprites, not four cats but four moles in this case.
积木，但有四个精灵，不是四只猫，而是四个地鼠。
We can actually turn these into actual games.
我们实际上可以把这些变成真正的游戏。
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
So here we go.
所以我们开始了。
Click Beginner.
点击初级。
OK.
好的。
And we just need you to center your head first.
我们只需要你首先把你的头居中。
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[含糊不清的聊天声]
[CHUCKLES]
[轻笑]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
Nice.
不错。
Ten seconds.
十秒钟。
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
Nice.
不错。
Two seconds.
两秒钟。
AUDIENCE: [LAUGHS]
观众：[笑声]
DAVID J. MALAN: All right.
大卫·J·马兰：好的。
A round of applause.
鼓掌。
[APPLAUSE]
[鼓掌]
Thank you.
谢谢。
You want to introduce yourself?
你想自我介绍一下吗？
AUDIENCE: Hi, everybody.
观众：大家好。
My name is [? Vanilla. ?] I'm a first year,
我的名字是[？香草。？] 我是一年级学生，
and I'm going to be majoring in computer science and economics.
我将主修计算机科学和经济学。
DAVID J. MALAN: Nice to meet you.
大卫·J·马兰：很高兴认识你。
Here we go.
开始吧。
Thank you.
谢谢。
AUDIENCE: Nice to meet you.
观众：很高兴认识你。
[APPLAUSE, CHEERING]
[鼓掌，欢呼]
DAVID J. MALAN: So we won't look at the code for that actual game.
大卫·J·马兰：所以我们不会看那个实际游戏的代码。
It was written by one of your predecessors.
它是你的前辈写的。
And you can see it online if you're curious.
如果你好奇的话，你可以在线查看。
But you can think about now with our functions, conditionals,
但是现在你可以考虑一下我们的函数，条件语句，
Boolean expressions, loops how you could kind of compose that kind of program.
布尔表达式，循环，你如何编写这种程序。
So odds are there was a loop that was just constantly listening
所以很有可能有一个循环一直在监听
for that kind of connectivity, or it was one
这种连接，或者它是一个
of those extensions that was waiting for motion to go
那些等待运动的扩展，去
touch one of those sprites.
接触其中一个精灵。
Notice that there's these numbers up here.
注意这里有这些数字。
And we haven't talked about this yet.
我们还没有谈论过这个。
But just like in math, where you can have variables x, y, and z,
但就像数学一样，你可以有变量x，y，和z，
in programming, you can create variables using other puzzle pieces
在编程中，你可以使用其他拼图块创建变量
in Scratch that just keep track of how many seconds are left,
在Scratch中，这些变量跟踪剩余的秒数，
that keeps track of how many times her head hit one of the moles.
跟踪她的头部击中地鼠的次数。
And so you can implement the mechanics of games using very simple building
因此，你可以使用非常简单的构建模块来实现游戏的机制。
blocks.
模块。
But how do you go about building something
但是你如何构建一些东西
that's more interesting and interactive like that?
更有趣和互动的东西？
Let me go ahead and bring up, for instance,
让我举个例子，
one of the very first things I wrote years ago
我几年前写的第一件事
when I was in graduate school and Scratch had just come out.
当我还在研究生院，Scratch刚刚问世的时候。
I was taking a class at MIT's Media Lab.
我当时在麻省理工学院媒体实验室上课。
And they invited us to beta test-- that is, try out the software before it then
他们邀请我们进行beta测试——也就是说，在它成为世界的一部分之前尝试这个软件。
became part of the world.
成为世界的一部分。
And the game I made was this one here.
我做的是这个游戏。
Let me find the right version of "Oscartime."
让我找到“奥斯卡时间”的正确版本。
So "Oscartime" is a game that took me tens of hours probably in the end.
所以“奥斯卡时间”是一款游戏，最后可能花费了我几十个小时。
It was a little bit addictive, but let me go ahead and full-screen it.
它有点上瘾，但是让我把它全屏显示。
And I won't play the whole game.
我不会玩完整的游戏。
But it looked a little something like this.
但是它看起来有点像这样。
OSCAR: (SINGS) Oh, I love--
奥斯卡：（唱歌）哦，我爱——
DAVID J. MALAN: Where trash is falling from the sky.
大卫·马兰：那里垃圾正从天而降。
And I can click on it and drag it.
我可以点击它并拖动它。
And notice as I get close, the lid opens up like this.
注意，当我靠近时，盖子像这样打开。
And if I let it keep falling, it goes in, and Oscar gives me a point.
如果我让它继续掉下去，它就会进去，奥斯卡就会给我一分。
And I can do this again.
我可以再做一次。
OSCAR: If you really want to see something trashy--
奥斯卡：如果你真的想看看什么叫垃圾——
DAVID J. MALAN: All right.
大卫·马兰：好的。
Here comes something else.
这里有其他东西。
OSCAR: I have here a sneaker that--
奥斯卡：我这里有一双运动鞋，它——
DAVID J. MALAN: So now there's two pieces of trash.
大卫·马兰：现在有两块垃圾了。
OSCAR: It's all full of holes, and the laces are--
奥斯卡：它到处都是洞，鞋带是——
DAVID J. MALAN: And it just keeps going, and going, and going.
大卫·马兰：而且它一直持续着，持续着，持续着。
And if we can lower the volume for just a moment, we'll let more trash fall.
如果我们能把音量调低一会儿，我们会让更多垃圾掉下来。
But to your comment earlier about one sprite or more
但是你之前说的一句话，关于一个精灵或者多个精灵
sprites, that's what we're seeing here.
精灵，就是我们现在看到的。
Even though our examples thus far are just one cat, one or two puzzle
尽管我们到目前为止的例子只是一个猫，一个或两个拼图
pieces, or a few puzzle pieces.
碎片，或者一些拼图碎片。
Here is, I claim, a sprite.
这是，我声称，一个精灵。
Here is another sprite.
这是另一个精灵。
And by toggling among them in that bottom right-hand corner,
通过在右下角切换它们，
I can just associate different puzzle pieces with each of these sprites.
我可以简单地将不同的拼图碎片与这些精灵中的每一个关联起来。
Now, I didn't start off by implementing this whole game.
现在，我并没有一开始就实现整个游戏。
And in just a moment, if we can raise the volume a little bit,
一会儿，如果我们能把音量调高一点，
we'll see even more trash is falling.
我们会看到有更多垃圾掉下来。
So this is what--
所以这就是——
I hate this song now, like 10 plus hours listening to this song on loop
我现在讨厌这首歌了，就像循环播放这首歌十多个小时
just to get the timing right.
只是为了把时间掌握好。
But it brings to life all of these different sprites.
但它让所有这些不同的精灵都栩栩如生。
And if you play it again and again, it's always a little bit different
如果你一遍又一遍地播放它，它总是有一点不同
because I'm using some randomness.
因为我使用了一些随机性。
So this newspaper doesn't always fall from there.
所以这份报纸并不总是从那里掉下来。
Sometimes it's here.
有时它在这里。
And so here, again, we have mechanics of a game where
所以在这里，再次地，我们有游戏的机制，在那里
things are being perturbed a little, randomized a little bit
一些东西被轻微地扰乱，稍微随机化一点
to keep things more interesting.
为了让事情更有趣。
And let me go ahead.
让我继续。
OSCAR: (SINGS) I love trash.
奥斯卡：（唱）我爱垃圾。
DAVID J. MALAN: There we go.
大卫·马兰：就是这样。
How. about raise a little volume?
怎么样，把音量调高一点？
One more piece of trash.
还有一块垃圾。
So a clock.
所以一个钟。
It just goes on forever, this kind of game.
这种游戏就这样永远地进行下去。
But let's go ahead and consider.
但让我们继续考虑。
Let me close that.
让我把它关掉。
Let me go ahead and consider.
让我继续考虑。
How I went about implementing that from the get-go.
我一开始是如何实现它的。
So I will stipulate--
所以我会声明——
let me open a few of these versions here-- that the very first thing I did
让我在这里打开其中的一些版本——我最先做的事情就是
was pretty much just implement the stage.
基本上就是搭建舞台。
Right?
对吧？
I was kind of procrastinating, so I poked around.
我有点拖延症，所以我就四处看了看。
I found the Sesame Street lamppost, and I dragged it into the world.
我找到了芝麻街的路灯，把它拖到了世界里。
And done.
就这样。
Version one is done.
第一版完成了。
It didn't do anything, but at least I had the world sort of laid out.
它什么也没做，但至少我将这个世界大致布局好了。
That is to say I took a baby step toward my goal.
也就是说，我朝着我的目标迈出了一小步。
Then I started thinking about, all right,
然后我开始思考，好吧，
how do I bring the trash to life, even if it doesn't do much of anything else?
即使它什么也不做，我该如何让垃圾活起来？
And so I created another sprite by clicking the appropriate button
所以我通过点击右下角的相应按钮创建了另一个精灵。
in that bottom right-hand corner.
就在那个右下角。
And I thought about, well, what do I want this trash to do?
我思考着，好吧，我想要这垃圾做什么？
I want it to just kind of fall from the sky.
我想要它从天空中掉下来。
And so what I did here was the following.
所以我在这里做的事情如下。
If I go to this trash piece here or-- actually, sorry.
如果我到这个垃圾块这里，或者……抱歉。
Out of order.
顺序颠倒了。
What I actually did first was I didn't even have the trash fall.
我真正首先做的是，我甚至没有让垃圾掉下来。
If I play this game, the trash just stays there in the air.
如果我玩这个游戏，垃圾就一直悬在空中。
But I can do this.
但我可以这样做。
I can drag it, and as before, as I touch the other sprite,
我可以拖动它，和之前一样，当我触碰另一个精灵时，
I get the trash can lid to go up.
垃圾桶盖就会打开。
So how do I do that?
那么我该怎么做呢？
Well, let me click on Oscar down there, my first sprite.
好吧，让我点击下面的奥斯卡，我的第一个精灵。
And here are the puzzle pieces via which I implemented this idea.
这就是我实现这个想法的拼图。
I changed Oscar's costume, his appearance,
我改变了奥斯卡的服装，他的外观，
to be just number one, which was one of the images I imported into the program.
变成了数字一，这是我导入程序的图片之一。
And then I forever did this.
然后我就一直这样做了。
If Oscar is touching the mouse pointer, then
如果奥斯卡碰到了鼠标指针，那么
change Oscar's costume to number two, otherwise change it back to one.
将奥斯卡的服装改为数字二，否则将其改回数字一。
So it's super simple animation.
所以这是一个非常简单的动画。
I'm just toggling between lid up, lid down, lid up, lid down,
我只是在盖子打开，盖子关闭，盖子打开，盖子关闭之间切换，
but it kind of feels interactive.
但这感觉有点互动性。
And if I wanted to really make this pretty,
如果我想要把它做得更漂亮，
I could have 30 different costumes where the lid is ever so slightly higher.
我可以制作30套不同的服装，让盖子稍微高一点。
Then it would look even more like a movie or fluid motion.
然后看起来会更像电影或流畅的运动。
But this was enough to get the job done, which
但这已经足够完成任务了，也就是说
is to say I didn't try to implement all of "Oscartime" together.
我并没有尝试将整个“奥斯卡时间”一起实现。
I just took a second baby step toward my goal.
我只是朝着我的目标迈出了第二步。
And then my next version of "Oscartime" might
然后我“奥斯卡时间”的下一版本可能会
have looked a little something like this, where now the trash--
看起来有点像这样，现在垃圾……
there's more going on here.
这里发生的事情更多。
Let's look at two of these blocks of code.
让我们看看这两块代码。
The first thing I did was I enabled drag mode to draggable,
我首先做的就是将拖动模式设置为可拖动，
and I had to Google to figure this out because otherwise it
我不得不求助谷歌来解决这个问题，因为否则
didn't let me drag the trash while playing the game.
在玩游戏时不允许我拖动垃圾。
But once I figured that out, I tell the trash
但我弄清楚后，我告诉垃圾
to go to a random x-coordinate between 0 and 240
移动到0到240之间的随机x坐标
from left to right and then the y location 180
从左到右，然后y坐标为180
because I always want the trash falling from the sky.
因为我一直希望垃圾从天而降。
And then what do I do?
然后我该怎么做呢？
I told the trash to forever change its y-coordinate, its vertical coordinate,
我告诉垃圾永远改变它的y坐标，也就是垂直坐标，
by negative 1, negative 1, negative 1, one pixel
每次减少1个像素，
at a time, which creates the illusion of it falling from the sky.
这样就造成了它从天而降的错觉。
But I needed to do one other thing, and let me scroll up.
但我还需要做一件事，让我向上滚动一下。
Each of your sprites can have multiple programs, multiple scripts,
你的每个精灵可以拥有多个程序，多个脚本，
so to speak, that are not attached to one another.
可以这么说，它们彼此之间并不关联。
They will happen in parallel for you.
它们会同时发生。
The second one is saying this.
第二个程序是这样的。
Forever if the trash is touching Oscar, what should it do?
如果垃圾碰到奥斯卡，它应该怎么做？
Go to a completely different x and y location at the very top.
移动到最上面一个完全不同的x和y坐标。
Why?
为什么？
Well, as soon as I drag the trash over the Oscar,
当我把垃圾拖到奥斯卡上面，
I want it to disappear as though it's going into the can.
我希望它消失，就像进入垃圾桶一样。
And I then want it to reappear at the top so more trash falls.
然后我希望它重新出现在顶部，这样更多垃圾就会掉下来。
So I just thought about what would it mean
所以我就想了一下，对于垃圾来说，进入垃圾桶意味着什么。
for the trash to go into the trash can.
意味着什么呢？
Well, who cares?
嗯，谁在乎呢？
What really matters to the human user is that it just
对用户来说，真正重要的是它只是
disappears and teleports elsewhere.
消失并传送到其他地方。
And so that's the idea I implemented here.
所以我在这里实现的就是这个想法。
So if you can reduce intuitive ideas to just basic building blocks like this,
所以，如果你能将直观的思路分解成像这样的基本构建块，
you can start to make things much more interactive.
你就能开始让事物变得更具互动性。
And lastly, if I look at this version here,
最后，如果我看看这个版本，
you'll see that we've combined these.
你会发现我们已经把它们结合在一起了。
And so indeed, if I actually go ahead and play this now,
所以，如果我实际运行一下这个程序，
not only is it falling.
它不仅会掉下来，
I can let it fall right on top of Oscar and watch it disappear.
我还可以让它掉到奥斯卡的头上，然后看着它消失。
But notice Oscar doesn't pop out yet because that was the fourth version
但是请注意，奥斯卡还没有跳出来，因为那是第四个版本
and then the fifth version.
然后是第五个版本。
And then I added the annoying music and so forth but sort of
然后我添加了令人讨厌的音乐等等，但我也是逐步地
composed this program step by step by step
构建了这个程序，
so as to accomplish my larger goal.
以实现我的最终目标。
And this is going to be true of all of the code you write,
而这将适用于你所编写的任何代码，
be it in Scratch, or C, or Python, or in the like, trying to come up with--
无论是Scratch、C、Python，还是其他任何语言，都要努力想出——
or rather, trying to reduce your ideas, your grand vision to just baby steps,
或者说，努力将你的想法，你的宏伟愿景，分解成一个个小步骤，
building blocks so that you start with version one,
一个个构建块，这样你就可以从第一个版本开始，
and maybe you submit version 10 or 20.
也许你会提交第10个或第20个版本。
But you don't try to implement version 10 or 20 at the get-go.
但你不会一开始就尝试实现第10个或第20个版本。
You take those incremental steps.
你需要逐步地进行。
All right.
好的。
How about one other?
还有其他例子吗？
Well, let me propose this.
嗯，让我来提议一下。
Let me go ahead and open three games that represent one
让我打开三个游戏，它们代表着
that your predecessors also implemented, which looks a little something
你的前辈也实现过的，看起来有点像
like this in version zero.
这样，在版本零的时候。
Suppose I wanted to implement a game that
假设我想实现一个游戏
simply has these kinds of mechanics.
它仅仅包含这些类型的机制。
I'm touching my arrow keys on my keyboard-- up, down, left, and right.
我在键盘上按着箭头键——上、下、左、右。
And I'm moving the Harvard logo.
我移动着哈佛大学的标志。
Let me zoom in a bit.
让我放大一点。
So if I hit the up arrow, the Harvard shield goes up.
所以如果我按下上箭头，哈佛的盾牌就会向上移动。
If I hit the down arrow, the shield goes down.
如果我按下下箭头，盾牌就会向下移动。
If I go all the way to the left, it goes left
如果我向左移动到底，它就会向左移动
until it hits the wall and same thing on the right.
直到它碰到墙壁，右边也是一样。
So this is like the beginnings of a game or a beginning
所以这就像一个游戏的开始，或者是一个迷宫的开始
of a maze, something like that.
类似于这样的东西。
Well, how might I implement this?
那么，我该如何实现它呢？
Well, let me look inside this one.
那么，让我看看里面的内容。
And there's a lot going on, but, again, I sort of took simple steps.
这里面有很多东西，但是，再次强调，我采取了一些简单的步骤。
Notice that I've got three sprites--
注意，我有三个精灵——
a left wall, which is just a straight line,
左侧墙壁，只是一条直线，
the right wall, which is a straight line.
右侧墙壁，也是一条直线。
And just intuitively, why did I implement those as sprites?
直观地说，为什么我要将它们实现为精灵呢？
Why do they need to exist as entities themselves?
为什么它们需要作为实体存在？
Yeah, in front.
是的，在前面。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah.
大卫·马兰：是的。
I want it to interact with the shield.
我想要它与盾牌进行交互。
So I need to be able to ask that Boolean expression, like,
因此我需要能够询问那个布尔表达式，例如，
not touching mouse pointer but touching shield, for instance,
没有触碰到鼠标指针，但是触碰到了盾牌，例如，
a different type of yes/no question.
一种不同的“是/否”问题。
And so what is the code for the shield actually doing?
那么，盾牌的代码实际上在做什么呢？
Well, there's a lot of duplication, and let me focus on the abstraction first.
好吧，这里有很多重复，让我先关注抽象的部分。
Notice that I've got this one green flag clicked.
注意，这里有一个绿色的旗帜被点击。
I want the shield to go dead center, 0 comma 0,
我想要盾牌移动到正中心，0 逗号 0，
and then forever listen for the human's keyboard, and feel for the wall.
然后一直监听人的键盘输入，并感知墙壁。
So I decided to implement my own pink puzzle pieces that
所以，我决定实现我自己的粉色拼图块，这些拼图块
implement the two separate ideas.
实现了两个不同的想法。
One, just listen for the keyboard-- up, down, left,
一个是，只监听键盘——上、下、左，
right-- and then do something.
右——然后做点什么。
And then feel for walls is this idea of whenever I go up,
然后感知墙壁，就是说当我向上移动的时候，
down, left, or right, if I touch a wall, I
向下、向左或向右移动，如果我触碰到了墙壁，我
need to stop doing whatever the keystrokes are telling me to do.
需要停止执行键盘输入指令。
So now if we dive into those implementation details, listen and feel
所以现在如果我们深入研究那些实现细节，“监听”和“感知”
are abstractions, custom puzzle pieces.
都是抽象的概念，是自定义的拼图块。
Let's look at the implementation details.
让我们看一下实现细节。
Well, here's the keyboard.
好吧，这里是键盘。
If the key arrow up is pressed, change y by 1.
如果按下向上箭头键，将 y 改变 1。
If key down arrow is pressed, change y by negative 1.
如果按下向下箭头键，将 y 改变 -1。
And you can probably see where this is going.
你可能已经猜到这将要做什么了。
Right arrow is x by 1.
向右箭头将 x 改变 1。
Left arrow is x by negative 1, and that's
向左箭头将 x 改变 -1，这就是
sort of all that's involved with up, down, left, right.
关于上、下、左、右所涉及的一切。
But wait a minute.
等等。
Why is there no loop in this listen for keyboard puzzle piece?
为什么在这个“监听键盘”的拼图块中没有循环？
I needed a loop last time so it constantly works.
我上次需要一个循环，这样它就能持续工作。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Exactly.
大卫·马兰：没错。
I put the loop in my main part of my program
我把循环放在程序的主体部分
up top so something is telling me to keep listening again and again.
在上面，所以有什么东西在告诉我，要不断地监听。
So it's got to be somewhere, but it doesn't have
所以它必须在某个地方，但它没有
to be in the actual implementation.
在实际的实现中。
And lastly, how about this feel for walls?
最后，关于这种墙壁的触感呢？
Well, if touching left wall, which is just another sprite, change x by 1.
好吧，如果触碰左边的墙壁，它只是另一个精灵，将 x 改变 1。
So that is to say if I'm touching the left wall,
也就是说，如果我触碰了左边的墙壁，
I want to bounce it back the other direction
我想要把它弹回到另一个方向
and same thing on the right wall.
在右边的墙壁上也是一样。
If I'm touching the right wall, I want to bounce it
如果我触碰了右边的墙壁，我想把它弹回来
back to the left, which effectively means that even if the human's hitting
弹回到左边，这实际上意味着，即使人类在击打
the key, it's like fighting with this code,
按键，就像在与这段代码作斗争，
but it's never going to go through the wall based on that math.
但它永远不会穿透墙壁，因为数学原因。
It's going to stop it right there.
它会直接把它停在那里。
All right.
好吧。
Let's add something else to the mix.
让我们再添加一些东西。
Suppose I want the game to change to be a little something like this,
假设我想让游戏稍微改变一下，就像这样，
where Yale is some kind of block in between me and the exit.
耶鲁大学的标志就像一块砖，挡在我和出口之间。
So some dramatic race here.
所以这里有场戏剧性的比赛。
OK.
好的。
I just got by, but the Yale logo doesn't seem
我刚过去，但是耶鲁的标志似乎
to be doing all that much except bouncing.
除了弹跳之外没有做太多事情。
So I'm guessing there's a loop, maybe a conditional checking for those walls
所以我想，可能有一个循环，可能有一个条件语句来检查那些墙壁
too.
也是。
So let's go ahead and zoom out, see inside.
所以让我们放大一点，看看里面。
Let's not worry about Harvard because it's pretty much the same.
我们不用担心哈佛，因为它和耶鲁差不多。
Let's look at the Yale puzzle pieces.
让我们看看耶鲁的拼图碎片。
And sure enough, go to the middle.
当然，去中间。
0 comma zero.
0 逗号 0。
Point in direction 90, so point horizontally on the grid.
指向 90 度方向，所以在网格上水平指向。
And then if touching left wall or touching right wall--
然后，如果碰到左边的墙壁，或者碰到右边的墙壁——
I'm kind of cheating this time, but cleverly, just spin around and do 180
这次我有点作弊，但很巧妙，只需旋转 180 度
so you effectively bounce off the wall.
这样你就相当于弹开了墙壁。
This just tightened up my code.
这只是让我的代码更紧凑了。
I don't need to do the negative 1 or the plus 1.
我不需要做减 1 或者加 1 的操作。
I just say bounce in this form of code, otherwise just
我只需要用这种代码形式说“弹跳”，否则就
constantly move one step.
持续移动一步。
Now, if this is a game where Yale is supposed to be better and faster,
现在，如果这是一款耶鲁应该更强更快游戏，
well, let's change the 1 to 5.
好吧，让我们把 1 改成 5。
Move 5 pixels at a time.
每次移动 5 个像素。
Let's move it 10 back and forth.
让我们来回移动 10 个像素。
Let's maybe 100.
让我们来试试 100 个像素。
Uh-oh.
糟糕。
So what just happened?
所以，刚刚发生了什么？
That is a bug, which we can avoid by just not doing that.
这是一个 bug，我们可以通过不做这样的操作来避免。
But why did it break out of the wall?
但是，为什么它会穿透墙壁呢？
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众：[听不清]。
At first it was [INAUDIBLE].
一开始是[听不清]。
DAVID J. MALAN: Exactly.
大卫·J·马兰：没错。
Because I'm doing 100 steps at a time, I'm
因为我一次走100步，我
never actually touching the other sprite because I'm
实际上并没有触碰到另一个精灵，因为我
sort of stepping way over it.
有点跨过它。
So there's never a moment where they're actually touching.
所以它们实际上从未接触过。
So previously, I was just getting lucky by doing fewer steps because it's
所以之前，我只是因为走得步数少而走运，因为它是
gradually going over the wall, which gives me
逐渐越过墙壁，这给了我
just enough time to detect as much.
足够的时间来检测这一点。
So I would have to kind of tinker, and he'll
所以我必须进行一些调整，他会
handle this a little bit differently.
以略微不同的方式处理这个问题。
So it's a bug if it's too fast.
所以如果它太快，就是一个bug。
But at least if I keep it slow and reasonable
但至少如果我让它保持缓慢和合理
the math actually does work out, so long as it starts again in the middle.
数学实际上是行得通的，只要它从中间重新开始。
Well, let's do one final flourish here, whereby let's bring MIT into the mix.
好了，让我们在这里进行最后的润色，让我们把麻省理工学院加入进来。
Right?
对吧？
They're super smart, so maybe they can kind of
他们非常聪明，所以也许他们可以
track us and follow wherever I'm going.
追踪我们，并跟随我去任何地方。
So how might this work?
那么这将如何运作呢？
All right.
好的。
So nothing happens yet because we haven't finished composing the game.
所以现在还没有发生任何事情，因为我们还没有完成游戏的编写。
And notice here--
并且请注意这里——
OK.
好的。
Now MIT is struggling.
现在麻省理工学院正在挣扎。
It's kind of twitching there because it's going just above, and below,
它有点在那里抽搐，因为它只是在上面和下面
and then above, and below.
然后在上面和下面。
So we could fix that too if we want.
所以我们也可以修复它，如果我们想要的话。
But that's just a function of my math, one pixel at a time.
但这只是我数学的结果，一次一个像素。
Let me open up this one, see inside, and click on MIT.
让我打开这个，看看里面，然后点击麻省理工学院。
And it doesn't take much to implement MIT, it seems.
看起来，实现麻省理工学院并不需要太多。
So go to random position, forever point towards the Harvard logo outline,
所以随机移动到一个位置，永远指向哈佛大学的标志轮廓，
AKA the shield, and then move one step.
也就是盾牌，然后移动一步。
So if I wanted to make MIT even smarter, even faster, what do I change here?
所以，如果我想让麻省理工学院更聪明，更快，我在这里应该改变什么呢？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah.
大卫·J·马兰：是的。
Change one step to two steps to double their speed or five steps, 10 steps,
将一步改为两步，使它们的移动速度翻倍，或者改为五步，十步，
or 100 steps.
或者一百步。
And the game is going to be over like that.
游戏就会这样结束。
But that's all it takes to now make these kinds of elements.
但这就是现在创造这些元素所需要的一切。
So if you are a game player on your phone, or consoles,
所以，如果你是在手机上，或者在游戏机上，
or computer, or whatever, if you think about almost any game,
或者是在电脑上，或者任何其他设备上，如果你想一下几乎任何游戏，
you can probably now start to think about how they implemented
你可能现在就开始思考它们是如何实现
those mechanics because it's just being reduced to functions, conditionals,
这些机制的，因为它只是被简化为函数、条件语句，
loops, variables, and the like in this case.
循环、变量，以及在这种情况下的类似内容。
So let's go ahead here and have maybe one final volunteer.
所以让我们在这里继续，也许再找一个志愿者。
We've got one more bag of Oreos here.
我们这里还有一袋奥利奥。
OK.
好的。
That was super fast.
太快了。
Do you want to come on up?
你想上来吗？
All right.
好的。
Brave volunteer.
勇敢的志愿者。
Come on up.
上来吧。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
All right.
好的。
Let me find the full-fledged version of this that one of your predecessors
让我找到这个的完整版本，这是你之前的人之一
made.
做的。
And let me get the right one.
让我找对一个。
OK.
好的。
Here we go.
开始了。
We'll see some instructions on the screen in just a moment.
我们一会儿会在屏幕上看到一些说明。
And when we hit Play, you'll see that the mechanics are all combined now
当你点击播放的时候，你会看到现在所有的机制都结合在一起了
into one full-fledged game.
变成了一个完整的游戏。
But first, an introduction.
但首先，介绍一下。
It's on.
开始了。
SAM: Hi, everyone.
SAM：大家好。
I'm Sam.
我是Sam。
I live in [INAUDIBLE].
我住在[听不清]。
I'm a freshman, and I'm from Nepal.
我是一名大一新生，来自尼泊尔。
DAVID J. MALAN: All right.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的。
Welcome to the stage.
欢迎来到舞台。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
SAM: Thank you.
SAM：谢谢。
DAVID J. MALAN: All right.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的。
So here we go.
所以，开始了。
Yep.
是的。
Go ahead and click the green flag.
请点击绿色旗帜。
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
[MC HAMMER, "U CAN'T TOUCH THIS"] You can't touch this.
[MC HAMMER，“你碰不到我”] 你碰不到我。
DAVID J. MALAN: You see the grid is just bigger this time.
DAVID J. MALAN：你看到这次网格更大了吧。
(SINGING) You can't touch this.
(唱着) 你碰不到我。
DAVID J. MALAN: Nice.
DAVID J. MALAN：不错。
Now there's that Yale element.
现在出现了耶鲁元素。
(SINGING) You can't touch this.
(唱着) 你碰不到我。
My, my, my my music hits me so hard.
我的，我的，我的，我的音乐打动我，如此强烈。
Makes me say, oh, my Lord.
让我忍不住说，哦，我的主。
Thank you for blessing me with a mind to rhyme and two hyped feet.
感谢你赐予我押韵的头脑和两双充满能量的双脚。
It feels good when you know you're down, a super dope homeboy from the Oaktown.
当你意识到你很落魄时，这感觉很好，一个来自奥克兰的超级棒的兄弟。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的。
Third Yale.
第三个耶鲁。
All started at slightly different positions.
它们都从略微不同的位置开始。
(SINGING) I told you, homeboy.
(唱着) 我告诉过你，兄弟。
You can't touch this.
你碰不到我。
DAVID J. MALAN: Nice.
DAVID J. MALAN：不错。
All right.
好的。
There's MIT.
那是麻省理工。
(SINGING) And ya know you can't touch this.
(唱着) 你知道你碰不到我。
[CHEERING, APPLAUSE]
[欢呼声，掌声]
DAVID J. MALAN: Oh.
DAVID J. MALAN：哦。
(SINGING) You can't touch this.
(唱着) 你碰不到我。
Yo.
嘿。
Let me bust the funky lyrics.
让我来唱一段有节奏的歌词。
DAVID J. MALAN: Gotta go fast.
大卫·马兰：得快点。
Oh.
哦。
No.
不。
Oh.
哦。
[CHUCKLES]
[轻笑]
(SINGING) Cold on a mission, so fall on back.
（演唱）任务艰巨，所以退后。
Let them know that you're too much, and this is a beat they can't touch.
让他们知道你太强大了，这是一种他们无法触及的节奏。
DAVID J. MALAN: Nice.
大卫·马兰：不错。
[EXCLAIMING]
[惊呼]
(SINGING) You can't touch this.
（演唱）你无法触及。
DAVID J. MALAN: No more walls but two MITs.
大卫·马兰：除了两所麻省理工，没有其他阻碍。
(SINGING) Yo, sound the bell.
（演唱）嘿，敲响钟声。
School's in, sucker.
上课了，笨蛋。
DAVID J. MALAN: Princeton now.
大卫·马兰：现在是普林斯顿。
(SINGING) Give me a song or rhythm.
（演唱）给我一首歌曲或节奏。
Making them sweat, that's what I'm giving them.
让他们流汗，这就是我给他们的。
Now, they know you talk about the Hammer when you're talkin'
现在，他们知道你谈论锤子的时候，
'bout a show that's hyped and tight.
就是在说一场非常受欢迎且精彩的演出。
Singers are sweatin', so pass them a wipe or a tape to learn.
歌手们在流汗，所以给他们递一块毛巾或一段录音来学习。
DAVID J. MALAN: Second to last level.
大卫·马兰：倒数第二级。
(SINGING) The chart's legit.
（演唱）图表是真实的。
Either work hard, or you might as well quit.
要么努力工作，要么你干脆放弃吧。
That's word because you know you can't touch this.
这就是真理，因为你知道你无法触及。
You can't touch this.
你无法触及。
Break it down.
分解它。
DAVID J. MALAN: All right.
大卫·马兰：好的。
Clear.
明白了。
There we go.
就这样。
Nice.
不错。
Oh, oh.
哦，哦。
Oh.
哦。
Few more lives.
还有几条命。
Oh.
哦。
(SINGING) Stop.
（演唱）停。
Hammer time.
锤子时间。
DAVID J. MALAN: Here we go.
大卫·马兰：开始了。
There we go.
就是这样。
[EXCLAIMING]
[惊呼]
All right.
好的。
Couple more tries.
再试几次。
Yes!
是的！
Oh, no.
哦，不。
(SINGING) This is it for a winner.
（演唱）这是属于胜利者的。
Dance to this, and you're gonna get thinner.
跳这支舞，你会变瘦的。
Now move, slide your rump.
现在动起来，扭动你的屁股。
DAVID J. MALAN: Starts getting stressful.
大卫·马兰：开始变得紧张了。
(SINGING) Just for a minute, let's all do the bump.
（演唱）就一分钟，我们都来跳蹦蹦。
Bump, bump, bump.
蹦，蹦，蹦。
Yeah.
是的。
You can't touch this.
你不能碰这个。
Look, man.
听着，伙计。
You can't touch this.
你不能碰这个。
You'll probably get hyped, boy.
你可能会兴奋起来，小子。
DAVID J. MALAN: One more try.
大卫·J·马兰：再试一次。
(SINGING) You can't touch this.
（唱）你不能碰这个。
Ring the bell.
按响铃。
School's back in.
学校回来了。
DAVID J. MALAN: All right.
大卫·J·马兰：好的。
A round of applause, nonetheless.
无论如何，掌声响起。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
Nicely done.
干得不错。
Thank you.
谢谢。
So as you might have noticed if your eyes started
所以，如果你发现你的眼睛开始
to wander to the light bulbs here, there's
在舞台上的灯光上游走，你会发现
actually 64 of these light bulbs.
实际上有64个灯泡。
And I'm wondering if you divide 64 by 8, that's 8 bytes of light bulbs.
如果你把64除以8，那就是8字节的灯泡。
And we now have some Unicode in our vocabulary.
现在我们词汇里有了 Unicode。
So might very well be the case that we've
所以很有可能，我们一直在
been spelling something out on the stage here for you all of this time.
一直在这舞台上为你们拼写一些东西。
But before we adjourn for cake to be served in the Transept,
但在我们去横厅吃蛋糕之前，
allow me to introduce some of CS50's human friends,
请允许我介绍一下 CS50 的一些人类朋友，
the Harvard Krokodiloes and the Radcliffe Pitches,
哈佛的 Krokodiloes 和 拉德克利夫的 Pitches，
to give us this exciting ending, "This is CS50."
来为我们带来这个激动人心的结尾，“这就是 CS50。”
[APPLAUSE, CHEERING]
[掌声，欢呼]
[HARMONICA NOTE]
[口琴音]
[VOCALIZING]
[哼唱]
SPEAKER: (SINGING) There's a certain someone who I'm indebted to.
说话者：（唱）我欠某人一个人情。
And since the old [? BNC ?] has 50, I have this friend for you.
因为老 [? BNC ?] 有 50，我给你带来这个朋友。
A two, three, four.
二、三、四。
[VOCALIZING]
[哼唱]
Oh, rubber ducky, you're the one.
哦，橡胶鸭子，你是我的唯一。
You make [INAUDIBLE] so much fun.
你让 [听不清] 变得如此有趣。
Rubber ducky, I'm awfully fond of you.
橡胶鸭子，我真的很喜欢你。
[SCATTING] Rubber ducky, you make me smile, and you help my code compile.
[即兴哼唱] 橡胶鸭子，你让我微笑，你帮助我的代码编译。
Rubber ducky, you're my very best friend.
橡胶鸭子，你是我的挚友。
It's true.
是真的。
When I'm at a standstill, your debugging abilities stun me.
当我很迷茫时，你的调试能力让我惊叹。
When I'm at the end of my rope, you just snap, and my code's up and running.
当我已经筋疲力尽时，你只需轻轻一点，我的代码就能运行起来。
Rubber ducky, you're so fine, and I'm lucky that you're mine.
橡胶鸭子，你太棒了，我真幸运拥有了你。
Rubber ducky, you're my very best friend.
橡胶鸭子，你是我的挚友。
It's true.
是真的。
You're my best friend.
你是我的挚友。
It's true.
是真的。
Rubber ducky, I'm awfully fond of you.
橡胶鸭子，我真的很喜欢你。
[CHEERING, APPLAUSE]
[欢呼，掌声]
SPEAKER: Good afternoon, CS50.
说话者：下午好，CS50。
We are the Harvard Krokodiloes, Harvard's oldest a cappella group,
我们是哈佛 Krokodiloes，哈佛最古老的无伴奏合唱团，
founded way back in 1946 at the historic Hasty Pudding Club.
成立于 1946 年的历史悠久的哈斯提·普丁俱乐部。
We'd love to make a big thank you to CS50 staff
我们非常感谢 CS50 的工作人员
and to David Malan for having us perform here at Sanders Theater.
以及大卫·马兰，感谢让我们在桑德斯剧院表演。
And you enjoyed this performance, please come audition for us
如果你喜欢我们的表演，请来参加我们的试镜
this weekend at Farkas Hall.
本周末在法尔卡斯大厅。
[CHEERING, APPLAUSE]
[欢呼，掌声]
SPEAKER: Hello, everyone.
大家好。
We are some of the Radcliffe Pitches, and we are also
我们是拉德克利夫女声合唱团的成员，我们也
hosting auditions this weekend.
将在本周末举办试镜。
You can find more information at our Instagram, @radcliffepitches.
你可以在我们的 Instagram 上找到更多信息，@radcliffepitches。
Now, let me tell you a little bit about just about a year ago
现在，让我告诉你，大约一年前
today, when I was sitting in your very seats on my first day of CS50 lecture.
今天，当我坐在你们现在坐的座位上，参加我的第一个 CS50 讲座的时候。
And this is just about how I was feeling.
这就是我当时的感觉。
[HARMONICA NOTE]
[口琴音]
[VOCALIZING]
[哼唱]
(SINGING) It's the first day of class, and I'm brand new to code.
(演唱) 今天是第一节课，我刚开始学习编程。
Is this for me?
这适合我吗？
So many people around.
周围有这么多人。
Can I get through the workload?
我能完成这些工作量吗？
But it's my dream.
但这可是我的梦想。
I tend to stick to English, not science.
我倾向于学习英语，而不是科学。
But my [INAUDIBLE] friends told me to try this.
但是我的[听不清]朋友告诉我试试。
Hey, dancing robot dog, you kind of look like you have your life together,
嘿，跳舞的机器人狗，你看起来好像生活很充实，
I guess.
我想。
I really need some advice.
我真的需要一些建议。
(ALL SINGING) We know you're feeling unsure,
(全体演唱) 我们知道你感到不确定，
but this is really the right call.
但这真的是正确的选择。
In CS50, you'll meet new friends, get free food.
在 CS50，你会结识新朋友，还能获得免费食物。
You'll be all set for this fall in CS50.
你将为今年秋季的 CS50 做好准备。
You have a thousand TAs who will help you.
你会有一千个助教来帮助你。
You'll get cupcakes, duckies, Chinese food.
你会得到蛋糕、小鸭子、中国菜。
And you can always take this class and set aside.
你可以随时参加这门课，并把它放在一边。
SPEAKER: This is CS50.
这就是 CS50。
Fist bump.
击拳。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
[APPLAUSE, CHEERING]
[掌声，欢呼]
DAVID J. MALAN: Thank you to the Kroks.
感谢 Kroks 乐队。
Thank you to the Pitches.
感谢 Pitches 乐队。
Cake is now served.
现在可以享用蛋糕了。
Come on up to say hi if you'd like or meet Spot.
如果你想打个招呼，或者见见 Spot，就上台来吧。
See you next time.
下次见。
[APPLAUSE, CHEERING]
[掌声，欢呼]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]